<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>US on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</title>
    <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/countries/us/</link>
    <description>Recent content in US on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© amantonio, scibook.org 2017–2019</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/countries/us/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A population-based serologic survey of immunity to tetanus in the United States</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/018-a-population-based-serologic-survey-of-immunity-to-tetanus-in-the-united-states/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/018-a-population-based-serologic-survey-of-immunity-to-tetanus-in-the-united-states/</guid>
      <description>70% of Americans had protective levels of tetanus antibodies (0.15 IU/ml). The children had protective levels higher than 80%, but much lower than the vaccination coverage (96%). Less than 5% of parents refused vaccination, meaning that refusing vaccination is not a significant factor for the absence of antibodies in the USA.
It is reported here that in tetanus vaccinated animals, TTC (non-toxic fragment of tetanus toxin) reached the brain in the same amount as in the unvaccinated animals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acceptance of human papillomavirus vaccination among Californian parents of daughters: a representative statewide analysis</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/013-acceptance-of-human-papillomavirus-vaccination-among-californian-parents-of-daughters-a-representative-statewide-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/013-acceptance-of-human-papillomavirus-vaccination-among-californian-parents-of-daughters-a-representative-statewide-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Parents with higher education and conservatives rarely allowed their daughters to get vaccinated against HPV. Parents who did not finish school, Catholics and liberals more often allowed their daughters to have this vaccination. (California, United States)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Outbreak of Diphtheria in Baltimore in 1944</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/018-an-outbreak-of-diphtheria-in-baltimore-in-1944/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/018-an-outbreak-of-diphtheria-in-baltimore-in-1944/</guid>
      <description>Diphtheria outbreak in Baltimore. 103 cases were recorded in 1943. 29% of the patients have been vaccinated, and another 14% claimed that they have also been vaccinated, but had no documented proof.
Consequently, they started to vaccinate more in Baltimore. In the first half of 1944, 142 cases were already recorded. 63% of them have been vaccinated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Recent Medical Graduates More Skeptical of Vaccines?</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/024-are-recent-medical-graduates-more-skeptical-of-vaccines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/024-are-recent-medical-graduates-more-skeptical-of-vaccines/</guid>
      <description>Recent graduates of medical faculties less often believe that vaccines are the safest medicines, and that vaccines become better and safer. They are more resistant to compulsory vaccination, and they believe more that vaccination does more harm than good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Children Who Have Received No Vaccines: Who Are They and Where Do They Live?</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/003-children-who-have-received-no-vaccines-who-are-they-and-where-do-they-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/003-children-who-have-received-no-vaccines-who-are-they-and-where-do-they-live/</guid>
      <description>Unvaccinated children are mostly white. Their mothers are over 30, married, have an academic degree, and their families earn more than $ 75,000 a year. (USA)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deciding to opt out of childhood vaccination mandates</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/006-deciding-to-opt-out-of-childhood-vaccination-mandates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/006-deciding-to-opt-out-of-childhood-vaccination-mandates/</guid>
      <description>Parents who do not vaccinate their children, value scientific knowledge, know where to look, and how to analyze information about vaccinations, and at the same time do not really trust medicine. (USA)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diphtheria in North America</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/006-diphtheria-in-north-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/006-diphtheria-in-north-america/</guid>
      <description>Diphtheria was always considered a childhood disease, but in mid 20th century adults also began to get sick with it. In 1960, 21% of the disease cases were in adults (over 15 years of age). In 1964, there were already 36% of adults, and it 1970s – 48%. The mortality ratio has also changed. In the 1960s, 70% of those who died of diphtheria in Canada were children, in in the 1970s, 73% of those who died were adults.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Maternal and Provider Characteristics on the Up-to-Date Immunization Status of Children Aged 19 to 35 Months</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/004-effects-of-maternal-and-provider-characteristics-on-the-up-to-date-immunization-status-of-children-aged-19-to-35-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/004-effects-of-maternal-and-provider-characteristics-on-the-up-to-date-immunization-status-of-children-aged-19-to-35-months/</guid>
      <description>The lower the mother&amp;rsquo;s level of education, and the poorer, the higher the chance that she fully vaccinates her children.
More African and Latin Americans are vaccinating their children, and the poorer they are, the more they vaccinate. (USA)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human intestinal carriers of tetanus spores in California</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/013-human-intestinal-carriers-of-tetanus-spores-in-california/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/013-human-intestinal-carriers-of-tetanus-spores-in-california/</guid>
      <description>In four years from 1922 to 1925 in California, 245 cases of tetanus have been recorded. Mortality rate was 67%.
Among the 530 people in the study, the authors found bacteria in the intestines of 24%. They believe that the presence of tetanus bacteria in the intestines depends on the microflora, since they have always seen other types of bacteria along with tetanus bacteria, and did not see other bacteria, when the tetanus bacteria were absent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influenza vaccination attitudes and practices among US registered nurses</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/021-influenza-vaccination-attitudes-and-practices-among-us-registered-nurses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/021-influenza-vaccination-attitudes-and-practices-among-us-registered-nurses/</guid>
      <description>41% of nurses are not vaccinated against the flu. They were afraid of side effects, they believed that the risk of infection was low, and in general, they did not consider this vaccine to be effective. (USA)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maternal characteristics and hospital policies for risk factors for nonreceipt of hepatitis B vaccine in the newborn nursery</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/014-maternal-characteristics-and-hospital-policies-for-risk-factors-for-nonreceipt-of-hepatitis-b-vaccine-in-the-newborn-nursery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/014-maternal-characteristics-and-hospital-policies-for-risk-factors-for-nonreceipt-of-hepatitis-b-vaccine-in-the-newborn-nursery/</guid>
      <description>More educated mothers and mothers with higher incomes often refuse to vaccinate their newborn child against hepatitis B. (Colorado, USA)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mumps in the workplace. Further evidence of the changing epidemiology of a childhood vaccine-preventable disease</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/008-mumps-in-the-workplace.-further-evidence-of-the-changing-epidemiology-of-a-childhood-vaccine-preventable-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/008-mumps-in-the-workplace.-further-evidence-of-the-changing-epidemiology-of-a-childhood-vaccine-preventable-disease/</guid>
      <description>20 years after the invention of the vaccine and 10 years after it became widely used, the first mumps outbreak (118 cases) occurred in the workplace (Chicago Futures Exchange). Total costs associated with the outbreak amounted to $120,738, whereas the vaccine costs only $4.47.
The authors report that historically, vaccine prevention of mumps did not get as much attention as the other diseases, because it is a mild one. However, $1,500 per case of mumps is too expensive, when the vaccine only costs $4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mumps meningoencephalitis</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/007-mumps-meningoencephalitis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/007-mumps-meningoencephalitis/</guid>
      <description>Here is the report of 119 cases of meningoencephalitis caused by mumps in San Francisco in 12 years (1943-1955). Most cases are mild, with no complications, no neurological consequences, last less than 5 days, and rarely require hospitalization. Death due to mumps meningoencephalitis is a very rare phenomenon, and in the entire medical literature only 3 such cases have been described (including one out of these 119).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physicians who do and do not recommend children get all vaccinations</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/011-physicians-who-do-and-do-not-recommend-children-get-all-vaccinations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/011-physicians-who-do-and-do-not-recommend-children-get-all-vaccinations/</guid>
      <description>11% of doctors did not recommend their patients vaccinate their children with all vaccines.
Doctors-therapists did not recommend inoculation twice as often as pediatricians did (therapists earn less on vaccinations).
Doctors trust medical journals more than the CDC and the FDA. They trust pharmaceutical companies less than the Internet. (USA)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Possible temporal association between diphtheria-tetanus toxoid-pertussis vaccination and sudden infant death syndrome</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/037-possible-temporal-association-between-diphtheria-tetanus-toxoid-pertussis-vaccination-and-sudden-infant-death-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/037-possible-temporal-association-between-diphtheria-tetanus-toxoid-pertussis-vaccination-and-sudden-infant-death-syndrome/</guid>
      <description>The DTP vaccine has been associated with sudden infant death syndrome (SIDS) in Los Angeles, and visits to the doctor have also been associated with SIDS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prevalence of Antibody to Bordetella pertussis Antigens in Serum Specimens Obtained from 1793 Adolescents and Adults</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/012-prevalence-of-antibody-to-bordetella-pertussis-antigens-in-serum-specimens-obtained-from-1793-adolescents-and-adults/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/012-prevalence-of-antibody-to-bordetella-pertussis-antigens-in-serum-specimens-obtained-from-1793-adolescents-and-adults/</guid>
      <description>Among 1,800 adolescents and adults, only 20% had antibodies against the pertussis toxin one month after vaccination. Antibodies to other vaccine antigens were found in only 39-68% of the subjects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk of Nontargeted Infectious Disease Hospitalizations Among US Children Following Inactivated and Live Vaccines, 2005-2014</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/017-risk-of-nontargeted-infectious-disease-hospitalizations-among-us-children-following-inactivated-and-live-vaccines-2005-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/017-risk-of-nontargeted-infectious-disease-hospitalizations-among-us-children-following-inactivated-and-live-vaccines-2005-2014/</guid>
      <description>In USA, the risk of hospitalization among children whose last vaccine was a live one was twice lower than for those who received the inactivated vaccine as their last one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serologic Immunity to Diphtheria and Tetanus in the United States</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/010-serologic-immunity-to-diphtheria-and-tetanus-in-the-united-states/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/010-serologic-immunity-to-diphtheria-and-tetanus-in-the-united-states/</guid>
      <description>40% of Americans do not have sufficient immunity to diphtheria (below 0.1 IU/ml).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skepticism towards Emerging Infectious Diseases and Influenza Vaccination Intentions in Nurses</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/022-skepticism-towards-emerging-infectious-diseases-and-influenza-vaccination-intentions-in-nurses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/022-skepticism-towards-emerging-infectious-diseases-and-influenza-vaccination-intentions-in-nurses/</guid>
      <description>Swiss nurses are skeptical of infectious diseases and the vaccine against influenza.
Outbreaks of diseases are always less dangerous than announced by public health authorities and the media, reducing public confidence in the reliability of expert sources of information. Conflict of interest between public organizations and private corporations also reduces public confidence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sociodemographic Predictors of Vaccination Exemptions on the Basis of Personal Belief in California</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/007-sociodemographic-predictors-of-vaccination-exemptions-on-the-basis-of-personal-belief-in-california/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/007-sociodemographic-predictors-of-vaccination-exemptions-on-the-basis-of-personal-belief-in-california/</guid>
      <description>The number of non-medically refused vaccinations in California increased 4-fold between 2001 and 2014 (from 0.77% to 3.15%).
In private schools, there were twice as many refusals as in public schools. The percentage of refusers was higher among white, richer and more educated people.
In other states the same is observed - the percentage of those who refuse vaccinations in private schools is much higher than in public.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study of tetanus agglutinins and antitoxin in human serums</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/012-study-of-tetanus-agglutinins-and-antitoxin-in-human-serums/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/012-study-of-tetanus-agglutinins-and-antitoxin-in-human-serums/</guid>
      <description>The researchers ran blood tests of 104 California residents. Agglutinins to several strains of tetanus bacteria were found in the blood of 80% of them, but they did not have antibodies. The authors believe that tetanus bacteria were in the intestines of these people in the past, but did not survive there and thus they do not have the antitoxin.
Tetanus agglutinins have not been researched since then.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tetanus and diphtheria immunity in urban Minnesota adults</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/009-tetanus-and-diphtheria-immunity-in-urban-minnesota-adults/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/009-tetanus-and-diphtheria-immunity-in-urban-minnesota-adults/</guid>
      <description>84% of men and 89% of women in Minnesota had diphtheria antibodies level below 0.01 IU/ml.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tetanus in the United States, 1900-1969, Analysis by cohorts</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/048-tetanus-in-the-united-states-1900-1969-analysis-by-cohorts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/048-tetanus-in-the-united-states-1900-1969-analysis-by-cohorts/</guid>
      <description>As in the case with whooping cough, it is argued that the vaccine is responsible for reducing the incidence of tetanus by 92%, and the mortality rate by 99%.
This article analyzes cases of tetanus in USA since 1900 and shows a graph, according to which, the mortality rate decreased by more than 95% even before the vaccination began in the late 40s.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unexpectedly limited durability of immunity following acellular pertussis vaccination in preadolescents in a North American outbreak</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/013-unexpectedly-limited-durability-of-immunity-following-acellular-pertussis-vaccination-in-preadolescents-in-a-north-american-outbreak/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/013-unexpectedly-limited-durability-of-immunity-following-acellular-pertussis-vaccination-in-preadolescents-in-a-north-american-outbreak/</guid>
      <description>During the whooping cough epidemic of 2010, the majority of cases were children aged between 8 and 12 years old. There was no difference in the incidence between vaccinated, under-vaccinated and unvaccinated children (2 to 12 years).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vaccination practices among physicians and their children</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/010-vaccination-practices-among-physicians-and-their-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/010-vaccination-practices-among-physicians-and-their-children/</guid>
      <description>21% of pediatric specialists and 10% of total pediatricians will refuse at least one vaccination for their child.
19% of specialist pediatricians and 5% of general pediatricians will delay MMR vaccination until 1.5 years of age.
18% of specialist pediatricians will not vaccinate their child against rotavirus, 6% will not vaccinate against hepatitis A. (USA)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waning Protection after Fifth Dose of Acellular Pertussis Vaccine in Children</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/008-waning-protection-after-fifth-dose-of-acellular-pertussis-vaccine-in-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/008-waning-protection-after-fifth-dose-of-acellular-pertussis-vaccine-in-children/</guid>
      <description>The risk of contracting pertussis after the fifth dose of the vaccine increases every year by 42%, and after five years the vaccine is already ineffective (assuming an initial effectiveness of 95%). Out of all the pertussis-affected children in northern California, none have been hospitalized, and none have died. More: [1].</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>