<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Encephalitis on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</title>
    <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/diseases/encephalitis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Encephalitis on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© amantonio, scibook.org 2017–2019</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/diseases/encephalitis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep sequencing reveals persistence of cell-associated mumps vaccine virus in chronic encephalitis</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/025-deep-sequencing-reveals-persistence-of-cell-associated-mumps-vaccine-virus-in-chronic-encephalitis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/025-deep-sequencing-reveals-persistence-of-cell-associated-mumps-vaccine-virus-in-chronic-encephalitis/</guid>
      <description>A 14 months old boy was given an MMR vaccine, and 4 months later he was diagnosed with a severe combined immunodeficiency. He then successfully underwent a bone marrow transplant, but developed chronic encephalitis, and died at the age of 5. A brain biopsy showed that he had the vaccine strain of the mumps virus in his brain. This was the first case of panencephalitis caused by the mumps virus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waning immunity against mumps in vaccinated young adults, France 2013</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/011-waning-immunity-against-mumps-in-vaccinated-young-adults-france-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/011-waning-immunity-against-mumps-in-vaccinated-young-adults-france-2013/</guid>
      <description>In 2013, 15 mumps outbreaks were registered in France. 72% of the cases had been vaccinated twice. The effectiveness of the vaccine was 49% for one dose and 55% for two doses.
Among those who had been vaccinated once, the risk of getting mumps increased by 7% for every year that had passed since the vaccination.
Among those who had been vaccinated twice, the risk of getting mumps increased by 10% for every year that had passed after the second dose.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>