<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Physicians on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</title>
    <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/conditions/physicians/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Physicians on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© amantonio, scibook.org 2017–2019</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/conditions/physicians/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Despite awareness of recommendations, why do not health care workers not immunize pregnant women?</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/008-despite-awareness-of-recommendations-why-do-not-health-care-workers-not-immunize-pregnant-women/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/008-despite-awareness-of-recommendations-why-do-not-health-care-workers-not-immunize-pregnant-women/</guid>
      <description>Despite the fact that 93% of doctors know that the Ministry of Health recommends vaccinating pregnant women for flu and whooping cough, only 70% follow these guidelines. A third of doctors believe that both vaccinations are dangerous, or that their safety is questionable. 40% of doctors from those who believe that these vaccinations are dangerous, still recommend them to their patients. (Israel)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factors associated with vaccination for hepatitis B, pertussis, seasonal and pandemic influenza among French general practitioners: a 2010 survey</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/013-factors-associated-with-vaccination-for-hepatitis-b-pertussis-seasonal-and-pandemic-influenza-among-french-general-practitioners-a-2010-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/013-factors-associated-with-vaccination-for-hepatitis-b-pertussis-seasonal-and-pandemic-influenza-among-french-general-practitioners-a-2010-survey/</guid>
      <description>27% of doctor’s families were not vaccinated against hepatitis B, 36% were not vaccinated against whooping cough, 23% were not vaccinated against influenza. (France)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do physicians immunize their own children? Differences among pediatricians and nonpediatricians</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/009-how-do-physicians-immunize-their-own-children-differences-among-pediatricians-and-nonpediatricians/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/009-how-do-physicians-immunize-their-own-children-differences-among-pediatricians-and-nonpediatricians/</guid>
      <description>5% of non-pediatric doctors do not vaccinate their children against measles, mumps and rubella. They believe that combined vaccines are unsafe, that it is better to have the disease than to get vaccinated, and that homeopathic treatment works well for these diseases.
10% postpone DTaP vaccination for a later date, 15% postpone MMR vaccination.
A third of the doctors did not vaccinate their children against hepatitis B and hemophilic bacilli. Only 12% were vaccinated against the flu, and only 3% were vaccinated against chickenpox.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influenza vaccination among healthcare workers in Italy</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/016-influenza-vaccination-among-healthcare-workers-in-italy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/016-influenza-vaccination-among-healthcare-workers-in-italy/</guid>
      <description>Health workers are refusing influenza vaccination, despite ten years of efforts to increase vaccination rates. Only 30% of doctors, 11% of nurses, and 9% of clinical staff have been vaccinated against the flu. (Italy)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influenza vaccination amongst hospital health care workers in Beijing</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/018-influenza-vaccination-amongst-hospital-health-care-workers-in-beijing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/018-influenza-vaccination-amongst-hospital-health-care-workers-in-beijing/</guid>
      <description>Only 13% of doctors and 21% of nurses vaccinated against influenza.
40% of health care workers believe that flu vaccine can cause flu. (Beijing, China)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influenza vaccination compliance among health care workers in a German university hospital</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/020-influenza-vaccination-compliance-among-health-care-workers-in-a-german-university-hospital/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/020-influenza-vaccination-compliance-among-health-care-workers-in-a-german-university-hospital/</guid>
      <description>For more than 20 years, German health care workers have been pushed to be vaccinated for influenza, but only 39% of doctors and 17% of nurses are vaccinated. They are afraid of side effects, believe that vaccination can lead to illness, and do not believe in its effectiveness. (Berlin, Germany)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge, attitudes, beliefs and practices of general practitioners towards measles and MMR vaccination in southeastern France in 2012</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/014-knowledge-attitudes-beliefs-and-practices-of-general-practitioners-towards-measles-and-mmr-vaccination-in-southeastern-france-in-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/014-knowledge-attitudes-beliefs-and-practices-of-general-practitioners-towards-measles-and-mmr-vaccination-in-southeastern-france-in-2012/</guid>
      <description>13% of doctors do not consider measles a dangerous disease. 12% of doctors consider the second dose of MMR to be useless.
33% of doctors do not believe that MMR vaccination should be mandatory for children under 2 years of age. (France)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paediatricians knowledge, attitudes, and practices for immunizations for infants in Italy</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/012-paediatricians-knowledge-attitudes-and-practices-for-immunizations-for-infants-in-italy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/012-paediatricians-knowledge-attitudes-and-practices-for-immunizations-for-infants-in-italy/</guid>
      <description>Only 10% of physicians had a good opinion of all vaccines.
60% of doctors would like to know more about vaccines.
Only 25% of doctors gave optional vaccines to their patients (whooping cough, measles, mumps, chickenpox, rubella, Hib, pneumococcus, meningococcus). (Italy)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Physicians who do and do not recommend children get all vaccinations</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/011-physicians-who-do-and-do-not-recommend-children-get-all-vaccinations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/011-physicians-who-do-and-do-not-recommend-children-get-all-vaccinations/</guid>
      <description>11% of doctors did not recommend their patients vaccinate their children with all vaccines.
Doctors-therapists did not recommend inoculation twice as often as pediatricians did (therapists earn less on vaccinations).
Doctors trust medical journals more than the CDC and the FDA. They trust pharmaceutical companies less than the Internet. (USA)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seasonal and Pandemic A (H1N1) 2009 influenza vaccination coverage and attitudes among health-care workers in a Spanish University Hospital</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/019-seasonal-and-pandemic-a-h1n1-2009-influenza-vaccination-coverage-and-attitudes-among-health-care-workers-in-a-spanish-university-hospital/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/019-seasonal-and-pandemic-a-h1n1-2009-influenza-vaccination-coverage-and-attitudes-among-health-care-workers-in-a-spanish-university-hospital/</guid>
      <description>More than half of health workers refused to be vaccinated against influenza, and only 16.5% were vaccinated against swine flu during the 2009 pandemic. They doubted the effectiveness of the vaccination and were afraid of side effects. (Madrid, Spain)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vaccinating health care workers during an influenza pandemic</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/017-vaccinating-health-care-workers-during-an-influenza-pandemic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/017-vaccinating-health-care-workers-during-an-influenza-pandemic/</guid>
      <description>41% of healthcare workers refused to vaccinate against swine flu during the 2009 pandemic. They believed that the vaccine was ineffective, and there were side effects, and in general, this infection usually passes easily.
57% of healthcare workers refused to get vaccinated for regular flu. (London, Great Britain)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vaccination practices among physicians and their children</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/010-vaccination-practices-among-physicians-and-their-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/010-vaccination-practices-among-physicians-and-their-children/</guid>
      <description>21% of pediatric specialists and 10% of total pediatricians will refuse at least one vaccination for their child.
19% of specialist pediatricians and 5% of general pediatricians will delay MMR vaccination until 1.5 years of age.
18% of specialist pediatricians will not vaccinate their child against rotavirus, 6% will not vaccinate against hepatitis A. (USA)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>