<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Diphtheria on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</title>
    <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Diphtheria on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© amantonio, scibook.org 2017–2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 22:46:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/001/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/001/</guid>
      <description>Diphtheria, like tetanus, is also a rather dangerous disease, but what is the probability of getting sick with diphtheria in this day and age, and how effective is the vaccine?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/003/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/003/</guid>
      <description>Diphtheria vaccine is not produced separately. It is always combined with tetanus (DT, Td) and usually with whooping cough (DTaP/DTP). Same as tetanus vaccine, this vaccine is a toxoid, i.e. formalin-inactivated toxin.
Antibiotics and diphtheria immunoglobulin are used as treatment. However, since diphtheria is an extremely rare disease, human immunoglobulin is not produced for it, and horse immunoglobulin is used instead, even in the developed countries..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/004/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/004/</guid>
      <description>The concept of allergies was unknown until 1906. It was invented by an Austrian pediatrician and used to describe the strange symptoms he observed in those who received the diphtheria immunoglobulin.
The concept of anaphylactic shock also did not exist until 1902.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/019/</guid>
      <description>Diphtheria in Western countries is so rare that no one even remembers what it is anymore. They barely even teach about it in medical school. In Russia and former USSR countries, however, many still fear diphtheria, because of the epidemic in the early &amp;lsquo;90s. But who was it that got sick during this epidemic?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/026/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/026/</guid>
      <description>In 2016, 25 years after diphtheria has been fully eradicated, a diphtheria outbreak began in Venezuela. Since the vaccination coverage there was only increasing, each year, and given the humanitarian crisis currently happening there, it is hard to blame the outbreak on the lack of vaccination. However, WHO wouldn’t be WHO if they let the facts confuse them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/027/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/027/</guid>
      <description>In November-December of 2017, diphtheria outbreaks began in Yemen and in a refugee camp in Bangladesh. This, of course, happened because of the insufficient vaccination, and not because of the civil war in Yemen, and certainly not because the refugees in Bangladesh lived in tents, 30 people in each.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/033/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/033/</guid>
      <description>The effect of vitamin C on diphtheria has not been studied since the 40s. in 1971, Klenner [reported==https://www.seanet.com/~alexs/ascorbate/197x/klenner-fr- j_appl_nutr-1971-v23-n3&amp;amp;4-p61.htm#appendix] a case of a girl being cured of diphtheria by an intravenous injection of the vitamin. Two other children, who did not get vitamin C, died. All three also received the antitoxin.
Clark (1976). [1]. J Nutr Sci Vitaminol (Tokyo)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/034/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/034/</guid>
      <description>As is the case with other diseases, the decrease in diphtheria mortality rate began long before the introduction of the vaccine.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/035/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/035/</guid>
      <description>Since diphtheria vaccine is a toxoid, it cannot prevent the infection, but it can prevent complications from the disease. Thus, it would be logical to expect the diphtheria mortality rate to decrease with the introduction of the vaccine. However, that did not happen. Despite the fact that the number of diphtheria cases was continuously decreasing, mortality rate remained at approximately 10% level from 1920s to 1970s, despite increasing vaccination coverage. (data source).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/036/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/036/</guid>
      <description>Here’s some data from India, one of the last countries in the world where diphtheria still exists. Despite the increased vaccination coverage, the number of diphtheria cases has barely decreased since the 80s.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/037/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/037/</guid>
      <description>Diphtheria is an extremely rare disease nowadays. It is rarely found even in most of the third world countries.
Since 2000, only 6 cases of diphtheria have been reported in the USA. One of these patients died. He was 63 years old, and got infected in Haiti. This is such a rare disease that CDC writes up a separate report on almost every case. [1], [2].
At the same time, 96 people have been sick with bubonic plague in USA since 2000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/038/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/038/</guid>
      <description>Death from diphtheria in developed countries is so rare that every such case is widely reported in the media. In 2015, a boy died of diphtheria in Spain, and in 2008, a girl died in England. These seem to be the only deaths of children from diphtheria in developed countries in the last 30 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/039/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/039/</guid>
      <description>Since the diphtheria vaccine is always combined with tetanus/whooping cough, its safety data is the same as was presented in the respective chapters.
The vaccine (without the whooping cough component) causes Guillain-Barre syndrome, anaphylactic shock and brachial neuritis, lowers the level of lymphocytes, increases the risk of allergies and antiphospholipid syndrome. From 2000 to 2017, VAERS has registered 29 deaths and 181 disability cases after the diphtheria vaccine, without the whooping cough component (DT/Td).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Outbreak Of Diphtheria In A Highly Immunized Community</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/015-an-outbreak-of-diphtheria-in-a-highly-immunized-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/015-an-outbreak-of-diphtheria-in-a-highly-immunized-community/</guid>
      <description>Diphtheria outbreak in a British school in 1946 (18 cases). All but two (or three) children have been vaccinated (which is probably the reason why no one died, the authors believe).
Among the 23 unvaccinated children, 13% got sick. Among the 299 vaccinated children, 5% got sick.
One of the unvaccinated children has actually been vaccinated, but more than ten years ago. If he is excluded, then the percentage of sick children among the unvaccinated goes down to 9%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Outbreak of Diphtheria in Baltimore in 1944</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/018-an-outbreak-of-diphtheria-in-baltimore-in-1944/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/018-an-outbreak-of-diphtheria-in-baltimore-in-1944/</guid>
      <description>Diphtheria outbreak in Baltimore. 103 cases were recorded in 1943. 29% of the patients have been vaccinated, and another 14% claimed that they have also been vaccinated, but had no documented proof.
Consequently, they started to vaccinate more in Baltimore. In the first half of 1944, 142 cases were already recorded. 63% of them have been vaccinated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Booster immunization for diphtheria and tetanus: no evidence of need in adults</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/013-booster-immunization-for-diphtheria-and-tetanus-no-evidence-of-need-in-adults/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/013-booster-immunization-for-diphtheria-and-tetanus-no-evidence-of-need-in-adults/</guid>
      <description>Recommendations for getting booster vaccines against diphtheria and tetanus every ten years are based on serological studies, according to which, the elderly have lower level of antibodies. However, the goal of the vaccination is to prevent disease, not the production of antibodies. In Canada, the incidence of diphtheria does not increase with age; neither does the tetanus mortality rate increase.
The authors conclude that the benefit from booster vaccines against diphtheria and tetanus in adults, does not justify neither the risks, nor the cost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CDC Pinkbook Diphtheria</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/002-cdc-pinkbook-diphtheria/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/002-cdc-pinkbook-diphtheria/</guid>
      <description>Diphtheria is caused by the bacterium called Corynebacterium diphtheria, which itself is fairy harmless. However, if this bacterium is infected with a specific virus (bacteriophage), it begins to produce and secrete a strong toxin. This toxin is responsible for the severe symptoms of diphtheria. Diphtheria toxin destroys the throat tissue and forms a pseudomembrane in it, whereas without the toxin this bacterium can only cause pharyngitis. If this toxin enters the circulatory system, the complications could lead to myocarditis and temporary paralysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Current situation and control strategies for the resurgence of diphtheria in newly independent states of the former Soviet Union</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/023-current-situation-and-control-strategies-for-the-resurgence-of-diphtheria-in-newly-independent-states-of-the-former-soviet-union/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/023-current-situation-and-control-strategies-for-the-resurgence-of-diphtheria-in-newly-independent-states-of-the-former-soviet-union/</guid>
      <description>Vaccination coverage in Ukraine is above 90% among children, and over half of adults have been vaccinated between 1991 and 1994. Nonetheless, the number of diphtheria cases is increasing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diphtheria Outbreaks in Immunized Populations</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/011-diphtheria-outbreaks-in-immunized-populations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/011-diphtheria-outbreaks-in-immunized-populations/</guid>
      <description>A decrease in the incidence of diphtheria in the 1970s occurred despite the lack of immunity among adults.
Recent diphtheria outbreaks occur only among alcoholics and homeless.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diphtheria in North America</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/006-diphtheria-in-north-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/006-diphtheria-in-north-america/</guid>
      <description>Diphtheria was always considered a childhood disease, but in mid 20th century adults also began to get sick with it. In 1960, 21% of the disease cases were in adults (over 15 years of age). In 1964, there were already 36% of adults, and it 1970s – 48%. The mortality ratio has also changed. In the 1960s, 70% of those who died of diphtheria in Canada were children, in in the 1970s, 73% of those who died were adults.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diphtheria in the Former Soviet Union: Reemergence of a Pandemic Disease</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/020-diphtheria-in-the-former-soviet-union-reemergence-of-a-pandemic-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/020-diphtheria-in-the-former-soviet-union-reemergence-of-a-pandemic-disease/</guid>
      <description>The role of antibacterial immunity in protection against diphtheria has not been studied since the 30s.
 Prior to the World War II, diphtheria was rarely observed in the countries of Western Europe. During the war, an epidemic started in Netherlands, Denmark and Norway, in the territories occupied by the Germans. It was the last diphtheria epidemic in developed European countries. The remaining isolated cases were observed mainly among the lower socioeconomic class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diphtheria outbreak in St. Petersburg: clinical characteristics of 1860 adult patients</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/021-diphtheria-outbreak-in-st.-petersburg-clinical-characteristics-of-1860-adult-patients/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/021-diphtheria-outbreak-in-st.-petersburg-clinical-characteristics-of-1860-adult-patients/</guid>
      <description>1,860 cases of diphtheria in the Botkin hospital in St. Petersburg. Mortality rate was 2.3%. 69% of those who died were chronic alcoholics.
Among those who suffered from the toxic form of the disease, mortality rate was 26%. 6% of vaccinated patients and 14% of unvaccinated patients suffered from the toxic form. However, only those vaccinated in the last five years were considered as vaccinated.
Overall, the diphtheria mortality rate (2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diphtheria: epidemiological update and review of prevention and control strategies</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/012-diphtheria-epidemiological-update-and-review-of-prevention-and-control-strategies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/012-diphtheria-epidemiological-update-and-review-of-prevention-and-control-strategies/</guid>
      <description>More than half of the population in different countries does not have the protective level of antibodies against diphtheria.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Vitamin C Intake on the Degree of Tooth Injury Produced by Diphtheria Toxin</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/030-effects-of-vitamin-c-intake-on-the-degree-of-tooth-injury-produced-by-diphtheria-toxin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/030-effects-of-vitamin-c-intake-on-the-degree-of-tooth-injury-produced-by-diphtheria-toxin/</guid>
      <description>When guinea pigs are injected with a sublethal dose of diphtheria toxin, a 30-50% decrease in the vitamin C level in tissues is observed within 24-48 hours.
 Children who received little vitamin C, developed scurvy during the infection. It resolved spontaneously after recovery, without increasing the amount of vitamin C in the diet.
 What correlated with the absence of tooth caries in children of 10-14 years of age are good nutrition and lack of diseases in infancy and childhood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epidemiology of three cases of severe diphtheria in Finnish patients with low antitoxin antibody levels</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/024-epidemiology-of-three-cases-of-severe-diphtheria-in-finnish-patients-with-low-antitoxin-antibody-levels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/024-epidemiology-of-three-cases-of-severe-diphtheria-in-finnish-patients-with-low-antitoxin-antibody-levels/</guid>
      <description>In the 90s, due to the opening of borders, a flood of tourists poured from Finland to Russia and from Russia to Finland. 400 thousand Finns visited Russia every year, and 200 thousand Russians visited Finland. 10 million trips were made. Despite the epidemic in Russia, only 10 Finns contracted diphtheria in Russia. Almost all of them were middle-aged men; only three of them had a severe form (described below), five had a mild form, and two were only carriers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immunity and immunization of children against diphtheria in Sweden</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/007-immunity-and-immunization-of-children-against-diphtheria-in-sweden/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/007-immunity-and-immunization-of-children-against-diphtheria-in-sweden/</guid>
      <description>The protective level of antibodies of diphtheria is considered to be from 0.01 to 0.1 IU/ml. The exact value cannot be determined.
 Not a single case of diphtheria has been recorded in Sweden from the late 1950s to 1984. 3 outbreaks were observed in 1984 (17 cases, 3 deaths). Almost all patients were chronic alcoholics. Most patients had the level of antibodies below 0.01 IU/ml.
 Researchers measured the level of antibodies in children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immunological notes. XVII-XXIV</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/005-immunological-notes.-xvii-xxiv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/005-immunological-notes.-xvii-xxiv/</guid>
      <description>In 1926, Glenny and his group experimented with the diphtheria vaccine and tried to improve its effectiveness. They accidentally found that adding aluminum to the vaccine triggers a stronger immune response. Since then, aluminum is added to most inactivated vaccines.
Glenny was not interested in the safety of having aluminum in a vaccine 90 years ago, nor does it interest anyone today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Response to diphtheria booster vaccination in healthy adults: vaccine trial</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/014-response-to-diphtheria-booster-vaccination-in-healthy-adults-vaccine-trial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/014-response-to-diphtheria-booster-vaccination-in-healthy-adults-vaccine-trial/</guid>
      <description>Adults in Belgium got revaccinated against diphtheria. 24% of them did not get their antibodies above the ‘protective’ level. Among those, whose antibodies level was initially low it remained insufficient in 42% of the cases. The authors conclude that one booster dose for adults is not enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk factors for diphtheria: a prospective case-control study in the Republic of Georgia, 1995-1996</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/022-risk-factors-for-diphtheria-a-prospective-case-control-study-in-the-republic-of-georgia-1995-1996/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/022-risk-factors-for-diphtheria-a-prospective-case-control-study-in-the-republic-of-georgia-1995-1996/</guid>
      <description>To get diphtheria from another person, the distance to that person should be less than 1 meter. If the distance is greater, the risk of infection is significantly reduced.
 40-78% of unvaccinated children in Afghanistan, Burma and Nigeria developed natural immunity by the age of 5.
 Socioeconomic factors, such as cramped quarters, poverty, alcoholism and low level of hygiene contribute to the spread of diphtheria.
  A study of 218 cases of diphtheria in Georgia in 1995-1996.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serologic Immunity to Diphtheria and Tetanus in the United States</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/010-serologic-immunity-to-diphtheria-and-tetanus-in-the-united-states/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/010-serologic-immunity-to-diphtheria-and-tetanus-in-the-united-states/</guid>
      <description>40% of Americans do not have sufficient immunity to diphtheria (below 0.1 IU/ml).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serological immunity to diphtheria in Sweden in 1978 and 1984</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/008-serological-immunity-to-diphtheria-in-sweden-in-1978-and-1984/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/008-serological-immunity-to-diphtheria-in-sweden-in-1978-and-1984/</guid>
      <description>The authors measured antibodies level of 2,400 people in Sweden. 19% of people of the age of 20 and under did not have immunity against diphtheria. Among people over 40 years of age, only 15% had sufficient level of antibodies. Among the elderly, 81% of women and 56% of men did not have the immunity. On average, 70% of adult women and 50% of adult men had antibodies level below 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sexually transmitted diphtheria</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/025-sexually-transmitted-diphtheria/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/025-sexually-transmitted-diphtheria/</guid>
      <description>The first case of infection with diphtheria through oral sex. A man, an immigrant from the USSR who lives in Germany, went to a male sex worker, and received from him with a blowjob also urethritis in addition with diphtheria. France), diphtheria has become more frequent in the last few years than in other developed countries (several cases per year).The reason for this is too liberal policy of these countries regarding reception of migrants from the countries of the third world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Observations on Diphtheria in the Immunized</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/017-some-observations-on-diphtheria-in-the-immunized/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/017-some-observations-on-diphtheria-in-the-immunized/</guid>
      <description>In the early 1940s, Canada had a diphtheria epidemic (1,028 cases, 4.3% mortality rate). 24% of the patients were vaccinated (or protected). Among them, five have died (one of them was vaccinated just six months before getting sick).
Overall, those vaccinated had milder symptoms. The authors conclude that the vaccine is effective, but not 100%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tetanus and diphtheria immunity in urban Minnesota adults</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/009-tetanus-and-diphtheria-immunity-in-urban-minnesota-adults/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/009-tetanus-and-diphtheria-immunity-in-urban-minnesota-adults/</guid>
      <description>84% of men and 89% of women in Minnesota had diphtheria antibodies level below 0.01 IU/ml.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Diphtheria Epidemic in Halifax</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/016-the-diphtheria-epidemic-in-halifax/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/016-the-diphtheria-epidemic-in-halifax/</guid>
      <description>Diphtheria outbreak in Halifax (Canada) in 1940. 66 cases, of which 30% were fully vaccinated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The effect of diphtheria toxin on the vitamin C content of guinea pig tissues</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/028-the-effect-of-diphtheria-toxin-on-the-vitamin-c-content-of-guinea-pig-tissues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/028-the-effect-of-diphtheria-toxin-on-the-vitamin-c-content-of-guinea-pig-tissues/</guid>
      <description>Apart from humans and primates, guinea pigs are the only mammals that do not synthesize vitamin C.
Guinea pigs were injected with diphtheria toxin. Those who were on a low vitamin C diet lost more weight than those on a regular diet. Diphtheria toxin depleted vitamin C in the adrenal glands, pancreas and kidneys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The effect of diphtheria toxin on vitamin C in vitro</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/032-the-effect-of-diphtheria-toxin-on-vitamin-c-in-vitro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/032-the-effect-of-diphtheria-toxin-on-vitamin-c-in-vitro/</guid>
      <description>Guinea pigs with low vitamin C reserve, who got injected with lethal dose of diphtheria toxin, died faster than guinea pigs on a regular diet.
Guinea pigs that received large doses of vitamin C, survived even after being injected with several lethal doses of the toxin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The influence of vitamin C deficiency in the protection of guinea pigs to diphtheria toxin glucose tolerance</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/029-the-influence-of-vitamin-c-deficiency-in-the-protection-of-guinea-pigs-to-diphtheria-toxin-glucose-tolerance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/029-the-influence-of-vitamin-c-deficiency-in-the-protection-of-guinea-pigs-to-diphtheria-toxin-glucose-tolerance/</guid>
      <description>Vitamin C deficiency causes the decreased resistance to infections and increased damages from bacterial toxins. Decreased resistance appears before the scurvy symptoms can be observed.
 Guinea pigs on a low vitamin C diet, who got injected with sublethal dose of diphtheria toxin, experienced a wider tissue damage, bigger weight loss, wider areas of necrosis, worse teeth development, and shorter lifespan, as compared to guinea pigs who were not restricted in vitamin C consumption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The influence of vitamin C level after resistance to diphtheria toxin</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/031-the-influence-of-vitamin-c-level-after-resistance-to-diphtheria-toxin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/031-the-influence-of-vitamin-c-level-after-resistance-to-diphtheria-toxin/</guid>
      <description>Guinea pigs with limited vitamin C in the diet got injected with sublethal dose of diphtheria toxin. They developed arteriosclerosis in the lungs, liver, spleen and kidneys.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>