<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Russia on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</title>
    <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/countries/russia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Russia on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© amantonio, scibook.org 2017–2019</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/countries/russia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/038/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/038/</guid>
      <description>Death from diphtheria in developed countries is so rare that every such case is widely reported in the media. In 2015, a boy died of diphtheria in Spain, and in 2008, a girl died in England. These seem to be the only deaths of children from diphtheria in developed countries in the last 30 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diphtheria in the Former Soviet Union: Reemergence of a Pandemic Disease</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/020-diphtheria-in-the-former-soviet-union-reemergence-of-a-pandemic-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/020-diphtheria-in-the-former-soviet-union-reemergence-of-a-pandemic-disease/</guid>
      <description>The role of antibacterial immunity in protection against diphtheria has not been studied since the 30s. Prior to the World War II, diphtheria was rarely observed in the countries of Western Europe. During the war, an epidemic started in Netherlands, Denmark and Norway, in the territories occupied by the Germans. It was the last diphtheria epidemic in developed European countries. The remaining isolated cases were observed mainly among the lower socioeconomic class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diphtheria outbreak in St. Petersburg: clinical characteristics of 1860 adult patients</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/021-diphtheria-outbreak-in-st.-petersburg-clinical-characteristics-of-1860-adult-patients/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/021-diphtheria-outbreak-in-st.-petersburg-clinical-characteristics-of-1860-adult-patients/</guid>
      <description>1,860 cases of diphtheria in the Botkin hospital in St. Petersburg. Mortality rate was 2.3%. 69% of those who died were chronic alcoholics.
Among those who suffered from the toxic form of the disease, mortality rate was 26%. 6% of vaccinated patients and 14% of unvaccinated patients suffered from the toxic form. However, only those vaccinated in the last five years were considered as vaccinated.
Overall, the diphtheria mortality rate (2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>