<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hepatitis B on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</title>
    <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hepatitis B on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© amantonio, scibook.org 2017–2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 12:18:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/001/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/001/</guid>
      <description>If there were anything more stupid than vaccinating a teenager against HPV, it certainly would be vaccinating a newborn baby against hepatitis B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/002/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/002/</guid>
      <description>As is HPV, hepatitis B is a virus, which is most commonly spread through sexual contact or through the blood. If the mother is infected with hepatitis B, the virus can pass to the baby through the placenta, or during delivery. Hepatitis B does not pass through breast milk. [1] [2]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/003/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/003/</guid>
      <description>80% of the infected adults show no symptoms or very mild ones, and they do not even know that they have been ill. After having been infected they get lifelong immunity.
Of the remaining 20% of those diagnosed with hepatitis B, 95% recover fully and get lifelong immunity.
Of the remaining 5%, only 25% (that is 0.25% of all those infected) will develop cirrhosis of the liver or cancer in 20-30 years after the infection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/004/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/004/</guid>
      <description>Why vaccinate a newborn baby against an STD, which they virtually have no chance of contracting? Well, simply because the adult drug addicts and gay people refused to get vaccinated. Therefore, it was decided to vaccinate children immediately after birth, while they are not yet able to refuse. Most family doctors and pediatricians did not support this venture. [1], [2]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/005/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/005/</guid>
      <description>Three doses of the vaccine are usually given: immediately after birth, at one and six months old. This is the only vaccine that is given immediately after delivery. It is not done to prevent the possibility of contracting the infection from the mother. In the USA and other countries, all women get tested for hepatitis B before childbirth. Children of infected mothers receive immunoglobulin (antibodies) together with the vaccine.
In some countries, however, all children get vaccinated just because it is much cheaper than testing all mothers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/007/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/007/</guid>
      <description>The first hepatitis B vaccine appeared in 1981. It was made with a live virus, and after its introduction, the number of people infected with hepatitis B increased rapidly. A 1994 study determined that despite the existence of the vaccine, the number of patients with hepatitis B was not decreasing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/008/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/008/</guid>
      <description>There are quite a few manufacturers of this vaccine, but in developed countries, Recombivax (Merck) and Engerix-B (GSK) are most commonly used, as well as combined vaccines.
Engerix-B contains aluminum hydroxide, and Recombivax contains Amorphous Aluminum Hydroxyphosphate Sulfate (AAHS, the same adjuvant that Gardasil has). Recombivax has twice as much aluminum (500 µg vs. 250 µg). Previously, the Recombivax package insert indicated that it contains aluminum hydroxide. Now they put it this way: 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/009/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/009/</guid>
      <description>In most European countries, newborns are not vaccinated against hepatitis B, but they are vaccinated 2-3 months after birth. In some countries (Finland, Iceland, Denmark, Hungary) children are not vaccinated] against hepatitis B at all, and yet there are no epidemics there. On the contrary, the mortality rate from hepatitis B in them is much lower than the average for Europe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/035/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/035/</guid>
      <description>Clinical trials of the safety of Recombivax were conducted on 147 infants and children, as well as 1,252 adults, and lasted 5 days after each dose. There was no control group.
Clinical trials of the safety of Engerix-B lasted 4 days after each dose. There was no control group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/036/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/036/</guid>
      <description>VAERS recorded 1,540 deaths, 600 cases of disability and 8,675 cases of serious complications in children under the age of 1 year after the hepatitis B vaccine (meaning that the real number is 10-100 times higher). Infants do not die due to the hepatitis B itself, of course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/037/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/037/</guid>
      <description>In Israel, since 2005 the Israeli vaccine Sci-B-Vac has been used. only in the center of Israel and in the south (because the entire market can not be given to one producer).In July 2015, this vaccine was withdrawn. According to a statement by the Ministry of Health, it was recalled because the ampoules arrived on the machine that glued the labels too quickly, which could theoretically result in micro-cracks and bacterial contamination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/038/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/038/</guid>
      <description>Sci-B-Vac is a third-generation vaccine, the first generation was a live vaccine, the second generation is a recombinant (genetically modified) vaccine containing virus-like particles. The third generation vaccine contains two more antigens, and therefore gives more strong immune response.
The only published clinical trial of the vaccine included 150 children. The vaccine did not receive a permission from the FDA. The Ministries of Health Committee report which allowed the vaccination in Israel, somewhere disappeared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/039/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/039/</guid>
      <description>These charts show the numbers of disease and death from hepatitis B, before and after the start of vaccination in the USA. Data provided by the CDC.
    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/040/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/040/</guid>
      <description>Ayurvedic medicine seems to cure acute and chronic hepatitis B.
Hepatitis B can also be cured with vitamin C. Moringa as well. And desmodium.
Hepatitis B might also be cured with vitamin C. [Baur, 1954], [Kirchmair, 1957], [Calleja, 1960], [Morishige, 1978], [Smith, 1988]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/041/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/041/</guid>
      <description>How do the vaccination advocate argue the need for this vaccination for infants? Let’s listen to Paul Offit.
His first argument is that the child can get infected from the mother while passing through the birth canal. In this case, however, the vaccine would be ineffective – the child needs immunoglobulin. In addition, all pregnant women in the USA are screened for hepatitis.
The second argument is that the child can get infected from someone else’s toothbrush, or from some uncle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A case-control study of serious autoimmune adverse events following hepatitis B immunization</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/020-a-case-control-study-of-serious-autoimmune-adverse-events-following-hepatitis-b-immunization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/020-a-case-control-study-of-serious-autoimmune-adverse-events-following-hepatitis-b-immunization/</guid>
      <description>VAERS analysis. Adults vaccinated against hepatitis B got multiple sclerosis 5.2 times more often than those vaccinated against tetanus. The risk of vasculitis was 2.6 times higher, alopecia – 7.2 times, lupus – 9 times, arthritis – 2 times, rheumatoid arthritis – 18 times, thrombocytopenia – 2 times, inflammation of optic nerve – 14 times higher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A study of molecular mimicry and immunological cross-reactivity between hepatitis B surface antigen and myelin mimics</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/032-a-study-of-molecular-mimicry-and-immunological-cross-reactivity-between-hepatitis-b-surface-antigen-and-myelin-mimics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/032-a-study-of-molecular-mimicry-and-immunological-cross-reactivity-between-hepatitis-b-surface-antigen-and-myelin-mimics/</guid>
      <description>Hepatitis B virus antigen is similar in shape to the proteins found in myelin. After vaccination, 60% of people develop a cross-reactive response to myelin proteins, which weakens over time.
This mechanism of molecular mimicry explains why multiple sclerosis can occur after hepatitis B vaccination.
Memory impairment, decreased blood cell count and brain gliosis were observed in mice vaccinated with Engerix-B or aluminum hydroxide. Vaccination also aggravated the course of kidney disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adverse events associated with hepatitis B vaccine in U.S. children less than six years of age, 1993 and 1994</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/021-adverse-events-associated-with-hepatitis-b-vaccine-in-u.s.-children-less-than-six-years-of-age-1993-and-1994/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/021-adverse-events-associated-with-hepatitis-b-vaccine-in-u.s.-children-less-than-six-years-of-age-1993-and-1994/</guid>
      <description>Hepatitis B vaccine is associated with a 5.9 times increase in the risk of arthritis, 1.6 times increase in the risk of otitis media, and 1.4 increase in the risk of pharyngitis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autoimmune hazards of hepatitis B vaccine</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/034-autoimmune-hazards-of-hepatitis-b-vaccine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/034-autoimmune-hazards-of-hepatitis-b-vaccine/</guid>
      <description>A review article about autoimmune effects of hepatitis B vaccination, and how this vaccine is connected to evidence-based medicine (not connected at all).
Here are the descriptions of 60 cases of hair loss after vaccinations, mainly in women. Most cases happened after the hepatitis B vaccine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autoimmunity following hepatitis B vaccine as part of the spectrum of &#39;Autoimmune (Auto-inflammatory) Syndrome induced by Adjuvants&#39; (ASIA): analysis of 93 cases</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/028-autoimmunity-following-hepatitis-b-vaccine-as-part-of-the-spectrum-of-autoimmune-auto-inflammatory-syndrome-induced-by-adjuvants-asia-analysis-of-93-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/028-autoimmunity-following-hepatitis-b-vaccine-as-part-of-the-spectrum-of-autoimmune-auto-inflammatory-syndrome-induced-by-adjuvants-asia-analysis-of-93-cases/</guid>
      <description>ASIA, or Schonfeld syndrome, is the general term for autoimmune diseases caused by adjuvants, and includes the autoimmune effects of aluminum adjuvants, Gulf war syndrome, Macrophagic myofasciitis (MMF) and silicosis (autoimmune effects of silicone implants). It leads to neurological and psychiatric symptoms, cognitive impairment, muscle pains, arthritis, chronic fatigue, insomnia, problems with vision and gastrointestinal tract, etc.
93 cases associated with hepatitis B vaccine are analyzed here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chronic fatigue syndrome and fibromyalgia, the following immunization with the hepatitis B vaccine: another angle of the &#39;autoimmune (auto-inflammatory) syndrome induced by adjuvants&#39; (ASIA)</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/027-chronic-fatigue-syndrome-and-fibromyalgia-the-following-immunization-with-the-hepatitis-b-vaccine-another-angle-of-the-autoimmune-auto-inflammatory-syndrome-induced-by-adjuvants-asia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/027-chronic-fatigue-syndrome-and-fibromyalgia-the-following-immunization-with-the-hepatitis-b-vaccine-another-angle-of-the-autoimmune-auto-inflammatory-syndrome-induced-by-adjuvants-asia/</guid>
      <description>Hepatitis B vaccine is associated with chronic fatigue syndrome and fibromyalgia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chronic hepatitis B infection in adolescents who received primary infantile vaccination</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/014-chronic-hepatitis-b-infection-in-adolescents-who-received-primary-infantile-vaccination/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/014-chronic-hepatitis-b-infection-in-adolescents-who-received-primary-infantile-vaccination/</guid>
      <description>15-year-old teenagers, vaccinated in childhood, were tested for the level of hepatitis B antibodies, and it turned out to be very low. That is, the immunity from vaccination ends before the onset of sexual activity, when it finally becomes necessary.
According to another study, antibodies already disappear by the age of five.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clustering of Cases of IDDM 2 to 4 Years after Hepatitis B Immunization is Consistent with Clustering after Infections and Progression to IDDM in Autoantibody Positive Individuals</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/026-clustering-of-cases-of-iddm-2-to-4-years-after-hepatitis-b-immunization-is-consistent-with-clustering-after-infections-and-progression-to-iddm-in-autoantibody-positive-individuals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/026-clustering-of-cases-of-iddm-2-to-4-years-after-hepatitis-b-immunization-is-consistent-with-clustering-after-infections-and-progression-to-iddm-in-autoantibody-positive-individuals/</guid>
      <description>After the start of the vaccination campaign, the number of children with type 1 diabetes in France increased by 61%, and by 48% in New Zealand. In Italy, those vaccinated against hepatitis B had type 1 diabetes 40% more often than those unvaccinated.
The increase in the number of cases of type 1 diabetes occurs 2-4 years after the vaccination have started, which hints at causal relationship.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delayed acquisition of neonatal reflexes in newborn primates receiving a thimerosal-containing hepatitis B vaccine: the impact of gestational age and birth weight</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/024-delayed-acquisition-of-neonatal-reflexes-in-newborn-primates-receiving-a-thimerosal-containing-hepatitis-b-vaccine-the-impact-of-gestational-age-and-birth-weight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/024-delayed-acquisition-of-neonatal-reflexes-in-newborn-primates-receiving-a-thimerosal-containing-hepatitis-b-vaccine-the-impact-of-gestational-age-and-birth-weight/</guid>
      <description>Newborn macaques were given a hepatitis B vaccine with thimerosal and were compared to the unvaccinated ones.
Vaccinated macaques acquired survival reflexes, as well as motor and sensory-motor reflexes much later than the unvaccinated ones. Low weight and preterm labor exacerbated the effect.
Thimerosal (ethylmercury) has not been added to the vaccines since 2003 in the USA and Western Europe, but is still used in other countries, such as Canada, for example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epidemiology of Hepatitis B in the United States</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/006-epidemiology-of-hepatitis-b-in-the-united-states/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/006-epidemiology-of-hepatitis-b-in-the-united-states/</guid>
      <description>Prior to the onset of the full vaccination of infants, in 1990, only 1 out of 100,000 children under the age of 15 had hepatitis B in the USA. Currently, the risk of getting infected with hepatitis B at any age under 20 years old is 0.3 in one million. In developed countries, hepatitis B is a rare disease. In Africa and Southeast Asia, it is much more common.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of the Protection Provided by Hepatitis B Vaccination in India</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/010-evaluation-of-the-protection-provided-by-hepatitis-b-vaccination-in-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/010-evaluation-of-the-protection-provided-by-hepatitis-b-vaccination-in-india/</guid>
      <description>In India, where hepatitis B is quite common, there is no difference in the effectiveness of the vaccine if given at birth, or at the age of six weeks.
The risk of chronic infection is 90% when infected at the age of less than one year, 30% if infected at the age of 1-5 years and 2% for adults.
The incidence of hepatitis in India is 2.4%, which should result in 250,000 deaths from hepatocellular carcinoma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of multiple sclerosis in France since the beginning of hepatitis B vaccination</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/019-evolution-of-multiple-sclerosis-in-france-since-the-beginning-of-hepatitis-b-vaccination/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/019-evolution-of-multiple-sclerosis-in-france-since-the-beginning-of-hepatitis-b-vaccination/</guid>
      <description>After hepatitis B vaccination began in France, the incidence of multiple sclerosis cases increased by 65%. There is a high correlation (0.93/0.73) between the number of doses of the vaccine taken and the number of cases of multiple sclerosis in 1-2 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hepatitis B immunisation for newborn infants of hepatitis B surface antigen-positive mothers</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/013-hepatitis-b-immunisation-for-newborn-infants-of-hepatitis-b-surface-antigen-positive-mothers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/013-hepatitis-b-immunisation-for-newborn-infants-of-hepatitis-b-surface-antigen-positive-mothers/</guid>
      <description>According Cochrane systematic review, the vaccine effectiveness in preventing infection from the mother is 72%, immunoglobulin effectiveness is 50%, and vaccine + immunoglobulin have 92% effectiveness. No statistically significant difference was found between vaccination immediately after birth and vaccination at 1 month of age. A single dose of immunoglobulin was as effective as multiple doses.
Another study reports that less than 4% of babies born to infected mothers contracted hepatitis B in utero.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hepatitis B immunization induces higher antibody and memory Th2 responses in new-borns than in adults</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/016-hepatitis-b-immunization-induces-higher-antibody-and-memory-th2-responses-in-new-borns-than-in-adults/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/016-hepatitis-b-immunization-induces-higher-antibody-and-memory-th2-responses-in-new-borns-than-in-adults/</guid>
      <description>Unlike with other vaccines, babies vaccinated against hepatitis B produce more antibodies than adults, but less interferon gamma. Meaning that the immune response in infants is biased towards the humoral immunity as compared to adults (see the chapter about whooping cough). The same was found with the oral polio vaccine.
Revaccination in adults causes a cellular immunity response, whereas in infants it does not.
Those who received BCG vaccine at birth together with hepatitis B vaccine had significantly more antibodies at the age of 12 months than those who received BCG at the age of 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hepatitis B triple series vaccine and developmental disability in US children aged 1-9 years</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/025-hepatitis-b-triple-series-vaccine-and-developmental-disability-in-us-children-aged-1-9-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/025-hepatitis-b-triple-series-vaccine-and-developmental-disability-in-us-children-aged-1-9-years/</guid>
      <description>The risk of developmental delay was 9 times higher for those vaccinated against hepatitis B than for the unvaccinated ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hepatitis B vaccination of male neonates and autism diagnosis, NHIS 1997-2002</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/023-hepatitis-b-vaccination-of-male-neonates-and-autism-diagnosis-nhis-1997-2002/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/023-hepatitis-b-vaccination-of-male-neonates-and-autism-diagnosis-nhis-1997-2002/</guid>
      <description>Newborn boys vaccinated against hepatitis had a 3 times higher risk of developing autism spectrum disorder, as compared to unvaccinated, or vaccinated at least one month after birth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hepatitis B vaccine and liver problems in U.S. children less than 6 years old, 1993 and 1994</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/022-hepatitis-b-vaccine-and-liver-problems-in-u.s.-children-less-than-6-years-old-1993-and-1994/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/022-hepatitis-b-vaccine-and-liver-problems-in-u.s.-children-less-than-6-years-old-1993-and-1994/</guid>
      <description>For those vaccinated against hepatitis B the risk of liver disease was increased by 1.5-2.3 times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hepatitis B vaccine and the risk of CNS inflammatory demyelination in childhood</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/018-hepatitis-b-vaccine-and-the-risk-of-cns-inflammatory-demyelination-in-childhood/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/018-hepatitis-b-vaccine-and-the-risk-of-cns-inflammatory-demyelination-in-childhood/</guid>
      <description>The Engerix-B vaccine is associated with a 2.77 times increase in the risk of multiple sclerosis, as compared to other hepatitis B vaccines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hepatitis B vaccine induces apoptotic death in Hepa1-6 cells</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/031-hepatitis-b-vaccine-induces-apoptotic-death-in-hepa1-6-cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/031-hepatitis-b-vaccine-induces-apoptotic-death-in-hepa1-6-cells/</guid>
      <description>Hepatitis B vaccine destroys mitochondria and kills liver cells in mice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In vivo study of hepatitis B vaccine effects on inflammation and metabolism gene expression</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/030-in-vivo-study-of-hepatitis-b-vaccine-effects-on-inflammation-and-metabolism-gene-expression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/030-in-vivo-study-of-hepatitis-b-vaccine-effects-on-inflammation-and-metabolism-gene-expression/</guid>
      <description>Epigenetic effect of the vaccine. Mice were given one or two hepatitis B vaccines (at the appropriate dose). One day later, they had significant changes in the expression of 144 genes in the liver. The authors analyzed 7 of them in detail. All changes were negative and led to mild liver injury, mainly due to aluminum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-term immunogenicity and efficacy of hepatitis B vaccine in homosexual men</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/011-long-term-immunogenicity-and-efficacy-of-hepatitis-b-vaccine-in-homosexual-men/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/011-long-term-immunogenicity-and-efficacy-of-hepatitis-b-vaccine-in-homosexual-men/</guid>
      <description>773 homosexuals were given hepatitis vaccination and observed for five years.
82% had sufficient level of antibodies after the vaccination. By the end of the observation period, the antibodies disappeared in 15% of them, and decreased below the protective level in 27%.
55 contracted hepatitis, 5 became chronic patients. Those infected had 29 non-regular sexual partners on average, whereas those who did not get infected had 11.5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persistence of an antibody in a healthcare worker vaccinated against hepatitis B</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/015-persistence-of-an-antibody-in-a-healthcare-worker-vaccinated-against-hepatitis-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/015-persistence-of-an-antibody-in-a-healthcare-worker-vaccinated-against-hepatitis-b/</guid>
      <description>In 4 years after the vaccination the level of antibodies in 50% of vaccinated physicians decreased below the protective level.
In 36% of vaccinated physicians the level of antibodies was below the protective level within 3 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recombinant hepatitis B vaccine and the risk of multiple sclerosis: a prospective study</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/017-recombinant-hepatitis-b-vaccine-and-the-risk-of-multiple-sclerosis-a-prospective-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/017-recombinant-hepatitis-b-vaccine-and-the-risk-of-multiple-sclerosis-a-prospective-study/</guid>
      <description>Hepatitis B vaccine is associated with threefold risk of multiple sclerosis three years after vaccination.
Other studies, the ones that did not find an increased risk of multiple sclerosis in those vaccinated, are analyzed there as well. Here, for example, is a study, which did not find an increased risk. This is because they used the date of diagnosis, and not the date of the first symptoms. Multiple sclerosis is usually diagnosed several years after the onset of symptoms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trained immunity in newborn infants of HBV-infected mothers</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/033-trained-immunity-in-newborn-infants-of-hbv-infected-mothers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/033-trained-immunity-in-newborn-infants-of-hbv-infected-mothers/</guid>
      <description>Hepatitis B, passed from mother to child, might, contrary to the popular belief, lead to better development of the immune system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vaccine-induced autoimmunity</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/029-vaccine-induced-autoimmunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/029-vaccine-induced-autoimmunity/</guid>
      <description>Autoimmune diseases such as Reiter’s syndrome, arthritis, lupus, chorioretinitis, myasthenia, erythema nodosum, thrombocytopenic purpura, Evans syndrome, and demyelinating diseases of the central nervous system are associated with hepatitis B vaccination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vertical HBV transmission in Jerusalem in the vaccine era</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/012-vertical-hbv-transmission-in-jerusalem-in-the-vaccine-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/012-vertical-hbv-transmission-in-jerusalem-in-the-vaccine-era/</guid>
      <description>In Israel, the rate of infected with hepatitis B has not changed compared with 1977 and 1991. In Arab women, the virus is found 4 times more often.
Despite vaccination, 8.4% of children were infected by their mothers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>