<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Israel on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</title>
    <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/countries/israel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Israel on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© amantonio, scibook.org 2017–2019</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/countries/israel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/038/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/038/</guid>
      <description>Death from diphtheria in developed countries is so rare that every such case is widely reported in the media. In 2015, a boy died of diphtheria in Spain, and in 2008, a girl died in England. These seem to be the only deaths of children from diphtheria in developed countries in the last 30 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/037/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/037/</guid>
      <description>In Israel, since 2005 the Israeli vaccine Sci-B-Vac has been used. only in the center of Israel and in the south (because the entire market can not be given to one producer).In July 2015, this vaccine was withdrawn. According to a statement by the Ministry of Health, it was recalled because the ampoules arrived on the machine that glued the labels too quickly, which could theoretically result in micro-cracks and bacterial contamination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/038/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/038/</guid>
      <description>Sci-B-Vac is a third-generation vaccine, the first generation was a live vaccine, the second generation is a recombinant (genetically modified) vaccine containing virus-like particles. The third generation vaccine contains two more antigens, and therefore gives more strong immune response.
The only published clinical trial of the vaccine included 150 children. The vaccine did not receive a permission from the FDA. The Ministries of Health Committee report which allowed the vaccination in Israel, somewhere disappeared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Despite awareness of recommendations, why do not health care workers not immunize pregnant women?</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/008-despite-awareness-of-recommendations-why-do-not-health-care-workers-not-immunize-pregnant-women/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/008-despite-awareness-of-recommendations-why-do-not-health-care-workers-not-immunize-pregnant-women/</guid>
      <description>Despite the fact that 93% of doctors know that the Ministry of Health recommends vaccinating pregnant women for flu and whooping cough, only 70% follow these guidelines. A third of doctors believe that both vaccinations are dangerous, or that their safety is questionable. 40% of doctors from those who believe that these vaccinations are dangerous, still recommend them to their patients. (Israel)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Israeli Parents Refusing to Vaccinate Their Babies According to State Regulations</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/008-more-israeli-parents-refusing-to-vaccinate-their-babies-according-to-state-regulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/008-more-israeli-parents-refusing-to-vaccinate-their-babies-according-to-state-regulations/</guid>
      <description>Mothers with an academic education are twice as likely to refuse vaccinations.
Jews are 4 times more likely to refuse vaccinations than Muslims.
The older the mothers, the more often they refuse vaccinations. (Israel)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mumps outbreak in Israel&#39;s highly vaccinated society: are two doses enough?</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/012-mumps-outbreak-in-israels-highly-vaccinated-society-are-two-doses-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/012-mumps-outbreak-in-israels-highly-vaccinated-society-are-two-doses-enough/</guid>
      <description>A mumps outbreak in Israel (over 5,000 cases). 78% had been fully vaccinated. Mostly teenagers and adults got sick. In other countries (Austria, USA, Netherlands, Great Britain) mumps outbreaks were also observed among teenagers and college students, whereas in countries where there is no vaccination against mumps, children aged 5-9 years got sick.
Despite the high vaccination coverage (90-97%), mumps antibodies were found in only 68% of the population.
The authors report that the recent mumps outbreaks have been caused by the genotype G virus, whereas the vaccine contains genotype A.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naturally Acquired Immunity to Tetanus Toxin in an Isolated Community</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/006-naturally-acquired-immunity-to-tetanus-toxin-in-an-isolated-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/006-naturally-acquired-immunity-to-tetanus-toxin-in-an-isolated-community/</guid>
      <description>There is a complete medical consensus on that natural immunity against tetanus is impossible, and only a vaccine can prevent the disease.
The authors ran blood tests of two hundred randomly selected immigrants from Ethiopia to Israel and found tetanus antibodies in 98% of them. 30% of them had the level of antibodies that is considered protective (above 0.01 UI/ml). None of them have been vaccinated.
The amount of antibodies increased with age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pertussis Infection in Fully Vaccinated Children in Day Care Centers, Israel</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/017-pertussis-infection-in-fully-vaccinated-children-in-day-care-centers-israel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/017-pertussis-infection-in-fully-vaccinated-children-in-day-care-centers-israel/</guid>
      <description>While there are hundreds of case reports for different vaccines, we have not yet cited any until now. This case occurred in the year 2000, when a whole-cell (i.e., more effective) vaccine was administered to a 2-month-old child in Israel. Despite the entire family (mother, aunt and three brothers - 2, 5 and 11 years old) being fully vaccinated, the child died of whooping cough at an age of 4 months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reduced rate of side effects associated with separate administration of MMR and DTaP-Hib-IPV vaccinations. </title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/018-reduced-rate-of-side-effects-associated-with-separate-administration-of-mmr-and-dtap-hib-ipv-vaccinations./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/018-reduced-rate-of-side-effects-associated-with-separate-administration-of-mmr-and-dtap-hib-ipv-vaccinations./</guid>
      <description>Side effects of vaccination were observed in 57% of children who received MMR and pentavalent vaccine simultaneously, but only in 40% among those, who only received the MMR vaccine.
Authors conclude that, perhaps, the current policy on simultaneous vaccinations should be reviewed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tetanus immunity in kibbutz women</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/007-tetanus-immunity-in-kibbutz-women/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/007-tetanus-immunity-in-kibbutz-women/</guid>
      <description>Researchers ran blood tests of 120 randomly selected women living in Israeli kibbutzim. All of them had sufficient levels of antibodies against tetanus toxin, despite the fact that 12.5% of them had never been vaccinated.
Many of them were not fully vaccinated (from 6% among the young to 68% among the elderly).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What lies behind the low rates of vaccinations among nurses who treat infants?</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/015-what-lies-behind-the-low-rates-of-vaccinations-among-nurses-who-treat-infants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/015-what-lies-behind-the-low-rates-of-vaccinations-among-nurses-who-treat-infants/</guid>
      <description>After Israeli nurses were asked to vaccinate against whooping cough at 3 months, only 2% (two percent) deigned to do so. And we are talking about nurses working in mother and child centers (tipat halav), that is, those whose main role is to vaccinate children.
Most nurses do not trust health authorities, and desperately resist compulsory vaccinations.
They believe that parents should have the choice to vaccinate a child or not, and they demand the same respect for their rights.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>