<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Human Chorionic Gonadotropin on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</title>
    <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/drugs/human-chorionic-gonadotropin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Human Chorionic Gonadotropin on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© amantonio, scibook.org 2017–2019</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/drugs/human-chorionic-gonadotropin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/033/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/033/</guid>
      <description>In 2014, WHO and UNICEF held a vaccination campaign for women of childbearing age (14-19 y.o.) in Kenya. Women received five doses of the vaccine. The Church usually carries out vaccination in Kenya, but this time the WHO carried out the vaccinations itself. The Organization of Catholic Bishops in Kenya found it strange and decided to send that vaccine for testing into four different labs. According to the Bishops’ statement, all labs found hCG in the tested vials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A vaccine that will reduce pregnancy in women</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/031-a-vaccine-that-will-reduce-pregnancy-in-women/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/031-a-vaccine-that-will-reduce-pregnancy-in-women/</guid>
      <description>hCG (Human Chorionic Gonadotropin) is a hormone, which is released during pregnancy, and which the home pregnancy test is based on.
Since this hormone is absolutely necessary for the development of pregnancy, scientists came up with a brilliant idea. They thought that if they could trigger an autoimmune reaction to this hormone, the immune system would begin to see it as a pathogen and destroy it. And that would make a vaccine against pregnancy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HCG Found in WHO Tetanus Vaccine in Kenya Raises Concern in the Developing World</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/034-hcg-found-in-who-tetanus-vaccine-in-kenya-raises-concern-in-the-developing-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/034-hcg-found-in-who-tetanus-vaccine-in-kenya-raises-concern-in-the-developing-world/</guid>
      <description>WHO has been working on development of pregnancy vaccine since 1970s. WHO has been working on the issue of reducing birth rates in third world countries since 1945. The US government has been officially supporting the decline in birth rates in third world countries since 1970s. The vaccination protocol used in Kenya (5 doses every six months) completely coincided with the pregnancy vaccination protocol, and did not coincide with the tetanus vaccination protocol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tetanus vaccine may be laced with anti-fertility drug. International/developing countries</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/032-tetanus-vaccine-may-be-laced-with-anti-fertility-drug.-international-developing-countries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/032-tetanus-vaccine-may-be-laced-with-anti-fertility-drug.-international-developing-countries/</guid>
      <description>(full text)
In the fall of 1994, the World Health Organization held a tetanus vaccination campaign in Mexico. For some reason, however, the vaccine was given exclusively to women of reproductive age (15-45 y.o.). And despite the fact, that one dose of tetanus vaccine gives protection for 10 years, the women were vaccinated five times. A Catholic organization, Human Life International, found it strange and decided to check these vaccines for hCG, and indeed, it turned out the vaccine contained it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>