<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MMR Vaccine on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</title>
    <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/drugs/mmr-vaccine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in MMR Vaccine on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© amantonio, scibook.org 2017–2019</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/drugs/mmr-vaccine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/017/</guid>
      <description>In 2010, two virologists, who had previously worked for Merck, sued the company. They claimed that Merck manipulated the results of the mumps vaccine clinical trial, which allowed the company to remain the exclusive MMR manufacturer in the United States.
The lawsuit states that Merck organized a fictitious vaccine-testing program in the late 90s. The company obliged the scientists to participate in the program, promising them all bonuses if the vaccine got certified, and threatening prison if they were to report this fraud to the FDA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/018/</guid>
      <description>All MMR safety studies described in the section about measles are applicable to mumps as well. Here are some more:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits and expenses due to animal serum used in cell culture production</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/036-benefits-and-expenses-due-to-animal-serum-used-in-cell-culture-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/036-benefits-and-expenses-due-to-animal-serum-used-in-cell-culture-production/</guid>
      <description>20-50% of fetal bovine serum is infected with bovine viral diarrhea virus, as well as other viruses.
We are talking only about the viruses known to science, which constitute only a small fraction of all the existing viruses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CDC Pinkbook Mumps</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/002-cdc-pinkbook-mumps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/002-cdc-pinkbook-mumps/</guid>
      <description>In pre-vaccination times, 15-27% of mumps cases were asymptomatic. The number of asymptomatic cases today is unknown, as it is unclear how the vaccine modifies clinical symptoms. Orchitis (testicular inflammation) is the most common complication of mumps, but it is only possible in post-pubertal males. Orchitis is primarily unilateral. Infertility caused by mumps orchitis is quite rare, even in cases of bilateral orchitis.
Prior to introduction of the vaccine, cases of mumps were not recorded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Co-administration of live measles and yellow fever vaccines and inactivated pentavalent vaccines is associated with increased mortality compared with measles and yellow fever vaccines only. An observational study from Guinea-Bissau</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/015-co-administration-of-live-measles-and-yellow-fever-vaccines-and-inactivated-pentavalent-vaccines-is-associated-with-increased-mortality-compared-with-measles-and-yellow-fever-vaccines-only.-an-observational-study-from-guinea-bissau/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/015-co-administration-of-live-measles-and-yellow-fever-vaccines-and-inactivated-pentavalent-vaccines-is-associated-with-increased-mortality-compared-with-measles-and-yellow-fever-vaccines-only.-an-observational-study-from-guinea-bissau/</guid>
      <description>Children who received a pentavalent vaccine (diphtheria/tetanus/pertussis/Hib/hepatitis B), in addition to measles and yellow fever vaccines, died 7.7 times more often than the children who did not receive a pentavalent vaccine.
In this lecture Susan Humphries explains why the combination of live and killed vaccines leads to this effect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep sequencing reveals persistence of cell-associated mumps vaccine virus in chronic encephalitis</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/025-deep-sequencing-reveals-persistence-of-cell-associated-mumps-vaccine-virus-in-chronic-encephalitis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/025-deep-sequencing-reveals-persistence-of-cell-associated-mumps-vaccine-virus-in-chronic-encephalitis/</guid>
      <description>A 14 months old boy was given an MMR vaccine, and 4 months later he was diagnosed with a severe combined immunodeficiency. He then successfully underwent a bone marrow transplant, but developed chronic encephalitis, and died at the age of 5. A brain biopsy showed that he had the vaccine strain of the mumps virus in his brain. This was the first case of panencephalitis caused by the mumps virus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DTP with or after measles vaccination is associated with increased in-hospital mortality in Guinea-Bissau</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/014-dtp-with-or-after-measles-vaccination-is-associated-with-increased-in-hospital-mortality-in-guinea-bissau/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/014-dtp-with-or-after-measles-vaccination-is-associated-with-increased-in-hospital-mortality-in-guinea-bissau/</guid>
      <description>Children from Guinea-Bissau, who received a diphtheria/tetanus/pertussis vaccine together with the measles vaccine died twice more often that those who only received a measles vaccine.
Authors cite several more studies with the same results in Gambia, Malawi, Congo, Ghana and Senegal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evidence of pestivirus RNA in human virus vaccines</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/038-evidence-of-pestivirus-rna-in-human-virus-vaccines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/038-evidence-of-pestivirus-rna-in-human-virus-vaccines/</guid>
      <description>The authors examined five types of live vaccines and detected bovine viral diarrhea virus RNA in MMR vaccines of two different manufacturers, as well as in two monovalent vaccines against mumps and rubella, which most likely got there from fetal bovine serum.
In infants, this virus might cause gastroenteritis, and in pregnant women, it might lead to the birth of children with microcephaly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factors associated with uptake of measles, mumps, and rubella vaccine (MMR) and use of single antigen vaccines in a contemporary UK cohort: prospective cohort study</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/012-factors-associated-with-uptake-of-measles-mumps-and-rubella-vaccine-mmr-and-use-of-single-antigen-vaccines-in-a-contemporary-uk-cohort-prospective-cohort-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/012-factors-associated-with-uptake-of-measles-mumps-and-rubella-vaccine-mmr-and-use-of-single-antigen-vaccines-in-a-contemporary-uk-cohort-prospective-cohort-study/</guid>
      <description>The higher the level of education, age and income, the more often parents refused the MMR, and chose a non-combined measles vaccine. (United Kingdom)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fetal Bovine Serum RNA Interferes with the Cell Culture derived Extracellular RNA</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/037-fetal-bovine-serum-rna-interferes-with-the-cell-culture-derived-extracellular-rna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/037-fetal-bovine-serum-rna-interferes-with-the-cell-culture-derived-extracellular-rna/</guid>
      <description>Fetal bovine serum contains extracellular RNA, which is impossible to separate from the serum. This RNA interacts with human cells RNA, in which vaccine viruses are grown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Henoch-Schönlein purpura and drug and vaccine use in childhood: a case-control study</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/023-henoch-sch%C3%B6nlein-purpura-and-drug-and-vaccine-use-in-childhood-a-case-control-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/023-henoch-sch%C3%B6nlein-purpura-and-drug-and-vaccine-use-in-childhood-a-case-control-study/</guid>
      <description>In those vaccinated with MMR, the risk of hemorrhagic vasculitis was 3.4 times higher. In children, this disease usually goes away on its own, but in 1% of cases it can lead to kidney failure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knowledge, attitudes, beliefs and practices of general practitioners towards measles and MMR vaccination in southeastern France in 2012</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/014-knowledge-attitudes-beliefs-and-practices-of-general-practitioners-towards-measles-and-mmr-vaccination-in-southeastern-france-in-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/014-knowledge-attitudes-beliefs-and-practices-of-general-practitioners-towards-measles-and-mmr-vaccination-in-southeastern-france-in-2012/</guid>
      <description>13% of doctors do not consider measles a dangerous disease. 12% of doctors consider the second dose of MMR to be useless.
33% of doctors do not believe that MMR vaccination should be mandatory for children under 2 years of age. (France)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mumps vaccine associated orchitis: Evidence supporting a potential immune-mediated mechanism</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/024-mumps-vaccine-associated-orchitis-evidence-supporting-a-potential-immune-mediated-mechanism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/024-mumps-vaccine-associated-orchitis-evidence-supporting-a-potential-immune-mediated-mechanism/</guid>
      <description>Orchitis may well occur as a result of mumps vaccine: [1], [2], [3], [4]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outbreak of aseptic meningitis and mumps after mass vaccination with MMR vaccine using the Leningrad-Zagreb mumps strain</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/021-outbreak-of-aseptic-meningitis-and-mumps-after-mass-vaccination-with-mmr-vaccine-using-the-leningrad-zagreb-mumps-strain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/021-outbreak-of-aseptic-meningitis-and-mumps-after-mass-vaccination-with-mmr-vaccine-using-the-leningrad-zagreb-mumps-strain/</guid>
      <description>The following year, learning from their mistakes, the Brazilian authorities bought MMR with another strain of mumps (Leningrad-Zagreb) and vaccinated 845 thousand children with it. Another outbreak of aseptic meningitis started, and this time the risk of disease was 74 times higher. Sure, it was known that this strain also increases the risk of meningitis, but since the vaccination campaign in the Bahamas did not cause a meningitis outbreak, they decided to see how it would turn out in Brazil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outbreak of aseptic meningitis associated with mass vaccination with a urabe-containing measles-mumps-rubella vaccine: implications for immunization programs</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/019-outbreak-of-aseptic-meningitis-associated-with-mass-vaccination-with-a-urabe-containing-measles-mumps-rubella-vaccine-implications-for-immunization-programs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/019-outbreak-of-aseptic-meningitis-associated-with-mass-vaccination-with-a-urabe-containing-measles-mumps-rubella-vaccine-implications-for-immunization-programs/</guid>
      <description>After the mass MMR vaccination campaign in Brazil with the Japanese strain of mumps (Urabe), an outbreak of aseptic meningitis began. The risk of disease increased by 14-30 times.
The fact that Urabe strain is associated with aseptic meningitis was already known, but Brazilian authorities decided to use this strain anyway, as it is cheaper and more effective than the Jeryl Lynn strain (which is used in the US), and because they thought the risk of meningitis was quite low.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reports of sensorineural deafness after measles, mumps, and rubella immunization</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/006-reports-of-sensorineural-deafness-after-measles-mumps-and-rubella-immunization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/006-reports-of-sensorineural-deafness-after-measles-mumps-and-rubella-immunization/</guid>
      <description>Here is the description of 9 cases of deafness after the MMR vaccine within four years of vaccination. The authors conclude that in 3 cases deafness was unrelated to the vaccine (but they do not provide an explanation for this conclusion), and in 6 other cases it may or may not have been related to the vaccine.
Since unilateral deafness is hard to diagnose in children, and they get vaccinated at the age of 12 months, there may have been other cases that were missed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The effectiveness of the mumps component of the MMR vaccine: a case control study</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/009-the-effectiveness-of-the-mumps-component-of-the-mmr-vaccine-a-case-control-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/009-the-effectiveness-of-the-mumps-component-of-the-mmr-vaccine-a-case-control-study/</guid>
      <description>Mumps outbreak in London. 51% of the patients had been vaccinated. The effectiveness of one dose of the vaccine is 64%. The effectiveness of two doses – 88%. This effectiveness is much lower than is stated in clinical trials, since immunogenicity (i.e. the amount of antibodies) is not an accurate biological marker of the vaccine effectiveness. Moreover, the vaccines might have been improperly stored, which could have caused them to lose their effectiveness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The use of fetal bovine serum: ethical or scientific problem?</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/035-the-use-of-fetal-bovine-serum-ethical-or-scientific-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/035-the-use-of-fetal-bovine-serum-ethical-or-scientific-problem/</guid>
      <description>One of the MMR components (and some other vaccines) is fetal bovine serum. Cells, in which the virus is grown, need to multiply. To do so, they need a nutrient medium with hormones, growth factors, proteins, amino acids, vitamins, etc. Fetal bovine serum is usually used as this medium. Since the serum should preferably be sterile, the blood of calves&amp;rsquo; fetuses is used instead of the cow’s blood.
A pregnant cow is killed and the uterus is removed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vaccination and Allergic Disease: A Birth Cohort Study</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/010-vaccination-and-allergic-disease-a-birth-cohort-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/010-vaccination-and-allergic-disease-a-birth-cohort-study/</guid>
      <description>A study of 30 thousand children from the UK.
Children vaccinated against diphtheria/tetanus/pertussis/polio had asthma 14 times more often and eczema – 9 times more often than unvaccinated children.
Children vaccinated against measles/mumps/rubella had asthma 3.5 times more often and eczema – 4.5 times more often.
The numbers seem to speak for themselves, right? But these figures do not suit the authors, as they want to justify vaccinations. So they do two sleights of hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vaccine-related mumps infections in Thailand and the identification of a novel mutation in the mumps fusion protein</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/010-vaccine-related-mumps-infections-in-thailand-and-the-identification-of-a-novel-mutation-in-the-mumps-fusion-protein/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/010-vaccine-related-mumps-infections-in-thailand-and-the-identification-of-a-novel-mutation-in-the-mumps-fusion-protein/</guid>
      <description>Two weeks after the MMR vaccination of nursing students in Thailand, an outbreak of mumps occurred. The vaccine strain of the virus (Leningrad-Zagreb) was found in those infected. This strain has repeatedly caused mumps outbreaks before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Viral contamination of bovine foetal serum and cell cultures</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/039-viral-contamination-of-bovine-foetal-serum-and-cell-cultures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/039-viral-contamination-of-bovine-foetal-serum-and-cell-cultures/</guid>
      <description>The fact that fetal bovine serum is infected with the bovine viral diarrhea virus was known already in 1977. It is known that this virus passes through placenta and can infect the calf fetus in the uterus. 60% of serum samples in Australia were contaminated with the virus. 8% of the vaccines against Bovine Rhinotracheitis were also contaminated.
The virus was also found in bovine kidney cells, which are used in production of measles vaccine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waning immunity against mumps in vaccinated young adults, France 2013</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/011-waning-immunity-against-mumps-in-vaccinated-young-adults-france-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/011-waning-immunity-against-mumps-in-vaccinated-young-adults-france-2013/</guid>
      <description>In 2013, 15 mumps outbreaks were registered in France. 72% of the cases had been vaccinated twice. The effectiveness of the vaccine was 49% for one dose and 55% for two doses.
Among those who had been vaccinated once, the risk of getting mumps increased by 7% for every year that had passed since the vaccination.
Among those who had been vaccinated twice, the risk of getting mumps increased by 10% for every year that had passed after the second dose.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>