<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Antacids on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</title>
    <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/drugs/antacids/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Antacids on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© amantonio, scibook.org 2017–2019</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/drugs/antacids/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Antacids and dietary supplements with an influence on the gastric pH increase the risk for food sensitization</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/037-antacids-and-dietary-supplements-with-an-influence-on-the-gastric-ph-increase-the-risk-for-food-sensitization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/037-antacids-and-dietary-supplements-with-an-influence-on-the-gastric-ph-increase-the-risk-for-food-sensitization/</guid>
      <description>Aluminum hydroxide and aluminum phosphate are also used as antacids (used to treat heartburn and some other gastrointestinal diseases, many of which are sold without prescription), which in turn leads to allergies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gut: An underestimated target organ for Aluminum</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/036-gut-an-underestimated-target-organ-for-aluminum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/036-gut-an-underestimated-target-organ-for-aluminum/</guid>
      <description>38% of orally consumed aluminum accumulates in the intestinal mucosa.
Even though the intestines absorb only a small amount of aluminum, 2% of aluminum entering the blood remains in the body and accumulates with age.
Aluminum is probably associated with inflammatory bowel disease.
Adults consume most of the aluminum with hot drinks (except coffee) and vegetables (except potato); children also consume it with pasta and confectionary; and babies get it from the formulas, which contain hundreds of times more aluminum than cow milk.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>