<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spain on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</title>
    <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/countries/spain/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spain on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© amantonio, scibook.org 2017–2019</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/countries/spain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/038/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/038/</guid>
      <description>Death from diphtheria in developed countries is so rare that every such case is widely reported in the media. In 2015, a boy died of diphtheria in Spain, and in 2008, a girl died in England. These seem to be the only deaths of children from diphtheria in developed countries in the last 30 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of vaccine human papillomavirus genotypes in squamous intraepithelial lesions (CIN2 - 3)</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/039-identification-of-vaccine-human-papillomavirus-genotypes-in-squamous-intraepithelial-lesions-cin2-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/039-identification-of-vaccine-human-papillomavirus-genotypes-in-squamous-intraepithelial-lesions-cin2-3/</guid>
      <description>Among the unvaccinated women with CIN 2-3 only 28% were infected with the HPV 16 and 18 strains.
9% of the women with CIN 2-3 did not have HPV at all (Barcelona).
In another study, HPV was only found in 60% of the cases of invasive cervical cancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pertussis epidemic despite high levels of vaccination coverage with acellular pertussis vaccine</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/009-pertussis-epidemic-despite-high-levels-of-vaccination-coverage-with-acellular-pertussis-vaccine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/009-pertussis-epidemic-despite-high-levels-of-vaccination-coverage-with-acellular-pertussis-vaccine/</guid>
      <description>This is an epidemiological study in Spain analysing 421 cases of Pertussis, mostly in children under the age of one year. The vast majority of infected individuals (90%) had actually been fully vaccinated. The carriers were mostly fully vaccinated children aged 5-9 years. Only 8% of the 421 cases were hospitalized, and not one died. The authors conclude that despite a high level of vaccination in Spain, whooping cough is totally uncontrollable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seasonal and Pandemic A (H1N1) 2009 influenza vaccination coverage and attitudes among health-care workers in a Spanish University Hospital</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/019-seasonal-and-pandemic-a-h1n1-2009-influenza-vaccination-coverage-and-attitudes-among-health-care-workers-in-a-spanish-university-hospital/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/019-seasonal-and-pandemic-a-h1n1-2009-influenza-vaccination-coverage-and-attitudes-among-health-care-workers-in-a-spanish-university-hospital/</guid>
      <description>More than half of health workers refused to be vaccinated against influenza, and only 16.5% were vaccinated against swine flu during the 2009 pandemic. They doubted the effectiveness of the vaccination and were afraid of side effects. (Madrid, Spain)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>