<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DTaP Vaccine on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</title>
    <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/drugs/dtap-vaccine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DTaP Vaccine on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© amantonio, scibook.org 2017–2019</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/drugs/dtap-vaccine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/003/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/003/</guid>
      <description>Since the 1950s, not a single vaccine against pertussis has been manufactured. Instead, it is always administered as part of a combined vaccine that also includes diphtheria and tetanus. This vaccine, DTP, is a whole-cell pertussis vaccine (plus diphtheria and tetanus). This means that it contains whole bacteria, which have been killed with formalin. While this vaccine has not been used in developed countries since 2001 because of its reactogenicity, it is still used throughout the rest of the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timing of the routine infant and allergy and eczema at one year of age</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/039-timing-of-the-routine-infant-and-allergy-and-eczema-at-one-year-of-age/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/039-timing-of-the-routine-infant-and-allergy-and-eczema-at-one-year-of-age/</guid>
      <description>Girls who received the first dose of DTaP at least one month after the suggested term developed allergies four times less frequently than girls who were vaccinated on time. Both boys and girls developed eczema two times less often if they were vaccinated at least one month after the programmed date.
Here it is also reported that vaccinated mice developed lung pathologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What lies behind the low rates of vaccinations among nurses who treat infants?</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/015-what-lies-behind-the-low-rates-of-vaccinations-among-nurses-who-treat-infants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/015-what-lies-behind-the-low-rates-of-vaccinations-among-nurses-who-treat-infants/</guid>
      <description>After Israeli nurses were asked to vaccinate against whooping cough at 3 months, only 2% (two percent) deigned to do so. And we are talking about nurses working in mother and child centers (tipat halav), that is, those whose main role is to vaccinate children.
Most nurses do not trust health authorities, and desperately resist compulsory vaccinations.
They believe that parents should have the choice to vaccinate a child or not, and they demand the same respect for their rights.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>