<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Autism on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</title>
    <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/diseases/autism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Autism on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© amantonio, scibook.org 2017–2019</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/diseases/autism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Do the aluminum vaccine adjuvants contribute to the rising prevalence of autism?</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/007-do-the-aluminum-vaccine-adjuvants-contribute-to-the-rising-prevalence-of-autism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/007-do-the-aluminum-vaccine-adjuvants-contribute-to-the-rising-prevalence-of-autism/</guid>
      <description>The more vaccinations containing aluminum are given in the country, the more children with ASD there are.
The increase in the number of children with ASD in the US correlates with the increase in the number of aluminum adjuvants used. (r = 0.92, p&amp;lt;0.0001)
The authors use Hill’s criteria and conclude that the relationship between aluminum in vaccines and ASD is probably causal. This article is also worth reading in full.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hepatitis B vaccination of male neonates and autism diagnosis, NHIS 1997-2002</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/023-hepatitis-b-vaccination-of-male-neonates-and-autism-diagnosis-nhis-1997-2002/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/023-hepatitis-b-vaccination-of-male-neonates-and-autism-diagnosis-nhis-1997-2002/</guid>
      <description>Newborn boys vaccinated against hepatitis had a 3 times higher risk of developing autism spectrum disorder, as compared to unvaccinated, or vaccinated at least one month after birth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pilot comparative study on the health of vaccinated and unvaccinated 6- to 12-year old U.S. children</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/003-pilot-comparative-study-on-the-health-of-vaccinated-and-unvaccinated-6-to-12-year-old-u.s.-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/003-pilot-comparative-study-on-the-health-of-vaccinated-and-unvaccinated-6-to-12-year-old-u.s.-children/</guid>
      <description>The study compares homeschooled children in four states of the USA. 405 vaccinated and 261 unvaccinated children.
Acute diseases:
Vaccinated children had chicken pox 4 times less often, whopping cough – 3 times less often and rubella – 10 times less often.
Vaccinated children had otitis media 4 times more often and pneumonia – 6 times more often.
Chronic diseases:
Those vaccinated had allergic rhinitis 30 times more often. They had allergies 4 times more often, ASD – 4 more often, ADHD – 4 times more often, eczema – 3 times more often, learning disabilities – 5 times more often, neurological disorders – 4 times more often.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>