<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unvaccinated on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</title>
    <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Unvaccinated on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© amantonio, scibook.org 2017–2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 14:40:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/001/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/001/</guid>
      <description>Neither CDC, nor FDA, and especially not the pharmaceutical companies, conduct studies comparing vaccinated and unvaccinated children. Here the director from CDC, being back against the wall, admits to this fact at the congressional hearing (20 seconds). (Full version)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/002/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/002/</guid>
      <description>Nonetheless, there are some studies comparing vaccinated and unvaccinated children available. These studies are small, all of them have flaws, but there is nothing better available at the moment. Only the studies comparing vaccinated and unvaccinated cihldren can provide an adequate picture of the real benefits and harm of vaccination, and therefore, despite all their shortcomings, these are the most important studies of all the existing ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Population-Based Cohort Study of Undervaccination in 8 Managed Care Organizations Across the United States</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/006-a-population-based-cohort-study-of-undervaccination-in-8-managed-care-organizations-across-the-united-states/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/006-a-population-based-cohort-study-of-undervaccination-in-8-managed-care-organizations-across-the-united-states/</guid>
      <description>The study compares vaccinated and undervaccinated children in the USA. Undervaccinated are the children who have not received at least one vaccine, or received at least one vaccine even one day later than the prescribed time limit.
Those who were undervaccinated by their parents’ choice used emergency care 9% less often, visited doctors 5% less often, and also had pharyngitis and URTI 11% less often.
The number of undervaccinated children is steadily increasing (from 42% in 2004 to 54% in 2008).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Co-administration of live measles and yellow fever vaccines and inactivated pentavalent vaccines is associated with increased mortality compared with measles and yellow fever vaccines only. An observational study from Guinea-Bissau</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/015-co-administration-of-live-measles-and-yellow-fever-vaccines-and-inactivated-pentavalent-vaccines-is-associated-with-increased-mortality-compared-with-measles-and-yellow-fever-vaccines-only.-an-observational-study-from-guinea-bissau/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/015-co-administration-of-live-measles-and-yellow-fever-vaccines-and-inactivated-pentavalent-vaccines-is-associated-with-increased-mortality-compared-with-measles-and-yellow-fever-vaccines-only.-an-observational-study-from-guinea-bissau/</guid>
      <description>Children who received a pentavalent vaccine (diphtheria/tetanus/pertussis/Hib/hepatitis B), in addition to measles and yellow fever vaccines, died 7.7 times more often than the children who did not receive a pentavalent vaccine.
In this lecture Susan Humphries explains why the combination of live and killed vaccines leads to this effect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DTP with or after measles vaccination is associated with increased in-hospital mortality in Guinea-Bissau</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/014-dtp-with-or-after-measles-vaccination-is-associated-with-increased-in-hospital-mortality-in-guinea-bissau/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/014-dtp-with-or-after-measles-vaccination-is-associated-with-increased-in-hospital-mortality-in-guinea-bissau/</guid>
      <description>Children from Guinea-Bissau, who received a diphtheria/tetanus/pertussis vaccine together with the measles vaccine died twice more often that those who only received a measles vaccine.
Authors cite several more studies with the same results in Gambia, Malawi, Congo, Ghana and Senegal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of diphtheria-tetanus-pertussis or tetanus vaccination on allergies and allergy-related respiratory symptoms among children and adolescents in the United States</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/011-effects-of-diphtheria-tetanus-pertussis-or-tetanus-vaccination-on-allergies-and-allergy-related-respiratory-symptoms-among-children-and-adolescents-in-the-united-states/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/011-effects-of-diphtheria-tetanus-pertussis-or-tetanus-vaccination-on-allergies-and-allergy-related-respiratory-symptoms-among-children-and-adolescents-in-the-united-states/</guid>
      <description>Children vaccinated against tetanus or with the DTP vaccine had asthma twice more often, allergies – 63% more often, and sinusitis – 81% more often, than the unvaccinated ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infant mortality rates regressed against the number of vaccine doses routinely given: Is there a biochemical or synergistic toxicity?</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/008-infant-mortality-rates-regressed-against-the-number-of-vaccine-doses-routinely-given-is-there-a-biochemical-or-synergistic-toxicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/008-infant-mortality-rates-regressed-against-the-number-of-vaccine-doses-routinely-given-is-there-a-biochemical-or-synergistic-toxicity/</guid>
      <description>The authors compare infant mortality in 30 countries, and the number of vaccinations done by the age of 12 months in those countries. There appears to be a linear correlation between them.
The more vaccinations there are in the country, the higher is the mortality rate.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influence of pediatric vaccines on amygdala growth and opioid ligand binding in rhesus macaque infants: A pilot study</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/007-influence-of-pediatric-vaccines-on-amygdala-growth-and-opioid-ligand-binding-in-rhesus-macaque-infants-a-pilot-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/007-influence-of-pediatric-vaccines-on-amygdala-growth-and-opioid-ligand-binding-in-rhesus-macaque-infants-a-pilot-study/</guid>
      <description>Macaques were given childhood vaccines according to the vaccination schedule in USA in 1999 and were compared with the unvaccinated macaques.
The vaccinated macaques had a much larger brain volume (this is observed in autistic children).
The amygdala (brain region responsible for emotions) was much larger in the vaccinated macaques, than the unvaccinated ones. (This also is observed in autistic children).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is infant immunization a risk factor for childhood asthma or allergy?</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/005-is-infant-immunization-a-risk-factor-for-childhood-asthma-or-allergy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/005-is-infant-immunization-a-risk-factor-for-childhood-asthma-or-allergy/</guid>
      <description>New Zealand, 23 unvaccinated (against DTP and Polio) out of 1,256 10-year old children. Out of the vaccinated children 23% had asthma, 22% got consults on asthma, and 30% had allergies.
There wasn’t a single case of asthma, or consults on asthma, or allergies among the unvaccinated children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pilot comparative study on the health of vaccinated and unvaccinated 6- to 12-year old U.S. children</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/003-pilot-comparative-study-on-the-health-of-vaccinated-and-unvaccinated-6-to-12-year-old-u.s.-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/003-pilot-comparative-study-on-the-health-of-vaccinated-and-unvaccinated-6-to-12-year-old-u.s.-children/</guid>
      <description>The study compares homeschooled children in four states of the USA. 405 vaccinated and 261 unvaccinated children.
Acute diseases:
Vaccinated children had chicken pox 4 times less often, whopping cough – 3 times less often and rubella – 10 times less often.
Vaccinated children had otitis media 4 times more often and pneumonia – 6 times more often.
Chronic diseases:
Those vaccinated had allergic rhinitis 30 times more often. They had allergies 4 times more often, ASD – 4 more often, ADHD – 4 times more often, eczema – 3 times more often, learning disabilities – 5 times more often, neurological disorders – 4 times more often.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reduced rate of side effects associated with separate administration of MMR and DTaP-Hib-IPV vaccinations. </title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/018-reduced-rate-of-side-effects-associated-with-separate-administration-of-mmr-and-dtap-hib-ipv-vaccinations./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/018-reduced-rate-of-side-effects-associated-with-separate-administration-of-mmr-and-dtap-hib-ipv-vaccinations./</guid>
      <description>Side effects of vaccination were observed in 57% of children who received MMR and pentavalent vaccine simultaneously, but only in 40% among those, who only received the MMR vaccine.
Authors conclude that, perhaps, the current policy on simultaneous vaccinations should be reviewed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Relative trends in hospitalizations and mortality among infants by the number of vaccine doses and age, based on the Vaccine Adverse Event Reporting System (VAERS), 1990-2010</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/013-relative-trends-in-hospitalizations-and-mortality-among-infants-by-the-number-of-vaccine-doses-and-age-based-on-the-vaccine-adverse-event-reporting-system-vaers-1990-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/013-relative-trends-in-hospitalizations-and-mortality-among-infants-by-the-number-of-vaccine-doses-and-age-based-on-the-vaccine-adverse-event-reporting-system-vaers-1990-2010/</guid>
      <description>The more vaccinations are done at a time, the higher the likelihood of hospitalization and death.The mortality among those who received 5-8 vaccinations was 1.5 times higher than those who received 1-4 vaccinations.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk of Nontargeted Infectious Disease Hospitalizations Among US Children Following Inactivated and Live Vaccines, 2005-2014</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/017-risk-of-nontargeted-infectious-disease-hospitalizations-among-us-children-following-inactivated-and-live-vaccines-2005-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/017-risk-of-nontargeted-infectious-disease-hospitalizations-among-us-children-following-inactivated-and-live-vaccines-2005-2014/</guid>
      <description>In USA, the risk of hospitalization among children whose last vaccine was a live one was twice lower than for those who received the inactivated vaccine as their last one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simultaneous vaccination with MMR and DTaP-IPV-Hib and rate of hospital admissions with any infections: A nationwide register based cohort study</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/016-simultaneous-vaccination-with-mmr-and-dtap-ipv-hib-and-rate-of-hospital-admissions-with-any-infections-a-nationwide-register-based-cohort-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/016-simultaneous-vaccination-with-mmr-and-dtap-ipv-hib-and-rate-of-hospital-admissions-with-any-infections-a-nationwide-register-based-cohort-study/</guid>
      <description>In Denmark, simultaneous administration of MMR with a pentavalent vaccine was associated with increased risk of hospitalization due to lower respiratory tract infections by 27%, compared to the administration of MMR vaccine alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Introduction of Diphtheria-Tetanus-Pertussis and Oral Polio Vaccine Among Young Infants in the Urban African Community: A Natural Experiment</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/004-the-introduction-of-diphtheria-tetanus-pertussis-and-oral-polio-vaccine-among-young-infants-in-the-urban-african-community-a-natural-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/004-the-introduction-of-diphtheria-tetanus-pertussis-and-oral-polio-vaccine-among-young-infants-in-the-urban-african-community-a-natural-experiment/</guid>
      <description>Due to the fact that in Guinea-Bissau children were vaccinated once in three months, it turned out to be a natural experiment. Some children have already been vaccinated by the age of 3-5 months, and some haven’t.
The risk of death in children vaccinated against diphtheria/tetanus/pertussis (DTP) was 10 times higher than that of the unvaccinated children. Children who were also vaccinated against poliomyelitis (OPV) died only 5 times more often that the unvaccinated children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The effect of DPT and BCG vaccinations on atopic disorders</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/012-the-effect-of-dpt-and-bcg-vaccinations-on-atopic-disorders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/012-the-effect-of-dpt-and-bcg-vaccinations-on-atopic-disorders/</guid>
      <description>Among the children vaccinated with the DTP vaccine, 56% had asthma, chronic rhinitis or dermatitis. Among the unvaccinated ones only 9% had those diseases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unvaccinated children are healthier</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/009-unvaccinated-children-are-healthier/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/009-unvaccinated-children-are-healthier/</guid>
      <description>A poll in New Zealand. 226 vaccinated and 269 unvaccinated children.
The vaccinated children had asthma 5 times more often, tonsillitis– 10 times more often, dermatitis – 2 times more often, apnea – 4 times more often, hyperactivity – 4 times more often, otitis media – 4 times more often, and they had ear drainage tube inserted 8 times more often.
5% of the vaccinated children had tonsils removed. There were no tonsils removals among unvaccinated children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vaccination and Allergic Disease: A Birth Cohort Study</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/010-vaccination-and-allergic-disease-a-birth-cohort-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/010-vaccination-and-allergic-disease-a-birth-cohort-study/</guid>
      <description>A study of 30 thousand children from the UK.
Children vaccinated against diphtheria/tetanus/pertussis/polio had asthma 14 times more often and eczema – 9 times more often than unvaccinated children.
Children vaccinated against measles/mumps/rubella had asthma 3.5 times more often and eczema – 4.5 times more often.
The numbers seem to speak for themselves, right? But these figures do not suit the authors, as they want to justify vaccinations. So they do two sleights of hand.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>