<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Australia on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</title>
    <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/countries/australia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Australia on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© amantonio, scibook.org 2017–2019</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/countries/australia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/015/</guid>
      <description>After Australia passed a law obliging parents to vaccinate children to receive child benefits (No jab, no pay), parents living in rich areas of Melbourne began to vaccinate even less. More educated parents, many with a scientific education, doubt the safety, and the need for vaccinations.
Only 20% of those parents who did not vaccinate before the adoption of this law, began to vaccinate because of it.
10% of Australian parents believe that vaccines are associated with autism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding the &#39;who&#39; in whooping cough: vaccinated siblings are important pertussis sources in infants 6 months of age and under</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/010-finding-the-who-in-whooping-cough-vaccinated-siblings-are-important-pertussis-sources-in-infants-6-months-of-age-and-under/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/010-finding-the-who-in-whooping-cough-vaccinated-siblings-are-important-pertussis-sources-in-infants-6-months-of-age-and-under/</guid>
      <description>Most infants six months of age and younger are infected with whooping cough by their fully vaccinated siblings, especially two- and three-year-old siblings. Those who are not infected by their siblings, are often infected by their parents. More: [1].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timing of the routine infant and allergy and eczema at one year of age</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/039-timing-of-the-routine-infant-and-allergy-and-eczema-at-one-year-of-age/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/039-timing-of-the-routine-infant-and-allergy-and-eczema-at-one-year-of-age/</guid>
      <description>Girls who received the first dose of DTaP at least one month after the suggested term developed allergies four times less frequently than girls who were vaccinated on time. Both boys and girls developed eczema two times less often if they were vaccinated at least one month after the programmed date.
Here it is also reported that vaccinated mice developed lung pathologies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>