<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Orchitis on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</title>
    <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/diseases/orchitis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Orchitis on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© amantonio, scibook.org 2017–2019</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/diseases/orchitis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A retrospective survey of the complications of mumps</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/005-a-retrospective-survey-of-the-complications-of-mumps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/005-a-retrospective-survey-of-the-complications-of-mumps/</guid>
      <description>Here is the analysis of 2,482 cases of mumps hospitalization in 1958-1969 in 16 hospitals in England. They constitute the majority of mumps cases that required hospitalization in the country. Half of the patients were 15 years old or older. Complications were recorded in 42% of all cases. Three patients died, but two of them had another serious underlying illness and mumps might not have had anything to do with the death, and the third patient was most probably misdiagnosed and did not even have mumps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CDC Pinkbook Mumps</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/002-cdc-pinkbook-mumps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/002-cdc-pinkbook-mumps/</guid>
      <description>In pre-vaccination times, 15-27% of mumps cases were asymptomatic. The number of asymptomatic cases today is unknown, as it is unclear how the vaccine modifies clinical symptoms. Orchitis (testicular inflammation) is the most common complication of mumps, but it is only possible in post-pubertal males. Orchitis is primarily unilateral. Infertility caused by mumps orchitis is quite rare, even in cases of bilateral orchitis.
Prior to introduction of the vaccine, cases of mumps were not recorded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mumps vaccine associated orchitis: Evidence supporting a potential immune-mediated mechanism</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/024-mumps-vaccine-associated-orchitis-evidence-supporting-a-potential-immune-mediated-mechanism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/024-mumps-vaccine-associated-orchitis-evidence-supporting-a-potential-immune-mediated-mechanism/</guid>
      <description>Orchitis may well occur as a result of mumps vaccine: [1], [2], [3], [4]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waning immunity against mumps in vaccinated young adults, France 2013</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/011-waning-immunity-against-mumps-in-vaccinated-young-adults-france-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/011-waning-immunity-against-mumps-in-vaccinated-young-adults-france-2013/</guid>
      <description>In 2013, 15 mumps outbreaks were registered in France. 72% of the cases had been vaccinated twice. The effectiveness of the vaccine was 49% for one dose and 55% for two doses.
Among those who had been vaccinated once, the risk of getting mumps increased by 7% for every year that had passed since the vaccination.
Among those who had been vaccinated twice, the risk of getting mumps increased by 10% for every year that had passed after the second dose.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>