<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Asthma on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</title>
    <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/diseases/asthma/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Asthma on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© amantonio, scibook.org 2017–2019</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/diseases/asthma/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Delay in diphtheria, pertussis, tetanus vaccination is associated with a reduced risk of childhood asthma</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/033-delay-in-diphtheria-pertussis-tetanus-vaccination-is-associated-with-a-reduced-risk-of-childhood-asthma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/033-delay-in-diphtheria-pertussis-tetanus-vaccination-is-associated-with-a-reduced-risk-of-childhood-asthma/</guid>
      <description>In an analysis of 11,000 children who received a whole-cell vaccine in Canada, those who received the first dose of the vaccine two months later than usual developed asthma far less often (2-fold lower chance). Furthermore, those who received all three doses of the vaccine later in childhood had a 2.5-fold lower risk of developing asthma.
This phenomenon is due to the fact that the immune reaction shifts towards Th2. The exact cause of asthma is not yet known, but according to one of the prevailing theories, asthma is caused by increased hygiene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early childhood infection and atopic disorder</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/035-early-childhood-infection-and-atopic-disorder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/035-early-childhood-infection-and-atopic-disorder/</guid>
      <description>In vaccinated with whole-cell vaccine, the risk of allergy was 76% higher. In those who took antibiotics in the first two years of life, the risk of allergy was 2 times higher.
Taking one course of antibiotics increased the risk of developing an allergy by 85%, two courses of antibiotics increased the risk 3-fold, and three courses of antibiotics increased the risk 8-fold.
Those who had measles and had not received the vaccine, had a 45% lower risk of developing an allergy (note: in this case there was no statistical significance).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of diphtheria-tetanus-pertussis or tetanus vaccination on allergies and allergy-related respiratory symptoms among children and adolescents in the United States</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/034-effects-of-diphtheria-tetanus-pertussis-or-tetanus-vaccination-on-allergies-and-allergy-related-respiratory-symptoms-among-children-and-adolescents-in-the-united-states/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/034-effects-of-diphtheria-tetanus-pertussis-or-tetanus-vaccination-on-allergies-and-allergy-related-respiratory-symptoms-among-children-and-adolescents-in-the-united-states/</guid>
      <description>The vaccinated had asthma twice as often as the unvaccinated. The authors believe that 50% of asthma cases (2.9 million) in US children and adolescents would be prevented if the DTP or tetanus vaccination was not administered. More: [1]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of diphtheria-tetanus-pertussis or tetanus vaccination on allergies and allergy-related respiratory symptoms among children and adolescents in the United States</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/011-effects-of-diphtheria-tetanus-pertussis-or-tetanus-vaccination-on-allergies-and-allergy-related-respiratory-symptoms-among-children-and-adolescents-in-the-united-states/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/011-effects-of-diphtheria-tetanus-pertussis-or-tetanus-vaccination-on-allergies-and-allergy-related-respiratory-symptoms-among-children-and-adolescents-in-the-united-states/</guid>
      <description>Children vaccinated against tetanus or with the DTP vaccine had asthma twice more often, allergies – 63% more often, and sinusitis – 81% more often, than the unvaccinated ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is infant immunization a risk factor for childhood asthma or allergy?</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/005-is-infant-immunization-a-risk-factor-for-childhood-asthma-or-allergy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/005-is-infant-immunization-a-risk-factor-for-childhood-asthma-or-allergy/</guid>
      <description>New Zealand, 23 unvaccinated (against DTP and Polio) out of 1,256 10-year old children. Out of the vaccinated children 23% had asthma, 22% got consults on asthma, and 30% had allergies.
There wasn’t a single case of asthma, or consults on asthma, or allergies among the unvaccinated children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pertussis vaccination and asthma: is there a link?</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/036-pertussis-vaccination-and-asthma-is-there-a-link/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/036-pertussis-vaccination-and-asthma-is-there-a-link/</guid>
      <description>Those individuals who had been vaccinated with a whole-cell vaccine, had a 5.4-fold greater chance of developing asthma compared to unvaccinated individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pilot comparative study on the health of vaccinated and unvaccinated 6- to 12-year old U.S. children</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/003-pilot-comparative-study-on-the-health-of-vaccinated-and-unvaccinated-6-to-12-year-old-u.s.-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/003-pilot-comparative-study-on-the-health-of-vaccinated-and-unvaccinated-6-to-12-year-old-u.s.-children/</guid>
      <description>The study compares homeschooled children in four states of the USA. 405 vaccinated and 261 unvaccinated children.
Acute diseases:
Vaccinated children had chicken pox 4 times less often, whopping cough – 3 times less often and rubella – 10 times less often.
Vaccinated children had otitis media 4 times more often and pneumonia – 6 times more often.
Chronic diseases:
Those vaccinated had allergic rhinitis 30 times more often. They had allergies 4 times more often, ASD – 4 more often, ADHD – 4 times more often, eczema – 3 times more often, learning disabilities – 5 times more often, neurological disorders – 4 times more often.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The effect of DPT and BCG vaccinations on atopic disorders</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/012-the-effect-of-dpt-and-bcg-vaccinations-on-atopic-disorders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/012-the-effect-of-dpt-and-bcg-vaccinations-on-atopic-disorders/</guid>
      <description>Among the children vaccinated with the DTP vaccine, 56% had asthma, chronic rhinitis or dermatitis. Among the unvaccinated ones only 9% had those diseases.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>