<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Natural immunity on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</title>
    <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/conditions/natural-immunity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Natural immunity on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© amantonio, scibook.org 2017–2019</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/conditions/natural-immunity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Human intestinal carriers of tetanus spores in California</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/013-human-intestinal-carriers-of-tetanus-spores-in-california/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/013-human-intestinal-carriers-of-tetanus-spores-in-california/</guid>
      <description>In four years from 1922 to 1925 in California, 245 cases of tetanus have been recorded. Mortality rate was 67%.
Among the 530 people in the study, the authors found bacteria in the intestines of 24%. They believe that the presence of tetanus bacteria in the intestines depends on the microflora, since they have always seen other types of bacteria along with tetanus bacteria, and did not see other bacteria, when the tetanus bacteria were absent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naturally Acquired Immunity to Tetanus Toxin in an Isolated Community</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/006-naturally-acquired-immunity-to-tetanus-toxin-in-an-isolated-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/006-naturally-acquired-immunity-to-tetanus-toxin-in-an-isolated-community/</guid>
      <description>There is a complete medical consensus on that natural immunity against tetanus is impossible, and only a vaccine can prevent the disease.
The authors ran blood tests of two hundred randomly selected immigrants from Ethiopia to Israel and found tetanus antibodies in 98% of them. 30% of them had the level of antibodies that is considered protective (above 0.01 UI/ml). None of them have been vaccinated.
The amount of antibodies increased with age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naturally acquired antibodies to tetanus toxin in humans and animals from the Galápagos islands</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/008-naturally-acquired-antibodies-to-tetanus-toxin-in-humans-and-animals-from-the-gal%C3%A1pagos-islands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/008-naturally-acquired-antibodies-to-tetanus-toxin-in-humans-and-animals-from-the-gal%C3%A1pagos-islands/</guid>
      <description>The level of tetanus antibodies of 57 tested residents of Galapagos Islands was above the protective level. None of them had been vaccinated. Two of them have had tetanus in the past. This contradicts the accepted dogma that having had the disease does not give immunity.
They also checked nine animals (horses, cows, donkeys and a dog) and all of them had sufficient levels of antibodies.
The authors believe that immunity is produced by swallowing bacterial spores that multiply in the intestines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Studies on the relation of tetanus bacilli in the digestive tract to tetanus antitoxin in the blood</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/010-studies-on-the-relation-of-tetanus-bacilli-in-the-digestive-tract-to-tetanus-antitoxin-in-the-blood/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/010-studies-on-the-relation-of-tetanus-bacilli-in-the-digestive-tract-to-tetanus-antitoxin-in-the-blood/</guid>
      <description>Continuing with the previous article. 26 people who had tetanus bacteria in their stool had antibodies in their blood.
Among the 30 people who did not have bacteria in their stool, 28 did not have tetanus antibodies either. The authors proved that tetanus bacteria multiply in human intestines. They also explained why despite the fact that a third of population have tetanus bacteria living in their intestines, they get sick with it very rarely, even after surgeries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study of tetanus agglutinins and antitoxin in human serums</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/012-study-of-tetanus-agglutinins-and-antitoxin-in-human-serums/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/012-study-of-tetanus-agglutinins-and-antitoxin-in-human-serums/</guid>
      <description>The researchers ran blood tests of 104 California residents. Agglutinins to several strains of tetanus bacteria were found in the blood of 80% of them, but they did not have antibodies. The authors believe that tetanus bacteria were in the intestines of these people in the past, but did not survive there and thus they do not have the antitoxin.
Tetanus agglutinins have not been researched since then.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tetanus immunity in kibbutz women</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/007-tetanus-immunity-in-kibbutz-women/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/007-tetanus-immunity-in-kibbutz-women/</guid>
      <description>Researchers ran blood tests of 120 randomly selected women living in Israeli kibbutzim. All of them had sufficient levels of antibodies against tetanus toxin, despite the fact that 12.5% of them had never been vaccinated.
Many of them were not fully vaccinated (from 6% among the young to 68% among the elderly).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The immunity produced by the growth of tetanus bacilli in the digestive tract</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/011-the-immunity-produced-by-the-growth-of-tetanus-bacilli-in-the-digestive-tract/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/011-the-immunity-produced-by-the-growth-of-tetanus-bacilli-in-the-digestive-tract/</guid>
      <description>Guinea pigs that were fed tetanus bacteria developed antibodies in six months. There are many strains of tetanus bacteria, however, and the antibodies were produced only for the strain, which was fed to them. They did not get immunity from other strains. Those who were fed with several strains, developed immunity to all the strains.
In one of the experiments the authors infected the guinea pigs with tetanus and all but two of them died.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The tetanus bacillus as an intestinal saprophyte in man</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/009-the-tetanus-bacillus-as-an-intestinal-saprophyte-in-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/009-the-tetanus-bacillus-as-an-intestinal-saprophyte-in-man/</guid>
      <description>The answer to the question, how natural immunity is produced was already given back in the 20s of last century. Tetanus bacteria were found in the intestines of 35% of the 78 men tested in Beijing. Tetanus was a very rare disease in China in early 20th century (not counting the neonatal tetanus).
Researchers found tetanus bacteria in the patients’ stool even after they spent three months in the hospital on a virtually sterile diet.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>