<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sudden infant death syndrome (SIDS) on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</title>
    <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/diseases/sudden-infant-death-syndrome-sids/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sudden infant death syndrome (SIDS) on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© amantonio, scibook.org 2017–2019</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/diseases/sudden-infant-death-syndrome-sids/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Possible temporal association between diphtheria-tetanus toxoid-pertussis vaccination and sudden infant death syndrome</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/037-possible-temporal-association-between-diphtheria-tetanus-toxoid-pertussis-vaccination-and-sudden-infant-death-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/037-possible-temporal-association-between-diphtheria-tetanus-toxoid-pertussis-vaccination-and-sudden-infant-death-syndrome/</guid>
      <description>The DTP vaccine has been associated with sudden infant death syndrome (SIDS) in Los Angeles, and visits to the doctor have also been associated with SIDS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The True Story of Pertussis Vaccination: A Sordid Legacy?</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/005-the-true-story-of-pertussis-vaccination-a-sordid-legacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/005-the-true-story-of-pertussis-vaccination-a-sordid-legacy/</guid>
      <description>A long but informative article on the history of the pertussis vaccine. If you still believe that the main goal of pharmaceutical companies is to create effective and safe drugs, this article might make you see things differently; we highly recommend reading it!
- The pertussis toxin is added to the whole-cell vaccine. This toxin increases the permeability of the blood-brain barrier, rendering this barrier more penetrable to other toxins and viruses.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>