<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UK on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</title>
    <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/countries/uk/</link>
    <description>Recent content in UK on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© amantonio, scibook.org 2017–2019</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/countries/uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/038/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/038/</guid>
      <description>Death from diphtheria in developed countries is so rare that every such case is widely reported in the media. In 2015, a boy died of diphtheria in Spain, and in 2008, a girl died in England. These seem to be the only deaths of children from diphtheria in developed countries in the last 30 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/020/</guid>
      <description>Urabe strain had been used in Great Britain since 1988, and stopped being used in 1992, only after the manufacturers declared that they are stopping production. However, according to the published documents, authorities knew about the dangers of this strain in 1987 already.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A retrospective survey of the complications of mumps</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/005-a-retrospective-survey-of-the-complications-of-mumps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/005-a-retrospective-survey-of-the-complications-of-mumps/</guid>
      <description>Here is the analysis of 2,482 cases of mumps hospitalization in 1958-1969 in 16 hospitals in England. They constitute the majority of mumps cases that required hospitalization in the country. Half of the patients were 15 years old or older. Complications were recorded in 42% of all cases. Three patients died, but two of them had another serious underlying illness and mumps might not have had anything to do with the death, and the third patient was most probably misdiagnosed and did not even have mumps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Outbreak Of Diphtheria In A Highly Immunized Community</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/015-an-outbreak-of-diphtheria-in-a-highly-immunized-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/015-an-outbreak-of-diphtheria-in-a-highly-immunized-community/</guid>
      <description>Diphtheria outbreak in a British school in 1946 (18 cases). All but two (or three) children have been vaccinated (which is probably the reason why no one died, the authors believe).
Among the 23 unvaccinated children, 13% got sick. Among the 299 vaccinated children, 5% got sick.
One of the unvaccinated children has actually been vaccinated, but more than ten years ago. If he is excluded, then the percentage of sick children among the unvaccinated goes down to 9%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differences in risk factors for partial and no immunization in the first year of life: prospective cohort study</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/009-differences-in-risk-factors-for-partial-and-no-immunization-in-the-first-year-of-life-prospective-cohort-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/009-differences-in-risk-factors-for-partial-and-no-immunization-in-the-first-year-of-life-prospective-cohort-study/</guid>
      <description>Non-vaccinating mothers are older and more educated than mothers who vaccinate. (United Kingdom)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early childhood infection and atopic disorder</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/035-early-childhood-infection-and-atopic-disorder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/035-early-childhood-infection-and-atopic-disorder/</guid>
      <description>In vaccinated with whole-cell vaccine, the risk of allergy was 76% higher. In those who took antibiotics in the first two years of life, the risk of allergy was 2 times higher.
Taking one course of antibiotics increased the risk of developing an allergy by 85%, two courses of antibiotics increased the risk 3-fold, and three courses of antibiotics increased the risk 8-fold.
Those who had measles and had not received the vaccine, had a 45% lower risk of developing an allergy (note: in this case there was no statistical significance).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of diphtheria-tetanus-pertussis or tetanus vaccination on allergies and allergy-related respiratory symptoms among children and adolescents in the United States</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/034-effects-of-diphtheria-tetanus-pertussis-or-tetanus-vaccination-on-allergies-and-allergy-related-respiratory-symptoms-among-children-and-adolescents-in-the-united-states/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/034-effects-of-diphtheria-tetanus-pertussis-or-tetanus-vaccination-on-allergies-and-allergy-related-respiratory-symptoms-among-children-and-adolescents-in-the-united-states/</guid>
      <description>The vaccinated had asthma twice as often as the unvaccinated. The authors believe that 50% of asthma cases (2.9 million) in US children and adolescents would be prevented if the DTP or tetanus vaccination was not administered. More: [1]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factors associated with uptake of measles, mumps, and rubella vaccine (MMR) and use of single antigen vaccines in a contemporary UK cohort: prospective cohort study</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/012-factors-associated-with-uptake-of-measles-mumps-and-rubella-vaccine-mmr-and-use-of-single-antigen-vaccines-in-a-contemporary-uk-cohort-prospective-cohort-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/012-factors-associated-with-uptake-of-measles-mumps-and-rubella-vaccine-mmr-and-use-of-single-antigen-vaccines-in-a-contemporary-uk-cohort-prospective-cohort-study/</guid>
      <description>The higher the level of education, age and income, the more often parents refused the MMR, and chose a non-combined measles vaccine. (United Kingdom)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increase in pertussis may be due to increased recognition and diagnosis</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/015-increase-in-pertussis-may-be-due-to-increased-recognition-and-diagnosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/015-increase-in-pertussis-may-be-due-to-increased-recognition-and-diagnosis/</guid>
      <description>An article by a British doctor states that, according to his long-term experience, whooping cough hasn&amp;rsquo;t disappeared. In fact, after vaccination was implemented, whooping cough only disappeared from official records because doctors stopped diagnosing it.
This article reports that even though vaccination coverage against pertussis in England fell from 78% to 49% between the 1960s and the 1970s, whooping cough-related mortality during this same period decreased 3-fold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prevention of mumps</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/004-prevention-of-mumps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/004-prevention-of-mumps/</guid>
      <description>13 years later, BMJ wonders again whether the UK needs yet another vaccine for infants.
Mumps is not subject to registration, thus the number of cases is unknown, especially since 40% of mumps cases are asymptomatic. Perhaps a combination vaccine with measles is justifiable. This vaccine could be given to children when they start school, for those who have not yet had mumps or measles.
Would the 50% of parents, who agree to the measles vaccine today, agree to another vaccine in addition to it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Severity of whooping cough in England before and after the decline in pertussis immunization</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/038-severity-of-whooping-cough-in-england-before-and-after-the-decline-in-pertussis-immunization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/038-severity-of-whooping-cough-in-england-before-and-after-the-decline-in-pertussis-immunization/</guid>
      <description>After the vaccination coverage in England fell sharply due to fear of the DTP vaccine, the number of pertussis cases and pertussis-related deaths fell 4-fold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tetanus in Injecting Drug Users, United Kingdom</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/028-tetanus-in-injecting-drug-users-united-kingdom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/028-tetanus-in-injecting-drug-users-united-kingdom/</guid>
      <description>Until 2003, tetanus was a rare disease in Great Britain, and mostly happened among the elderly. After 2003, drug users began to get infected with tetanus. In 2003, there were 35 cases of tetanus, and two of them died. The authors researched for common factors and found out that they got sick from infected heroin from Liverpool. The authors urge the doctors and prison staff to vaccinate drug users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The effectiveness of the mumps component of the MMR vaccine: a case control study</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/009-the-effectiveness-of-the-mumps-component-of-the-mmr-vaccine-a-case-control-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/009-the-effectiveness-of-the-mumps-component-of-the-mmr-vaccine-a-case-control-study/</guid>
      <description>Mumps outbreak in London. 51% of the patients had been vaccinated. The effectiveness of one dose of the vaccine is 64%. The effectiveness of two doses – 88%. This effectiveness is much lower than is stated in clinical trials, since immunogenicity (i.e. the amount of antibodies) is not an accurate biological marker of the vaccine effectiveness. Moreover, the vaccines might have been improperly stored, which could have caused them to lose their effectiveness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vaccinating health care workers during an influenza pandemic</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/017-vaccinating-health-care-workers-during-an-influenza-pandemic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/physicians/017-vaccinating-health-care-workers-during-an-influenza-pandemic/</guid>
      <description>41% of healthcare workers refused to vaccinate against swine flu during the 2009 pandemic. They believed that the vaccine was ineffective, and there were side effects, and in general, this infection usually passes easily.
57% of healthcare workers refused to get vaccinated for regular flu. (London, Great Britain)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vaccination and Allergic Disease: A Birth Cohort Study</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/010-vaccination-and-allergic-disease-a-birth-cohort-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/010-vaccination-and-allergic-disease-a-birth-cohort-study/</guid>
      <description>A study of 30 thousand children from the UK.
Children vaccinated against diphtheria/tetanus/pertussis/polio had asthma 14 times more often and eczema – 9 times more often than unvaccinated children.
Children vaccinated against measles/mumps/rubella had asthma 3.5 times more often and eczema – 4.5 times more often.
The numbers seem to speak for themselves, right? But these figures do not suit the authors, as they want to justify vaccinations. So they do two sleights of hand.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>