<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Canada on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</title>
    <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/countries/canada/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Canada on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© amantonio, scibook.org 2017–2019</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/countries/canada/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Population-Based Evaluation of a Publicly Funded, School-Based HPV Vaccine Program in British Columbia, Canada: Parental Factors Associated with HPV Vaccine Receipt</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/010-a-population-based-evaluation-of-a-publicly-funded-school-based-hpv-vaccine-program-in-british-columbia-canada-parental-factors-associated-with-hpv-vaccine-receipt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/010-a-population-based-evaluation-of-a-publicly-funded-school-based-hpv-vaccine-program-in-british-columbia-canada-parental-factors-associated-with-hpv-vaccine-receipt/</guid>
      <description>More educated parents more often refused HPV vaccines for their daughters. (Canada)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Booster immunization for diphtheria and tetanus: no evidence of need in adults</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/013-booster-immunization-for-diphtheria-and-tetanus-no-evidence-of-need-in-adults/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/013-booster-immunization-for-diphtheria-and-tetanus-no-evidence-of-need-in-adults/</guid>
      <description>Recommendations for getting booster vaccines against diphtheria and tetanus every ten years are based on serological studies, according to which, the elderly have lower level of antibodies. However, the goal of the vaccination is to prevent disease, not the production of antibodies. In Canada, the incidence of diphtheria does not increase with age; neither does the tetanus mortality rate increase.
The authors conclude that the benefit from booster vaccines against diphtheria and tetanus in adults, does not justify neither the risks, nor the cost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delay in diphtheria, pertussis, tetanus vaccination is associated with a reduced risk of childhood asthma</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/033-delay-in-diphtheria-pertussis-tetanus-vaccination-is-associated-with-a-reduced-risk-of-childhood-asthma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/033-delay-in-diphtheria-pertussis-tetanus-vaccination-is-associated-with-a-reduced-risk-of-childhood-asthma/</guid>
      <description>In an analysis of 11,000 children who received a whole-cell vaccine in Canada, those who received the first dose of the vaccine two months later than usual developed asthma far less often (2-fold lower chance). Furthermore, those who received all three doses of the vaccine later in childhood had a 2.5-fold lower risk of developing asthma.
This phenomenon is due to the fact that the immune reaction shifts towards Th2. The exact cause of asthma is not yet known, but according to one of the prevailing theories, asthma is caused by increased hygiene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Observations on Diphtheria in the Immunized</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/017-some-observations-on-diphtheria-in-the-immunized/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/017-some-observations-on-diphtheria-in-the-immunized/</guid>
      <description>In the early 1940s, Canada had a diphtheria epidemic (1,028 cases, 4.3% mortality rate). 24% of the patients were vaccinated (or protected). Among them, five have died (one of them was vaccinated just six months before getting sick).
Overall, those vaccinated had milder symptoms. The authors conclude that the vaccine is effective, but not 100%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Diphtheria Epidemic in Halifax</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/016-the-diphtheria-epidemic-in-halifax/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/016-the-diphtheria-epidemic-in-halifax/</guid>
      <description>Diphtheria outbreak in Halifax (Canada) in 1940. 66 cases, of which 30% were fully vaccinated.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>