<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Allergy on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</title>
    <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/diseases/allergy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Allergy on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© amantonio, scibook.org 2017–2019</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/diseases/allergy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/031/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/031/</guid>
      <description>Aluminum hydroxide is used to stimulate allergies in mice.
Intracerebral injections of aluminum hydroxide cause epilepsy in monkeys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/004/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/004/</guid>
      <description>The concept of allergies was unknown until 1906. It was invented by an Austrian pediatrician and used to describe the strange symptoms he observed in those who received the diphtheria immunoglobulin.
The concept of anaphylactic shock also did not exist until 1902.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of diphtheria-tetanus-pertussis or tetanus vaccination on allergies and allergy-related respiratory symptoms among children and adolescents in the United States</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/011-effects-of-diphtheria-tetanus-pertussis-or-tetanus-vaccination-on-allergies-and-allergy-related-respiratory-symptoms-among-children-and-adolescents-in-the-united-states/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/011-effects-of-diphtheria-tetanus-pertussis-or-tetanus-vaccination-on-allergies-and-allergy-related-respiratory-symptoms-among-children-and-adolescents-in-the-united-states/</guid>
      <description>Children vaccinated against tetanus or with the DTP vaccine had asthma twice more often, allergies – 63% more often, and sinusitis – 81% more often, than the unvaccinated ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is infant immunization a risk factor for childhood asthma or allergy?</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/005-is-infant-immunization-a-risk-factor-for-childhood-asthma-or-allergy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/005-is-infant-immunization-a-risk-factor-for-childhood-asthma-or-allergy/</guid>
      <description>New Zealand, 23 unvaccinated (against DTP and Polio) out of 1,256 10-year old children. Out of the vaccinated children 23% had asthma, 22% got consults on asthma, and 30% had allergies.
There wasn’t a single case of asthma, or consults on asthma, or allergies among the unvaccinated children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pilot comparative study on the health of vaccinated and unvaccinated 6- to 12-year old U.S. children</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/003-pilot-comparative-study-on-the-health-of-vaccinated-and-unvaccinated-6-to-12-year-old-u.s.-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/003-pilot-comparative-study-on-the-health-of-vaccinated-and-unvaccinated-6-to-12-year-old-u.s.-children/</guid>
      <description>The study compares homeschooled children in four states of the USA. 405 vaccinated and 261 unvaccinated children.
Acute diseases:
Vaccinated children had chicken pox 4 times less often, whopping cough – 3 times less often and rubella – 10 times less often.
Vaccinated children had otitis media 4 times more often and pneumonia – 6 times more often.
Chronic diseases:
Those vaccinated had allergic rhinitis 30 times more often. They had allergies 4 times more often, ASD – 4 more often, ADHD – 4 times more often, eczema – 3 times more often, learning disabilities – 5 times more often, neurological disorders – 4 times more often.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vaccination and Allergic Disease: A Birth Cohort Study</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/010-vaccination-and-allergic-disease-a-birth-cohort-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/unvaccinated/010-vaccination-and-allergic-disease-a-birth-cohort-study/</guid>
      <description>A study of 30 thousand children from the UK.
Children vaccinated against diphtheria/tetanus/pertussis/polio had asthma 14 times more often and eczema – 9 times more often than unvaccinated children.
Children vaccinated against measles/mumps/rubella had asthma 3.5 times more often and eczema – 4.5 times more often.
The numbers seem to speak for themselves, right? But these figures do not suit the authors, as they want to justify vaccinations. So they do two sleights of hand.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>