<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anti-vaxxers on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</title>
    <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Anti-vaxxers on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© amantonio, scibook.org 2017–2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 23:26:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/001/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/001/</guid>
      <description>Scientists usually allocate very few grants for research on the safety of vaccinations, adjuvants and other vaccine components. However, there is more than enough money to research why people are not vaccinated, and how to make them vaccinate their children. Therefore, there are many studies characterizing anti-invasive parents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/002/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/002/</guid>
      <description>It is believed that anti-vaccination is usually uneducated, religious and anti-scientific people. However, scientific evidence suggests otherwise. Most anti-vaccines are well-educated and wealthy.
In some private schools in Los Angeles, less than 20% of children are vaccinated. How can it be that these rich and educated people do not vaccinate their children? Do they not know that vaccinations are completely safe, and that they protect against terrible diseases? Or maybe they know something about vaccinations that others do not?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/015/</guid>
      <description>After Australia passed a law obliging parents to vaccinate children to receive child benefits (No jab, no pay), parents living in rich areas of Melbourne began to vaccinate even less. More educated parents, many with a scientific education, doubt the safety, and the need for vaccinations.
Only 20% of those parents who did not vaccinate before the adoption of this law, began to vaccinate because of it.
10% of Australian parents believe that vaccines are associated with autism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/017/</guid>
      <description>Most of these studies come to the same conclusions. Parents who do not vaccinate their children are older, more educated and more affluent. Please stop treating them like idiots. [1], [2], [3].
And here are some more unusually important studies for which taxpayers&amp;rsquo; money was used:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/028/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/028/</guid>
      <description>There are a lot of similar studies, here are a few more, for those who want to further delve into this fun topic: [1], [2], [3], [4], [5], [6], [7], [8], [9].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/029/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/029/</guid>
      <description>Professor of Pediatrics Dr. Carol J. Baker offers a simple solution to the anti-vaccination problem. Since anti-vaccinationers are mostly white and educated, she suggests getting rid of white people in the US.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/030/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/030/</guid>
      <description>For all these studies there were grants. But adequate vaccine safety studies, those that lasted more than a few days, and would use a real placebo - there is no money for that.
But you stay there, all the best to you, and be happy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Population-Based Evaluation of a Publicly Funded, School-Based HPV Vaccine Program in British Columbia, Canada: Parental Factors Associated with HPV Vaccine Receipt</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/010-a-population-based-evaluation-of-a-publicly-funded-school-based-hpv-vaccine-program-in-british-columbia-canada-parental-factors-associated-with-hpv-vaccine-receipt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/010-a-population-based-evaluation-of-a-publicly-funded-school-based-hpv-vaccine-program-in-british-columbia-canada-parental-factors-associated-with-hpv-vaccine-receipt/</guid>
      <description>More educated parents more often refused HPV vaccines for their daughters. (Canada)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A comparison of the use of language in in-formation and anti-vaccination in the response to a high profile Facebook post</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/020-a-comparison-of-the-use-of-language-in-in-formation-and-anti-vaccination-in-the-response-to-a-high-profile-facebook-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/020-a-comparison-of-the-use-of-language-in-in-formation-and-anti-vaccination-in-the-response-to-a-high-profile-facebook-post/</guid>
      <description>The authors of the study analyzed comments on the post of Mark Zuckerberg on Facebook. They concluded that anti-vaccination comments were more analytical, and were greater in this case. Comments on vaccines were characterized by increased anxiety.
Here the authors analyzed the anti-vaccination movement on Facebook, and concluded that the majority of participants in anti-vaccination groups are women.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acceptance of human papillomavirus vaccination among Californian parents of daughters: a representative statewide analysis</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/013-acceptance-of-human-papillomavirus-vaccination-among-californian-parents-of-daughters-a-representative-statewide-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/013-acceptance-of-human-papillomavirus-vaccination-among-californian-parents-of-daughters-a-representative-statewide-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Parents with higher education and conservatives rarely allowed their daughters to get vaccinated against HPV. Parents who did not finish school, Catholics and liberals more often allowed their daughters to have this vaccination. (California, United States)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antivaccination activists on the world wide web</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/022-antivaccination-activists-on-the-world-wide-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/022-antivaccination-activists-on-the-world-wide-web/</guid>
      <description>In 43% of queries about vaccinations, search engines showed anti-vaccination sites in the top ten. In Google, 100% of the sites in the top ten were anti-vaccine. More than half of the sites cite doctors who speak out against vaccination. 75% cite &amp;ldquo;scientific&amp;rdquo; sources.
The authors conclude that there is a high probability that parents stumble on anti-vaccination materials on the Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Children Who Have Received No Vaccines: Who Are They and Where Do They Live?</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/003-children-who-have-received-no-vaccines-who-are-they-and-where-do-they-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/003-children-who-have-received-no-vaccines-who-are-they-and-where-do-they-live/</guid>
      <description>Unvaccinated children are mostly white. Their mothers are over 30, married, have an academic degree, and their families earn more than $ 75,000 a year. (USA)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clinician-parent discussions about in fl uenza vaccination of children and their association with vaccine acceptance</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/018-clinician-parent-discussions-about-in-fl-uenza-vaccination-of-children-and-their-association-with-vaccine-acceptance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/018-clinician-parent-discussions-about-in-fl-uenza-vaccination-of-children-and-their-association-with-vaccine-acceptance/</guid>
      <description>If the doctor says &amp;ldquo;we will do the flu vaccine today,&amp;rdquo; 72% of parents agree. And if the doctor asks, “are we going to be vaccinated for flu today?”, Only 17% agree.
If a doctor recommends a flu shot along with any other vaccine, then 83% of parents agree. And if the doctor offers a separate flu vaccine, then only 33% agree to do it. Doctors should note.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cognitive processes and the decisions of some parents for forego pertussis vaccination for their children</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/025-cognitive-processes-and-the-decisions-of-some-parents-for-forego-pertussis-vaccination-for-their-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/025-cognitive-processes-and-the-decisions-of-some-parents-for-forego-pertussis-vaccination-for-their-children/</guid>
      <description>When parents are told that whooping cough is more dangerous than a vaccine against it, they believe it, but their intention to vaccinate their children is only decreased.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content and Design Attributes of Antivaccination Web Sites</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/021-content-and-design-attributes-of-antivaccination-web-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/021-content-and-design-attributes-of-antivaccination-web-sites/</guid>
      <description>In this study, the authors analyzed 22 anti-invasive sites, and concluded that anti-vaccination sites are against vaccinations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deciding to opt out of childhood vaccination mandates</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/006-deciding-to-opt-out-of-childhood-vaccination-mandates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/006-deciding-to-opt-out-of-childhood-vaccination-mandates/</guid>
      <description>Parents who do not vaccinate their children, value scientific knowledge, know where to look, and how to analyze information about vaccinations, and at the same time do not really trust medicine. (USA)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Differences in risk factors for partial and no immunization in the first year of life: prospective cohort study</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/009-differences-in-risk-factors-for-partial-and-no-immunization-in-the-first-year-of-life-prospective-cohort-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/009-differences-in-risk-factors-for-partial-and-no-immunization-in-the-first-year-of-life-prospective-cohort-study/</guid>
      <description>Non-vaccinating mothers are older and more educated than mothers who vaccinate. (United Kingdom)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effective messages in vaccine promotion: a randomized trial</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/023-effective-messages-in-vaccine-promotion-a-randomized-trial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/023-effective-messages-in-vaccine-promotion-a-randomized-trial/</guid>
      <description>When parents are told about a child having almost died from measles, it only strengthens their belief that MMR leads to serious side effects.
When parents are shown photographs of children with measles, this only strengthens their belief that vaccines lead to autism.
When parents are told the horrors of diseases, this does not affect their intention not to vaccinate children.
When parents are told that MMR is not related to autism, they agree, but their intention to vaccinate their children only decreases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Maternal and Provider Characteristics on the Up-to-Date Immunization Status of Children Aged 19 to 35 Months</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/004-effects-of-maternal-and-provider-characteristics-on-the-up-to-date-immunization-status-of-children-aged-19-to-35-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/004-effects-of-maternal-and-provider-characteristics-on-the-up-to-date-immunization-status-of-children-aged-19-to-35-months/</guid>
      <description>The lower the mother&amp;rsquo;s level of education, and the poorer, the higher the chance that she fully vaccinates her children.
More African and Latin Americans are vaccinating their children, and the poorer they are, the more they vaccinate. (USA)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Factors associated with uptake of measles, mumps, and rubella vaccine (MMR) and use of single antigen vaccines in a contemporary UK cohort: prospective cohort study</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/012-factors-associated-with-uptake-of-measles-mumps-and-rubella-vaccine-mmr-and-use-of-single-antigen-vaccines-in-a-contemporary-uk-cohort-prospective-cohort-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/012-factors-associated-with-uptake-of-measles-mumps-and-rubella-vaccine-mmr-and-use-of-single-antigen-vaccines-in-a-contemporary-uk-cohort-prospective-cohort-study/</guid>
      <description>The higher the level of education, age and income, the more often parents refused the MMR, and chose a non-combined measles vaccine. (United Kingdom)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greater freedom of speech on Web 2.0 correlates with dominance of views linking vaccines to autism</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/019-greater-freedom-of-speech-on-web-2.0-correlates-with-dominance-of-views-linking-vaccines-to-autism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/019-greater-freedom-of-speech-on-web-2.0-correlates-with-dominance-of-views-linking-vaccines-to-autism/</guid>
      <description>The authors of this study analyzed YouTube, Google, Wikipedia and Pubmed, and came to the conclusion that the more freedom of speech on a resource, the more it associates vaccines with autism. Freedom of speech on YouTube is highest, in Google it is less, and in Wikipedia and Pubmed it is very low. This leads to the fact that on YouTube 75% of the videos link vaccinations with autism, in Google 41% of the links, in Wikipedia 14% of the articles, and in Pubmed 17% of the articles link the vaccines with autism (more than in Wikipedia!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influences on Immunization Decision-Making among US Parents of Young Children</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/027-influences-on-immunization-decision-making-among-us-parents-of-young-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/027-influences-on-immunization-decision-making-among-us-parents-of-young-children/</guid>
      <description>Parents who know someone whose child has suffered from vaccination rarely vaccinate their children, and more often postpone vaccination until a later date.
Many parents doubt the recommendations of doctors, because they know that doctors should reach a certain coverage of vaccination, and have a financial interest in vaccinations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It has correcting myths about the flu vaccine work? An experimental evaluation of the effects of corrective information</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/024-it-has-correcting-myths-about-the-flu-vaccine-work-an-experimental-evaluation-of-the-effects-of-corrective-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/024-it-has-correcting-myths-about-the-flu-vaccine-work-an-experimental-evaluation-of-the-effects-of-corrective-information/</guid>
      <description>When people are told that a flu vaccine cannot cause flu, they believe it, but their intention to get vaccinated only decreases..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maternal characteristics and hospital policies for risk factors for nonreceipt of hepatitis B vaccine in the newborn nursery</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/014-maternal-characteristics-and-hospital-policies-for-risk-factors-for-nonreceipt-of-hepatitis-b-vaccine-in-the-newborn-nursery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/014-maternal-characteristics-and-hospital-policies-for-risk-factors-for-nonreceipt-of-hepatitis-b-vaccine-in-the-newborn-nursery/</guid>
      <description>More educated mothers and mothers with higher incomes often refuse to vaccinate their newborn child against hepatitis B. (Colorado, USA)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Misinformation lingers in memory: Failure of three pro-vaccination strategies</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/026-misinformation-lingers-in-memory-failure-of-three-pro-vaccination-strategies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/026-misinformation-lingers-in-memory-failure-of-three-pro-vaccination-strategies/</guid>
      <description>Existing misinformation correction strategies are ineffective and lead only to the opposite effect, reinforcing unfounded beliefs about vaccination and reducing the intention to vaccinate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Israeli Parents Refusing to Vaccinate Their Babies According to State Regulations</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/008-more-israeli-parents-refusing-to-vaccinate-their-babies-according-to-state-regulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/008-more-israeli-parents-refusing-to-vaccinate-their-babies-according-to-state-regulations/</guid>
      <description>Mothers with an academic education are twice as likely to refuse vaccinations.
Jews are 4 times more likely to refuse vaccinations than Muslims.
The older the mothers, the more often they refuse vaccinations. (Israel)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Negative attitude of highly educated parents and health care workers to future vaccinations in the Dutch childhood vaccination program</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/005-negative-attitude-of-highly-educated-parents-and-health-care-workers-to-future-vaccinations-in-the-dutch-childhood-vaccination-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/005-negative-attitude-of-highly-educated-parents-and-health-care-workers-to-future-vaccinations-in-the-dutch-childhood-vaccination-program/</guid>
      <description>Parents with higher education are 3 times more likely to refuse vaccinations.
Medical workers are 4 times more likely to refuse vaccinations.
Atheists are 2.6 times more likely to refuse vaccinations. (Netherlands)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predictors of HPV vaccine acceptability: a theory-informed, systematic review</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/011-predictors-of-hpv-vaccine-acceptability-a-theory-informed-systematic-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/011-predictors-of-hpv-vaccine-acceptability-a-theory-informed-systematic-review/</guid>
      <description>A systematic review of 28 studies showed the higher the level of education of parents, the more often they refused the HPV vaccine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sociodemographic Predictors of Vaccination Exemptions on the Basis of Personal Belief in California</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/007-sociodemographic-predictors-of-vaccination-exemptions-on-the-basis-of-personal-belief-in-california/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/007-sociodemographic-predictors-of-vaccination-exemptions-on-the-basis-of-personal-belief-in-california/</guid>
      <description>The number of non-medically refused vaccinations in California increased 4-fold between 2001 and 2014 (from 0.77% to 3.15%).
In private schools, there were twice as many refusals as in public schools. The percentage of refusers was higher among white, richer and more educated people.
In other states the same is observed - the percentage of those who refuse vaccinations in private schools is much higher than in public.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Vaccine Confidence 2016: Global Insights Through a 67-Country Survey. </title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/016-the-state-of-vaccine-confidence-2016-global-insights-through-a-67-country-survey./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/anti-vaxx/016-the-state-of-vaccine-confidence-2016-global-insights-through-a-67-country-survey./</guid>
      <description>Residents of European countries, as well as countries where education and medicine are better, doubt the safety of vaccines more</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>