<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meningitis on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</title>
    <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/diseases/meningitis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meningitis on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© amantonio, scibook.org 2017–2019</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/diseases/meningitis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A retrospective survey of the complications of mumps</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/005-a-retrospective-survey-of-the-complications-of-mumps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/005-a-retrospective-survey-of-the-complications-of-mumps/</guid>
      <description>Here is the analysis of 2,482 cases of mumps hospitalization in 1958-1969 in 16 hospitals in England. They constitute the majority of mumps cases that required hospitalization in the country. Half of the patients were 15 years old or older. Complications were recorded in 42% of all cases. Three patients died, but two of them had another serious underlying illness and mumps might not have had anything to do with the death, and the third patient was most probably misdiagnosed and did not even have mumps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outbreak of aseptic meningitis and mumps after mass vaccination with MMR vaccine using the Leningrad-Zagreb mumps strain</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/021-outbreak-of-aseptic-meningitis-and-mumps-after-mass-vaccination-with-mmr-vaccine-using-the-leningrad-zagreb-mumps-strain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/021-outbreak-of-aseptic-meningitis-and-mumps-after-mass-vaccination-with-mmr-vaccine-using-the-leningrad-zagreb-mumps-strain/</guid>
      <description>The following year, learning from their mistakes, the Brazilian authorities bought MMR with another strain of mumps (Leningrad-Zagreb) and vaccinated 845 thousand children with it. Another outbreak of aseptic meningitis started, and this time the risk of disease was 74 times higher. Sure, it was known that this strain also increases the risk of meningitis, but since the vaccination campaign in the Bahamas did not cause a meningitis outbreak, they decided to see how it would turn out in Brazil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outbreak of aseptic meningitis associated with mass vaccination with a urabe-containing measles-mumps-rubella vaccine: implications for immunization programs</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/019-outbreak-of-aseptic-meningitis-associated-with-mass-vaccination-with-a-urabe-containing-measles-mumps-rubella-vaccine-implications-for-immunization-programs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/019-outbreak-of-aseptic-meningitis-associated-with-mass-vaccination-with-a-urabe-containing-measles-mumps-rubella-vaccine-implications-for-immunization-programs/</guid>
      <description>After the mass MMR vaccination campaign in Brazil with the Japanese strain of mumps (Urabe), an outbreak of aseptic meningitis began. The risk of disease increased by 14-30 times.
The fact that Urabe strain is associated with aseptic meningitis was already known, but Brazilian authorities decided to use this strain anyway, as it is cheaper and more effective than the Jeryl Lynn strain (which is used in the US), and because they thought the risk of meningitis was quite low.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waning immunity against mumps in vaccinated young adults, France 2013</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/011-waning-immunity-against-mumps-in-vaccinated-young-adults-france-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/mumps/011-waning-immunity-against-mumps-in-vaccinated-young-adults-france-2013/</guid>
      <description>In 2013, 15 mumps outbreaks were registered in France. 72% of the cases had been vaccinated twice. The effectiveness of the vaccine was 49% for one dose and 55% for two doses.
Among those who had been vaccinated once, the risk of getting mumps increased by 7% for every year that had passed since the vaccination.
Among those who had been vaccinated twice, the risk of getting mumps increased by 10% for every year that had passed after the second dose.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>