<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Menopause on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</title>
    <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/conditions/menopause/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Menopause on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© amantonio, scibook.org 2017–2019</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/conditions/menopause/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Adolescent Premature Ovarian Insufficiency Following Human Papillomavirus Vaccination: A Case Series Seen in General Practice</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/024-adolescent-premature-ovarian-insufficiency-following-human-papillomavirus-vaccination-a-case-series-seen-in-general-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/024-adolescent-premature-ovarian-insufficiency-following-human-papillomavirus-vaccination-a-case-series-seen-in-general-practice/</guid>
      <description>Three more girls with menopause after the vaccination. All from the same Australian state. The authors write that menopause in adolescence virtually did not exist before.
(On the other hand, after the menopause one girl had less teenage acne! So if your daughter has acne and you do not want any grandchildren, you can suggest Gardasil to her.)
  But I cite this article because it also analyzes pre-clinical, clinical and post-clinical trials of the vaccine in terms of its effect on fertility, and it is worth reading in full.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human papilloma virus vaccine and primary ovarian failure: another facet of the autoimmune/inflammatory syndrome induced by adjuvants</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/023-human-papilloma-virus-vaccine-and-primary-ovarian-failure-another-facet-of-the-autoimmune-inflammatory-syndrome-induced-by-adjuvants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/023-human-papilloma-virus-vaccine-and-primary-ovarian-failure-another-facet-of-the-autoimmune-inflammatory-syndrome-induced-by-adjuvants/</guid>
      <description>Three girls (ages 13, 14 and 21) had menopause after the vaccination. The tests revealed autoantibodies, hinting at the role of the HPV vaccine. All of them got the regular symptoms as well – nausea, headache, insomnia, cognitive and psychiatric disorders.
HPV virus for Cervarix is grown in caterpillar cells, and the virus for Gardasil is grown in yeast. Yeast is a known trigger of autoimmune reactions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>