<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Papilloma on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</title>
    <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Papilloma on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© amantonio, scibook.org 2017–2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 17:51:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/001/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/001/</guid>
      <description>I’m beginning the review of individual vaccines with the Human Papilloma Virus (HPV) vaccine, as it is, without doubt, the most dangerous and useless one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/002/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/002/</guid>
      <description>HPV is transmitted mainly through sexual contact, but it can also be contracted from parents and friends. Most people contract it at some point in their lives and in 90% of the cases the virus passes on its own, without any symptoms, and only in 0.15% of the cases the virus leads to cervical cancer.
There are over 170 strains of papillomavirus. 17 of them are potentially oncogenic, some only cause warts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/003/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/003/</guid>
      <description>Three HPV vaccines are currently available. Gardasil (Merck) is a tetravalent vaccine (protects against types 6, 11, 16, 18) and Cervarix (GlaxoSmithKline) is bivalent (protects against types 16 and 18). Types 16 and 18 are oncogenic and ‘responsible’ for 70% of the cases of cervical cancer, while types 6 and 11 cause warts. Since 2014 there is also a new, nine-valent vaccine – Gardasil-9.
This vaccine is usually given to children starting at the age of 9, boys and girls, in three doses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/004/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/004/</guid>
      <description>How is it usually determined that a specific virus (or other pathogen) is the cause of a specific disease?
Theoretically, Koch’s postulates are usually used. The causal link between HPV and cervical cancer does not meet the requirements of the Koch’s postulates.
In practice, this does not mean much, as even Koch himself understood the limitations of his postulates.
In reality, there are currently no generally accepted criteria for establishing a causal relationship in medicine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/007/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/007/</guid>
      <description>HPV and cervical cancer could be compared to aluminum and Alzheimer’s disease. Despite the fact that many scientists understand that aluminum plays a major role in the occurrence of the disease, admitting to it would not benefit anyone. It would not benefit the aluminum industry, or the cosmetics industry, or the pharmaceutical industry, all of which will lose hundreds of millions in profits, and will have to payout huge compensations. Neither does it benefit the governments, whose countries’ economies will suffer because or this, nor does it benefit the scientists, who will lose their scarce grants and who do not wish to become another Wakefield.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/009/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/009/</guid>
      <description>Cervical cancer develops very slowly; it is a process that takes 20-40 years (although rapid development is possible). It is preceded by cervical dysplasia.
Cervical dysplasia is the presence of atypical cells in the cervix. There are tree types of dysplasia: CIN 1 (mild dysplasia), CIN 2 (moderate dysplasia), CIN 3 (severe dysplasia).
Having dysplasia does not mean that cervical cancer is inevitable.
Only 1% of CIN 1 develops into cancer; only 5% of CIN 2 develops into cancer; only 12-32% of CIN 3 develops into cancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/019/</guid>
      <description>After the European Medicines Agency (EMA) published a report stating that the HPV vaccine is completely safe, the Scandinavian division of Cochrane filed a complaint with the EMA. In the 19-page letter Cochrane provides evidence of the report having been written by people with conflict of interest, which they forgot to mention. The letter also says that they completely ignored testimonies, expert opinions and evidence of this vaccine being unsafe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/026/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/026/</guid>
      <description>One of the components of Gardasil in ‘Polysorbate 80’. It’s an emulsifier that is often used in food and cosmetics, and is considered safe enough to be used in vaccines as well. Although, of course, no one checked for its safety in vaccines. In a study on rats, however, it turned out that when newborn rats are injected with Polysorbate 80 their oestrus cycle is disrupted (increase from 4.3 to 9-14 days).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/027/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/027/</guid>
      <description>In addition, Polysorbate 80 can penetrate the blood-brain barrier. [1] [2]. Moreover, because of this property it is often added to medicine intended for the central nervous system.
This, in addition to aluminum, also explains why most side effects of the vaccine are neurological and psychiatric disorders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/028/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/028/</guid>
      <description>According to the toxicology report of the manufacturer, Polysorbate 80 is a carcinogen and causes DNA mutations. Also, judging by the animal testing, it causes cardiac changes, psychological changes, and weight loss. Whether it penetrates the skin is unclear, but that does not prevent it from being widely used in soaps, shampoos and other cosmetics.
Polysorbate 80 can cause anaphylactic shock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/030/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/030/</guid>
      <description>Healthy mice, whose diet was supplemented with a low concentration of Polysorbate 80, developed] an intestinal inflammation. They had obesity, metabolic syndrome and colitis. Polysorbate 80 also changed intestinal microflora and increased the inflammatory potential. The authors conclude that using Polysorbate 80 and similar emulsifiers contributed to the increase in the number of cases of obesity, metabolic syndrome and chronic inflammatory bowel diseases.
Polysorbate 80 also plays a role in the development of the Crohn’s disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/031/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/031/</guid>
      <description>Polysorbate 80 is also found in some vaccines against diphtheria, tetanus, whooping cough, polio, Hib, hepatitis A and B, flue, pneumococcus, meningococcus and rotavirus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/032/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/032/</guid>
      <description>In clinical trials of both vaccines, aluminum was used instead of a placebo. Therefore, it is impossible to determine the real number of side effects from these trials. This is the document Merck provided for the FDA approval of Gardasil. 20,000 girls participated in the vaccine trails. 75% of the young girls and girls of the ages of 9-26 developed some kind of new diseases during the three years of the trial (page 137).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/033/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/033/</guid>
      <description>For the longest time I could not understand how they managed to create such a dangerous vaccine. After all, unlike most vaccines that are given to small children with an undeveloped immune system, this vaccine is given to older children and adults. Then why is it that the number of side effects of this particular vaccine is so overwhelming? Vaccination advocates have a simple answer to this question. According to them, this happens because older children and adults, unlike babies, can speak.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/034/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/034/</guid>
      <description>But there is another answer. New types of aluminum salts were used as adjuvants in these vaccines. Aluminum hydroxide (Al(OH)3) and aluminum phosphate (AlPO4) were discussed in the aluminum chapter. But there are new, more potent aluminum adjuvants.
Amorphous Aluminum Hydrophosphate Sulfate (AAHS) was used in Gardasil. Gardasil-9 has 2.2 times more of this aluminum than the previous version of the vaccine (500 μg).
Adjuvant system 04 (AS04) was used in Cervarix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/037/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/037/</guid>
      <description>A very interesting video, which explains in more detail about these new adjuvants. It explains what exactly is meant by ‘amorphous’, and how it affects the fact that each dose of the vaccine has a different amount of antigen, and why AAHS cannot be patented (it is unstable). It also speaks about the fact that the same adjuvant was used in the DTP vaccine (which is no longer used in developed countries because the side effects were too frequent), as well as in other vaccines against hepatitis (in the insert to which Merck forgot to mention this ingredient).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/040/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/040/</guid>
      <description>In the period from 2006 to 2017, after being vaccinated against HPV in USA, 14,518 people went to ER, 4,795 were hospitalized, 1,924 became disabled, 324 died, 279 developed cervical dysplasia, 618 had abnormal pap smears and 129 got cervical cancer. (Data taken from VAERS, i.e. include about 1-10% of all cases).
Three of the deceased were children under the age of three, three of the disabled were children under the age of 6, and 17 children under the age of 3 were hospitalized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/044/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/044/</guid>
      <description>Two interesting lectures about this vaccine:
Dr. Lucija Tomljenovic - HPV Vaccine Safety and Efficacy Issues.
Dr. Suzanne Humphries on Gardasil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A case-control study of quadrivalent human papillomavirus vaccine-associated autoimmune negative events</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/015-a-case-control-study-of-quadrivalent-human-papillomavirus-vaccine-associated-autoimmune-negative-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/015-a-case-control-study-of-quadrivalent-human-papillomavirus-vaccine-associated-autoimmune-negative-events/</guid>
      <description>The authors analyzed the serious adverse events of Gardasil in the USA. The vaccine is associated with an increase in the risk of gastroenteritis by 4.6 times, arthritis – 2.5 times, systemic lupus – 5.3 times, vasculitis – 4 times, alopecia – 8.3 times, nervous system diseases – 1.8 times.
Vasculitis (inflammation of the blood vessels) starts, on average, 6 days after the vaccination, lupus – 19 days later, arthritis – after 55 days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A lowered probability of pregnancy in females in the USA aged 25-29 who received a human papillomavirus vaccine injection</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/025-a-lowered-probability-of-pregnancy-in-females-in-the-usa-aged-25-29-who-received-a-human-papillomavirus-vaccine-injection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/025-a-lowered-probability-of-pregnancy-in-females-in-the-usa-aged-25-29-who-received-a-human-papillomavirus-vaccine-injection/</guid>
      <description>The birth rate in the USA decreased by 11.5% since 2007, even though it’s been rising since 1995.
Married women at the ages of 25-29, who received the HPV vaccine, got pregnant 3 times less often than those who did not get vaccinated.
Among all women, the ones that got one dose got pregnant 2.4 times less often, and those who got three doses got pregnant 3.2 times less often, as compared to the women unvaccinated against HPV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adolescent Premature Ovarian Insufficiency Following Human Papillomavirus Vaccination: A Case Series Seen in General Practice</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/024-adolescent-premature-ovarian-insufficiency-following-human-papillomavirus-vaccination-a-case-series-seen-in-general-practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/024-adolescent-premature-ovarian-insufficiency-following-human-papillomavirus-vaccination-a-case-series-seen-in-general-practice/</guid>
      <description>Three more girls with menopause after the vaccination. All from the same Australian state. The authors write that menopause in adolescence virtually did not exist before.
(On the other hand, after the menopause one girl had less teenage acne! So if your daughter has acne and you do not want any grandchildren, you can suggest Gardasil to her.)  But I cite this article because it also analyzes pre-clinical, clinical and post-clinical trials of the vaccine in terms of its effect on fertility, and it is worth reading in full.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adverse events following HPV vaccination, Alberta 2006-2014</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/016-adverse-events-following-hpv-vaccination-alberta-2006-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/016-adverse-events-following-hpv-vaccination-alberta-2006-2014/</guid>
      <description>Out of 195 thousand girls who received Gardasil, 10% came to emergency department within 42 days of vaccination. 958 were hospitalized.
The authors conclude that the vaccine is safe. 10% of emergency care visits among 10-year-old girls is, of course, quite normal and has nothing to do with the vaccination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adverse reactions to human papillomavirus vaccine in the Valencian Community (2007-2011)</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/006-adverse-reactions-to-human-papillomavirus-vaccine-in-the-valencian-community-2007-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/006-adverse-reactions-to-human-papillomavirus-vaccine-in-the-valencian-community-2007-2011/</guid>
      <description>Gardasil causes 2.6 times more fainting, and 8 times more epileptic seizure than do other vaccines. The authors conclude that the vaccine is perfectly safe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behavioral abnormalities in female mice following the administration of aluminum adjuvants and the human papillomavirus (HPV) vaccine Gardasil</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/014-behavioral-abnormalities-in-female-mice-following-the-administration-of-aluminum-adjuvants-and-the-human-papillomavirus-hpv-vaccine-gardasil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/014-behavioral-abnormalities-in-female-mice-following-the-administration-of-aluminum-adjuvants-and-the-human-papillomavirus-hpv-vaccine-gardasil/</guid>
      <description>Mice were injected with Gardasil in doses equivalent to the humans’ and compared to control mice. Vaccinated mice showed signs of depression, as well as inflammation of the brain nerve tissue and autoimmune reactions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death after Quadrivalent Human Papillomavirus (HPV) Vaccination: Causal or Coincidental?</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/020-death-after-quadrivalent-human-papillomavirus-hpv-vaccination-causal-or-coincidental/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/020-death-after-quadrivalent-human-papillomavirus-hpv-vaccination-causal-or-coincidental/</guid>
      <description>Two girls died after getting the HPV vaccine. The first girl died at the age of 19, 6 months after receiving the third vaccine. The second girl died at the age of 14, two weeks after receiving the second vaccine. Both had autopsies, which did not reveal any pathologies.
The authors of the study analyzed the samples of the girls’ brain tissue and discovered that they both had autoimmune cerebral vasculitis (inflammation of the blood vessels of the brain), caused by the HPV-16 antibodies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detection of human papillomavirus (HPV) L1 gene DNA bound to particulate aluminum adjuvant in the HPV vaccine Gardasil</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/038-detection-of-human-papillomavirus-hpv-l1-gene-dna-bound-to-particulate-aluminum-adjuvant-in-the-hpv-vaccine-gardasil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/038-detection-of-human-papillomavirus-hpv-l1-gene-dna-bound-to-particulate-aluminum-adjuvant-in-the-hpv-vaccine-gardasil/</guid>
      <description>Despite the manufacturer’s claims that the vaccine is purified and does not contain papillomavirus DNA, all 16 of the tested doses, collected from around the world, had fragments of the virus’s DNA.
Since these fragments are bonded with aluminum, (which is devoured and spread throughout the body through the lymphatic system by macrophages), these virus DNA fragments enter all organs, and further enhance the autoimmune response. However, there could easily be a whole live virus, not just the fragments, which will infect the whole body, instead of the usual way of infecting only the cells of the skin, vagina or throat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of alternative aluminum adjuvants on the absorption and immunogenicity of HPV16 L1 VLPs in mice</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/035-effect-of-alternative-aluminum-adjuvants-on-the-absorption-and-immunogenicity-of-hpv16-l1-vlps-in-mice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/035-effect-of-alternative-aluminum-adjuvants-on-the-absorption-and-immunogenicity-of-hpv16-l1-vlps-in-mice/</guid>
      <description>This articles compares the immune response to these new adjuvants with aluminum hydroxide on mice. The authors happily conclude that both of the new adjuvants induce an immune response 3-8 greater than the immune response to aluminum hydroxide. For some reason they never mention that eightfold immune response also means an eightfold risk of the autoimmune response.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effectiveness of the Quadrivalent Human Papillomavirus Vaccine Against Cervical Dysplasia in Manitoba, Canada</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/012-effectiveness-of-the-quadrivalent-human-papillomavirus-vaccine-against-cervical-dysplasia-in-manitoba-canada/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/012-effectiveness-of-the-quadrivalent-human-papillomavirus-vaccine-against-cervical-dysplasia-in-manitoba-canada/</guid>
      <description>Another study proving the low effectiveness of Gardasil and negative effectiveness for those already infected with HPV.
Regarding the negative effectiveness of the vaccine for those already infected, the CDC writes: “The vaccine is less effective in preventing HPV-related disease in young women who have already been exposed to one or more HPV types. ‘Less effective’, according to CDC, means negative effectiveness. However, they are technically right. Negative effectiveness, indeed, is less than the positive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human papilloma virus vaccine and primary ovarian failure: another facet of the autoimmune/inflammatory syndrome induced by adjuvants</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/023-human-papilloma-virus-vaccine-and-primary-ovarian-failure-another-facet-of-the-autoimmune-inflammatory-syndrome-induced-by-adjuvants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/023-human-papilloma-virus-vaccine-and-primary-ovarian-failure-another-facet-of-the-autoimmune-inflammatory-syndrome-induced-by-adjuvants/</guid>
      <description>Three girls (ages 13, 14 and 21) had menopause after the vaccination. The tests revealed autoantibodies, hinting at the role of the HPV vaccine. All of them got the regular symptoms as well – nausea, headache, insomnia, cognitive and psychiatric disorders.
HPV virus for Cervarix is grown in caterpillar cells, and the virus for Gardasil is grown in yeast. Yeast is a known trigger of autoimmune reactions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human papillomavirus (HPV) vaccine policy and evidence-based medicine: are they at odds?</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/013-human-papillomavirus-hpv-vaccine-policy-and-evidence-based-medicine-are-they-at-odds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/013-human-papillomavirus-hpv-vaccine-policy-and-evidence-based-medicine-are-they-at-odds/</guid>
      <description>Despite the fact that HPV vaccine is positioned as vaccine against cervical cancer, to this day it has not prevented a single case of cancer, let alone cancer death. The long-term benefits of this vaccine are based on theoretical assumptions, rather than on research. (It has not been established that the immunity will last for decades). Side effects from it include seizures, paralysis, Guillain-Barre syndrome, transverse myelitis, facial neuritis, anaphylactic shock, deep vein thrombosis, chronic fatigue syndrome, cervical cancer and death.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human papillomavirus (HPV) vaccines as an option for preventing cervical malignancies: (how effective and safe?</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/011-human-papillomavirus-hpv-vaccines-as-an-option-for-preventing-cervical-malignancies-how-effective-and-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/011-human-papillomavirus-hpv-vaccines-as-an-option-for-preventing-cervical-malignancies-how-effective-and-safe/</guid>
      <description>This article analyzes clinical trials of HPV vaccines. The article is long, but very informative, and is worth reading in full.
 PAP smear is a test that determines whether one has dysplasia. In developed countries where it is widely used, the risk of death from cervical cancer is very low (1.4/100,000 women). 90% of deaths from cervical cancer are recorded in third world countries. (The risk of disease is also very low – 7/100,000 women.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of vaccine human papillomavirus genotypes in squamous intraepithelial lesions (CIN2 - 3)</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/039-identification-of-vaccine-human-papillomavirus-genotypes-in-squamous-intraepithelial-lesions-cin2-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/039-identification-of-vaccine-human-papillomavirus-genotypes-in-squamous-intraepithelial-lesions-cin2-3/</guid>
      <description>Among the unvaccinated women with CIN 2-3 only 28% were infected with the HPV 16 and 18 strains.
9% of the women with CIN 2-3 did not have HPV at all (Barcelona).
In another study, HPV was only found in 60% of the cases of invasive cervical cancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Murine hypothalamic destruction with vascular cell apoptosis subsequent to the combined administration of human papilloma virus vaccine and pertussis toxin</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/036-murine-hypothalamic-destruction-with-vascular-cell-apoptosis-subsequent-to-the-combined-administration-of-human-papilloma-virus-vaccine-and-pertussis-toxin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/036-murine-hypothalamic-destruction-with-vascular-cell-apoptosis-subsequent-to-the-combined-administration-of-human-papilloma-virus-vaccine-and-pertussis-toxin/</guid>
      <description>In mice that injected Gardasil together in pertussis toxin, there was damage to the central nervous system and death of cells of vessels around the thalamus and hypothalamus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orthostatic intolerance and postural tachycardia syndrome as suspected adverse effects of vaccination against human papilloma virus</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/021-orthostatic-intolerance-and-postural-tachycardia-syndrome-as-suspected-adverse-effects-of-vaccination-against-human-papilloma-virus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/021-orthostatic-intolerance-and-postural-tachycardia-syndrome-as-suspected-adverse-effects-of-vaccination-against-human-papilloma-virus/</guid>
      <description>Orthostatic intolerance is a decrease in pressure upon rising from a sitting or lying position. The authors analyzed the symptoms of 35 girls who came to them. All of them had orthostatic intolerance start, on average, 9 days after the vaccination, but they were diagnosed two years later, on average. Most of them also had severe headaches, nausea, cognitive disorders, rapid heartbeat, weakness, tremor, sleeping problems, rash, neuropathic pain, etc. Five girls could not get about without a wheelchair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pharmaceutical companies&#39; role in state vaccination policymaking: the case of human papillomavirus vaccination</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/042-pharmaceutical-companies-role-in-state-vaccination-policymaking-the-case-of-human-papillomavirus-vaccination/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/042-pharmaceutical-companies-role-in-state-vaccination-policymaking-the-case-of-human-papillomavirus-vaccination/</guid>
      <description>Here the aggressive lobbying by Merck is being analyzed, and how it led to the HPV vaccine becoming mandatory is several states just a year after being licensed.
Only 48% of completed HPV vaccine clinical trial results were published.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polysorbate 80 and E-Ferol toxicity</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/029-polysorbate-80-and-e-ferol-toxicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/029-polysorbate-80-and-e-ferol-toxicity/</guid>
      <description>In the early 1980s, premature babies were injected intravenously with a drug containing vitamin E. It was associated with pulmonary insufficiency, hepatomegaly, cholestatic jaundice, ascites, splenomegaly, renal insufficiency, azotemia and thrombocytopenia. At least 38 babies died.
It turned out that Polysorbate 80, contained in the drug, was responsible for these side effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prevalence of HPV After the Introduction of the Vaccination Program in the United States</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/017-prevalence-of-hpv-after-the-introduction-of-the-vaccination-program-in-the-united-states/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/017-prevalence-of-hpv-after-the-introduction-of-the-vaccination-program-in-the-united-states/</guid>
      <description>Nature abhors a vacuum. By preventing girls from getting the infection from two or four strains of HPV, the vaccine only causes them to be replaced with other strains.
There is a decrease in prevalence of the four strains of HPV in young girls, but there is no change in the prevalence of HPV, taking into account all strains of the virus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probiotics enhance the clearance of human papillomavirus-related cervical lesions: a prospective controlled pilot study</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/045-probiotics-enhance-the-clearance-of-human-papillomavirus-related-cervical-lesions-a-prospective-controlled-pilot-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/045-probiotics-enhance-the-clearance-of-human-papillomavirus-related-cervical-lesions-a-prospective-controlled-pilot-study/</guid>
      <description>Probiotics may help in the treatment of cervical dysplasia.
Vitamins C, A, E, vitamin D, group B vitamins, green tea extract, turmeric and healthy vaginal flora significantly reduce the risk of dysplasia.
That is, if you do not smoke, do not take oral contraceptives, eat well, do not destroy vaginal microflora with douching chemicals, get pap-smears once in a while, then the risk of cervical cancer, which is already very low, is reduced to almost zero without any vaccinations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quadrivalent human papillomavirus vaccine and autoimmune adverse events: a case-control assessment of the vaccine adverse event reporting system (VAERS) database</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/010-quadrivalent-human-papillomavirus-vaccine-and-autoimmune-adverse-events-a-case-control-assessment-of-the-vaccine-adverse-event-reporting-system-vaers-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/010-quadrivalent-human-papillomavirus-vaccine-and-autoimmune-adverse-events-a-case-control-assessment-of-the-vaccine-adverse-event-reporting-system-vaers-database/</guid>
      <description>VAERS analysis. For those vaccinated with Gardasil the risk of getting gastroenteritis was increased in 4.6 times, rheumatoid arthritis – 5.6 times, thrombocytopenia – 2.2 times, systemic lupus erythematosus – 7.6 times, vasculitis – 3.4 times, alopecia – 8.9 times, fainting – 5.3 times, damage to the ovaries – 15 times, irritable bowel syndrome – 10 times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serious adverse events after HPV vaccination: a critical review of randomized trials and post-marketing case series</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/008-serious-adverse-events-after-hpv-vaccination-a-critical-review-of-randomized-trials-and-post-marketing-case-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/008-serious-adverse-events-after-hpv-vaccination-a-critical-review-of-randomized-trials-and-post-marketing-case-series/</guid>
      <description>Analysis of clinical and post-clinical trials of the vaccine:
 In most clinical studies, an inert placebo was not used; In two largest clinical trials the number of serious negative cases reported was significantly higher in the group that received the vaccine; In the group that received Cervarix, 14 deaths were recorded, while the group that got the placebo only three girls died; In the group that received Gardasil-9 the number of serious negative cases reported was significantly higher than in the group that got regular Gardasil (3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shift in the prevalence of HPV types in cervical cytology specimens in the era of HPV vaccination</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/018-shift-in-the-prevalence-of-hpv-types-in-cervical-cytology-specimens-in-the-era-of-hpv-vaccination/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/018-shift-in-the-prevalence-of-hpv-types-in-cervical-cytology-specimens-in-the-era-of-hpv-vaccination/</guid>
      <description>Oncogenic strains of HPV, 16 and 18, have been replaced with other oncogenic strains: 31, 51, 53, 56 and 66.
Three more studies with the same conclusions in Italy, Netherlands and the USA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suspected side effects to the quadrivalent human papilloma vaccine</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/022-suspected-side-effects-to-the-quadrivalent-human-papilloma-vaccine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/022-suspected-side-effects-to-the-quadrivalent-human-papilloma-vaccine/</guid>
      <description>The authors analyzed the symptoms of 53 girls after the vaccination. Common symptoms were headaches, orthostatic intolerance, fainting, weakness, cognitive disorders, insomnia, irregular menstrual cycle, tremor, twitching, difficulty walking, stomachache, chest pain and neuropathic pains, etc. None of the girls had any chronic diseases before the vaccination.
The symptoms started, on average, 11 days after the vaccination. Before vaccination all patients were professionally involved in sports. After the vaccination 98% of them could not function normally, 75% had to quit studies or jobs for at least two months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The cause of invasive cancer can be multifactorial</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/005-the-cause-of-invasive-cancer-can-be-multifactorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/005-the-cause-of-invasive-cancer-can-be-multifactorial/</guid>
      <description>Despite the fact that HPV-16 and 18 play a major role in the development of cervical cancer, contracting HPV is neither a necessary nor a sufficient factor in causing cervical cancer.
 HPV is found in only 90% of the tumors, and therefore that causal relationship between them does not satisfy Koch’s first postulate in 1970s researchers believed that it was the herpes virus (HSV-2) that was responsible for this disease</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cochrane HPV vaccine review was incomplete and ignored important evidence of bias</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/043-the-cochrane-hpv-vaccine-review-was-incomplete-and-ignored-important-evidence-of-bias/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/043-the-cochrane-hpv-vaccine-review-was-incomplete-and-ignored-important-evidence-of-bias/</guid>
      <description>In May 2018, Cochrane published a systemic review of randomized studies of HPV vaccines.
In late July, another Cochrane group published an article criticizing this review:
 The review only included 26 out 46 studies that met the criteria. All these studies used aluminum adjuvants or hepatitis vaccines as placebo. The number of serious side effects in the review did not match the published data. The authors also forgot to report that some studies did not record serious side effect that happened 14 days after the vaccination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too fast or not too fast: the FDA&#39;s approval of Merck&#39;s HPV vaccine Gardasil</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/041-too-fast-or-not-too-fast-the-fdas-approval-of-mercks-hpv-vaccine-gardasil/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/papilloma/041-too-fast-or-not-too-fast-the-fdas-approval-of-mercks-hpv-vaccine-gardasil/</guid>
      <description>The process of licensing a new drug is quite long. Some drugs, however, get exceptions from the FDA and are licensed much faster, if there is reason to believe that they are very effective, safe, better than the drugs already on the market, and will improve the public health. This is called fast track. The licensing process of Gardasil went down this path and took only six months.
This article analyses the approval process of Gardasil and proves that Gardasil does not meet any of the four criteria required to get the fast track.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>