<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Getting into vaccination on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</title>
    <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Getting into vaccination on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© amantonio, scibook.org 2017–2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 15:44:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/001/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/001/</guid>
      <description>Over the past few months, I spent hundreds of hours researching vaccination topics. I have fully read over a thousand scientific studies, and many abstracts. Now I can say with all certainty that if you have not deliberately dealt with this topic, then practically everything you know about vaccinations is a lie. From the beginning to the end. All that is written on this topic in the media is propaganda, fake news, and all this has nothing to do with either science or reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/002/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/002/</guid>
      <description>I absolutely do not want to engage in reverse propaganda, because this is a very thankless task, but firstly, I just cannot not write about it, secondly, I write all this to organize my thoughts on this topic, and thirdly, perhaps my excessive investment of time in the study of the theme of vaccinations will help other parents make the right decision.
If you are absolutely sure that vaccinations are important, safe and effective, and want to stay like that, then please do not read further.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/003/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/003/</guid>
      <description>Recently I talked to one relative who told me that when he had his first child, he devoted quite a lot of time to choosing a stroller, a cot, a child seat for the car, etc. But he did not spend a minute trying to figure out what vaccinations are worth or not worth doing. Almost all parents delegate the right to this decision to others. They believe that other people - scientists, doctors or nurses have already dealt with this topic, and made the best decision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/004/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/004/</guid>
      <description>Parents take a huge number of decisions for their children. What they eat during pregnancy, where they give birth, how and what to feed the child, to feed according to a schedule or on demand, how to introduce solid foods and when, whether to give a pacifier, what babysitter to use, to which kindergarten / school to send it, etc., etc. Parents take hundreds of decisions related to all aspects of the life of the child, with the goal of raising a healthy and happy child.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/005/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/005/</guid>
      <description>At the moment I believe that the most important parental decision is to vaccinate or not to vaccinate a child. And this most important decision, almost all parents delegate. After all, the most important thing for any parent is the health of the child. And there is practically nothing else that would influence their health more than the decision to vaccinate or not, and if done, which.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/006/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/006/</guid>
      <description>Some parents with whom I spoke are so confident in the importance of vaccinations that even knowing that some people think that vaccines are unsafe, they just do not want to understand it, but they aggressively defend their point of view without reading a single scientific article. They do not want to listen to a word that some vaccines may not be very effective, or not very safe, though this has been proven by many scientific studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/007/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/007/</guid>
      <description>The theme of vaccinations is very extensive. It cannot be understood in a few hours, or even in a few days. It is desirable to devote at least 50-100 hours to it, and even better, more still. On the one hand it&#39;s a lot of time, on the other hand, a lot of materials on vaccines are documentaries, series and video lectures. Replacing only a couple of seasons of your favorite TV series with serials, films and lectures on the theme of vaccinations, you will already provide the lion&#39;s share of the time needed to research this topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/008/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/008/</guid>
      <description>Many parents believe that they basically cannot deal with vaccinations, and put forward two arguments. The first argument is that a biological or medical education is needed to understand this topic.
This is not true. Vaccinations are not rocket science, and any sane person is able to understand them.
I do not even have close to a biomedical education, but my wife is a doctor, which, of course, very much helped me understand this topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/009/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/009/</guid>
      <description>The second argument is that no one can understand this topic better than scientists from the FDA or CDC. And if these scientists claim that vaccinations are completely safe and effective, then any other opinion is, by definition, the opinion of an incompetent person.
First, it is an appeal to authority, i.e. a logical error in itself.
Secondly, the question that faces scientists from the CDC, is very different from the question that faces parents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/010/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/010/</guid>
      <description>The theme of vaccinations is extremely emotional. Many people, for some reason, find it very difficult to rationally study this topic, and even read something on this topic. But in order to understand it, you need to leave emotions aside. It is necessary to admit that perhaps the arguments against vaccination, or some part of them, are true, and soberly assess the arguments for and against.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/011/</guid>
      <description>It is not right to ask whether the vaccines are generally good or not. Some &amp;ldquo;experts&amp;rdquo; begin to prove that vaccinations against smallpox or yellow fever saved millions of lives. Even if this is so, it is absolutely not important. Parents do not need to make a decision about vaccination against smallpox or from yellow fever. They need to make decisions about other vaccinations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/012/</guid>
      <description>Each vaccination is unique. The safety and effectiveness of each of them is completely different. There are vaccinations which are quite effective, there are those which are almost useless, and there are those whose effectiveness is negative. There are vaccinations which are safer, but there are such that God forbid.
Each vaccination should be dealt with separately. Biologically they work quite differently, and this is important. The measles vaccine is very different from the whooping cough vaccine, and both are very different from the pneumococcal vaccine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/013/</guid>
      <description>In most developed countries, vaccinations are made against the same diseases, but the number of vaccinations and vaccination schedules in different countries is very different.
In total there are approximately 15 vaccinations: hepatitis B, diphtheria, tetanus, whooping cough, poliomyelitis, hemophilia B, measles, mumps, rubella, chickenpox, hepatitis A, rotavirus, pneumococcus, papilloma and influenza. In some countries, there are vaccinations against tuberculosis and meningococcus.
It is necessary to make a separate decision for each vaccination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/014/</guid>
      <description>In addition to vaccinations, it is necessary to also understand the diseases from which they protect. It is necessary to understand whether childhood illnesses are as dangerous as they are painted. It is necessary to understand how many years the vaccine gives immunity for, and for how many years does it give the transferred illness. It is necessary to understand whether the disease is only harmful, or, perhaps, the transferred illness has also advantages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/015/</guid>
      <description>The decision to do or not to do every inoculation should not be emotional, but purely mathematical. If the likelihood of getting sick and getting complications from it is higher than the probability of a complication from vaccination, it is worth vaccinating. And if it is lower, it&#39;s not worth it. This is a simplification, of course, because complications can be more or less severe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/016/</guid>
      <description>In addition to the active substance, they contain many additives. Adjuvants (aluminum hydroxide, aluminum phosphate, AAHS, squalene), preservatives and stabilizers (thiomersal, polysorbate 80, gelatin, formaldehyde), fragments of diploid human cells (WI-38, MRC-5), antibiotics, fragments of monkey cells, DNA fragments (human and animals), yeast, urea, borax (cockroach remedy), egg white, sodium glutamate and many others (the complete list here), as well as all kinds of heavy metals not listed on the package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/017/</guid>
      <description>It&#39;s amazing that even those people who read the inserts in medicines do not read inserts in vaccines, and in general are practically not interested in their side effects, despite the fact that these vaccines they give to their healthy newborn children! Moreover, unlike drugs that are taken orally, and are filtered by the liver and intestines, the entire content of intramuscular vaccinations falls completely into the circulatory, lymphatic or nervous systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/018/</guid>
      <description>If you read any media, you probably know that in 1998, Andrew Wakefield published a study linking the MMR inoculation with autism. Subsequently, dozens of studies have been published proving that this vaccine does not cause autism, it was proved that Wakefield invented patients, and for this he was deprived of a doctor&#39;s license. All anti-vaccination arguments are based on his invented data, and only on this one withdrawn study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/019/</guid>
      <description>There are thousands of studies published in peer-reviewed scientific journals that prove both unsafety and the inefficiency of vaccinations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/020/</guid>
      <description>But maybe anti-vaccination arguments are engaged in cherry picking? They base their decision on a thousand studies on the dangers of vaccinations, and ignore a thousand other studies proving the safety of vaccinations?
Maybe. Therefore, it is also necessary to read studies that prove that vaccinations are safe to make sure that they do not usually prove this, and to understand who is actually engaged in cherry picking. It is very important to read these studies completely, and not just the abstracts, because too often the data speak of one thing, and the conclusions speak something quite the opposite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/021/</guid>
      <description>The opportunity to deal with the vaccination problem itself appeared only a few years ago thanks to the Kazakh student Alexandra Elbakyan. Before that, almost all scientific research was inaccessible to the general public, and for reading each article it was necessary to pay $30. Science was hidden from the uninitiated, sealed with seven seals. Now, thanks to the sci-hub site, it is possible to find any research for free in just a few seconds, and verify with your own eyes what kind of crap some scientists are involved in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/022/</guid>
      <description>To prove that vaccinations are safe and effective, you only need to conduct a randomized, placebo-controlled trial. Half the children are vaccinated with all vaccinations, and the second half is not vaccinated at all. There are no such studies, since it is considered unethical at this time not to vaccinate children. Therefore, almost all existing studies are observational studies, case reports, hypotheses, expert opinions, animal studies, etc. There are no studies that check the entire vaccination schedule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/023/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/023/</guid>
      <description>It is believed that serious side effects from vaccinations occur extremely rarely. One for one hundred thousand, or even one for a million. It&#39;s a lie. Since no one has conducted adequate vaccination studies, it is difficult to estimate the real number of side effects, but even with the most optimistic assessments, serious consequences are more frequent than in one in fifty (see part 5). Half (!) of the children in the US have at least one chronic disease, and their number is constantly growing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/intro/024/</guid>
      <description>Reading the scientific research on vaccines at first glance looks very boring. Nevertheless, it was incredibly exciting. At first it feels like being a detective. You try to figure out who is good and who is bad, who is telling the truth, and who is lying. Then it looks like an anti-utopia, when you see how pharmaceutical companies manipulate doctors and scientists, doctors manipulate patients, and patients do not suspect anything, and they demand that the banquet continue.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>