<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vitamin C on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</title>
    <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/drugs/vitamin-c/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vitamin C on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© amantonio, scibook.org 2017–2019</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/drugs/vitamin-c/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/033/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/033/</guid>
      <description>The effect of vitamin C on diphtheria has not been studied since the 40s. in 1971, Klenner reported a case of a girl being cured of diphtheria by an intravenous injection of the vitamin. Two other children, who did not get vitamin C, died. All three also received the antitoxin.
Clark (1976). [1]. J Nutr Sci Vitaminol (Tokyo)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/040/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/hepatitisb/040/</guid>
      <description>Ayurvedic medicine seems to cure acute and chronic hepatitis B.
Hepatitis B can also be cured with vitamin C. Moringa as well. And [desmodium](https://data.epo.org/gpi/EP0309342A1-Use-of-desmodium-in-the-treatment-of- hepatitis-and-medicaments-thereof).
Hepatitis B might also be cured with vitamin C. [Baur, 1954], [Kirchmair, 1957], [Calleja, 1960], [Morishige, 1978], [Smith, 1988]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/042/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/pertussis/042/</guid>
      <description>In 1936, articles on the effectiveness of vitamin C against pertussis began to appear in the medical literature. The first study was by Otani in Japan, who administered the vitamin intravenously. Later, in 1937, an independent study by Omerod [1], [2] used the oral vitamin C to treat pertussis in Canada. Furthermore, in 1938, vitamin C was successfully used in a study by Vermillion to help cure pertussis in only a few days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of ascorbic acid in the treatment of tetanus</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/045-effect-of-ascorbic-acid-in-the-treatment-of-tetanus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/045-effect-of-ascorbic-acid-in-the-treatment-of-tetanus/</guid>
      <description>A controlled study of the effects of vitamin C on tetanus in Bangladesh. 117 patients were divided into two groups. The first group received 1g of vitamin C intravenously each day, in addition to the immunoglobulin. The second group only received immunoglobulin.
In the children’s group (1-12 years old), among those who did not receive the vitamin, the mortality rate was 74%. No one died from the group that received vitamin C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Vitamin C Intake on the Degree of Tooth Injury Produced by Diphtheria Toxin</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/030-effects-of-vitamin-c-intake-on-the-degree-of-tooth-injury-produced-by-diphtheria-toxin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/030-effects-of-vitamin-c-intake-on-the-degree-of-tooth-injury-produced-by-diphtheria-toxin/</guid>
      <description>When guinea pigs are injected with a sublethal dose of diphtheria toxin, a 30-50% decrease in the vitamin C level in tissues is observed within 24-48 hours. Children who received little vitamin C, developed scurvy during the infection. It resolved spontaneously after recovery, without increasing the amount of vitamin C in the diet. What correlated with the absence of tooth caries in children of 10-14 years of age are good nutrition and lack of diseases in infancy and childhood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficacy of Vitamin C in Counteracting Tetanus Toxin Toxicity</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/044-efficacy-of-vitamin-c-in-counteracting-tetanus-toxin-toxicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/044-efficacy-of-vitamin-c-in-counteracting-tetanus-toxin-toxicity/</guid>
      <description>30 rats were divided into five groups.
The first group received two minimal lethal doses of tetanus toxin. All rats died.
The second group received a vitamin C injection (1g/kg) together with the toxin injection, and additional injections twice a day. All rats survived. Mild symptoms of tetanus were observed.
The third group got three injections of the vitamin first, and then a toxin with an additional vitamin injection. All rats survived.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inactivation of Tetanus Toxin by Crystalline Vitamin C</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/043-inactivation-of-tetanus-toxin-by-crystalline-vitamin-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/043-inactivation-of-tetanus-toxin-by-crystalline-vitamin-c/</guid>
      <description>Vitamin C inactivates tetanospasmin in vitro, but not in vivo, in guinea pigs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The effect of diphtheria toxin on the vitamin C content of guinea pig tissues</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/028-the-effect-of-diphtheria-toxin-on-the-vitamin-c-content-of-guinea-pig-tissues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/028-the-effect-of-diphtheria-toxin-on-the-vitamin-c-content-of-guinea-pig-tissues/</guid>
      <description>Apart from humans and primates, guinea pigs are the only mammals that do not synthesize vitamin C.
Guinea pigs were injected with diphtheria toxin. Those who were on a low vitamin C diet lost more weight than those on a regular diet. Diphtheria toxin depleted vitamin C in the adrenal glands, pancreas and kidneys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The effect of diphtheria toxin on vitamin C in vitro</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/032-the-effect-of-diphtheria-toxin-on-vitamin-c-in-vitro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/032-the-effect-of-diphtheria-toxin-on-vitamin-c-in-vitro/</guid>
      <description>Guinea pigs with low vitamin C reserve, who got injected with lethal dose of diphtheria toxin, died faster than guinea pigs on a regular diet.
Guinea pigs that received large doses of vitamin C, survived even after being injected with several lethal doses of the toxin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The influence of vitamin C deficiency in the protection of guinea pigs to diphtheria toxin glucose tolerance</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/029-the-influence-of-vitamin-c-deficiency-in-the-protection-of-guinea-pigs-to-diphtheria-toxin-glucose-tolerance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/029-the-influence-of-vitamin-c-deficiency-in-the-protection-of-guinea-pigs-to-diphtheria-toxin-glucose-tolerance/</guid>
      <description>Vitamin C deficiency causes the decreased resistance to infections and increased damages from bacterial toxins. Decreased resistance appears before the scurvy symptoms can be observed. Guinea pigs on a low vitamin C diet, who got injected with sublethal dose of diphtheria toxin, experienced a wider tissue damage, bigger weight loss, wider areas of necrosis, worse teeth development, and shorter lifespan, as compared to guinea pigs who were not restricted in vitamin C consumption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The influence of vitamin C level after resistance to diphtheria toxin</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/031-the-influence-of-vitamin-c-level-after-resistance-to-diphtheria-toxin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/031-the-influence-of-vitamin-c-level-after-resistance-to-diphtheria-toxin/</guid>
      <description>Guinea pigs with limited vitamin C in the diet got injected with sublethal dose of diphtheria toxin. They developed arteriosclerosis in the lungs, liver, spleen and kidneys.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vitamin C for prevention and treatment of tetanus</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/046-vitamin-c-for-prevention-and-treatment-of-tetanus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/tetanus/046-vitamin-c-for-prevention-and-treatment-of-tetanus/</guid>
      <description>A very interesting systematic review by Cochrane on the treatment of tetanus with vitamin C. It is worth reading in full, and then comparing in to the systematic review of the subject of aluminum in vaccines.
The authors of this review only found one of the aforementioned studies on the effects of vitamin C on tetanus, in the entire medical literature. However, they report the following, among other things:
Vitamin C shortens the period of common cold.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>