<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aluminum on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</title>
    <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/drugs/aluminum/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aluminum on SciBook: analysis of published information about vaccinations and infections</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© amantonio, scibook.org 2017–2019</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/drugs/aluminum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A study of the distribution of aluminum in human placental tissues based on alkaline solubilization with determination by electrothermal atomic absorption spectrometry</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/011-a-study-of-the-distribution-of-aluminum-in-human-placental-tissues-based-on-alkaline-solubilization-with-determination-by-electrothermal-atomic-absorption-spectrometry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/011-a-study-of-the-distribution-of-aluminum-in-human-placental-tissues-based-on-alkaline-solubilization-with-determination-by-electrothermal-atomic-absorption-spectrometry/</guid>
      <description>95% of women who gave birth had aluminum found in the placenta, 81% had it in the placental membrane, 46% - in the umbilical cord. This goes to the question of vaccinating pregnant women.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Addressing Parents&#39; Concerns: Do Vaccines Contain Harmful Preservatives, Adjuvants, Additives, or Residuals?</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/028-addressing-parents-concerns-do-vaccines-contain-harmful-preservatives-adjuvants-additives-or-residuals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/028-addressing-parents-concerns-do-vaccines-contain-harmful-preservatives-adjuvants-additives-or-residuals/</guid>
      <description>His arguments:
 Aluminum adjuvants are safe, because they have been used in vaccines for over 70 years; There’s aluminum in breast milk, baby formula, and in general – it is one of the most common metals; There were experiments done on mice, when they were fed aluminum lactate and nothing happened to them.
The first argument is so ridiculous and anti-scientific that it is difficult to respond to it. 70 years ago half of the children did not have chronic diseases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adverse events after immunization with aluminum-containing DTP vaccines: systematic review of the evidence</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/018-adverse-events-after-immunization-with-aluminum-containing-dtp-vaccines-systematic-review-of-the-evidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/018-adverse-events-after-immunization-with-aluminum-containing-dtp-vaccines-systematic-review-of-the-evidence/</guid>
      <description>And here is a systematic review and meta-analysis, which proves that aluminum in DTP vaccines is safe. I highly recommend reading this articles in full. After doing so, you opinion of science will never be the same again.
The authors identified 8 studies of aluminum adjuvants and did a meta-analysis of 5 of them.
The safety studies lasted from 24 hours to 6 weeks. The only side effects these studies were looking for were crying, screaming, pain, fever, seizure and redness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aluminum content of human semen: Implications for semen quality</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/016-aluminum-content-of-human-semen-implications-for-semen-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/016-aluminum-content-of-human-semen-implications-for-semen-quality/</guid>
      <description>Aluminum is accumulated in semen, and the more there is, the worse is the quality of sperm. [1], [2], [3].
Aluminum also disrupts the ovarian function in rats. [1], [[2]](https://www. ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24530740).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aluminum content of some foods and food products in the USA, with aluminium food additives</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/038-aluminum-content-of-some-foods-and-food-products-in-the-usa-with-aluminium-food-additives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/038-aluminum-content-of-some-foods-and-food-products-in-the-usa-with-aluminium-food-additives/</guid>
      <description>Analysis of the amount of aluminum in different products.
There is a lot of aluminum in frozen pizzas, sausages, cheese, pancakes, baking powder, baking mixes, etc.
There is also much aluminum in beverages served in aluminum beer cans.
Rats that have been given drinks from aluminum cans had 69% more aluminum in their bones.
There is much aluminum in chocolate, very much in cacao, as well as tea and fruit juices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aluminum hydroxide injections lead to motor deficits and motor neuron degeneration</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/008-aluminum-hydroxide-injections-lead-to-motor-deficits-and-motor-neuron-degeneration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/008-aluminum-hydroxide-injections-lead-to-motor-deficits-and-motor-neuron-degeneration/</guid>
      <description>Mice were injected with aluminum hydroxide dose equivalent to human vaccines. Increased loss of motor neurons, reduced motor activity, poor spatial memory and other effects, similar to the symptoms of dementia, Alzheimer’s disease and Gulf War syndrome, were observed. Two more similar studies: [1] [2]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aluminum incorporation into the brain of rat fetuses and sucklings</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/009-aluminum-incorporation-into-the-brain-of-rat-fetuses-and-sucklings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/009-aluminum-incorporation-into-the-brain-of-rat-fetuses-and-sucklings/</guid>
      <description>Pregnant rats were given subcutaneous injections of radioactive aluminum, which reached the embryo’s brain in just a couple of days. After the birth, the aluminum continued to accumulate in the brain, now passed on through the breast milk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aluminum Involvement in Neurotoxicity</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/043-aluminum-involvement-in-neurotoxicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/043-aluminum-involvement-in-neurotoxicity/</guid>
      <description>Removing aluminum by chelation therapy in multiple sclerosis patients led to improvement of their symptoms. Patients with neuro-degenerative diseases and multiple sclerosis have much higher levels of aluminum than healthy people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aluminum Should Now Be Considered a Primary Etiological Factor in Alzheimer&#39;s Disease</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/013-aluminum-should-now-be-considered-a-primary-etiological-factor-in-alzheimers-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/013-aluminum-should-now-be-considered-a-primary-etiological-factor-in-alzheimers-disease/</guid>
      <description>The exact cause of Alzheimer’s disease is still unknown, but aluminum plays a major part in it.
Another meta-analysis on this topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aluminum vaccine adjuvants: are they safe?</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/005-aluminum-vaccine-adjuvants-are-they-safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/005-aluminum-vaccine-adjuvants-are-they-safe/</guid>
      <description>Despite the fact that aluminum adjuvants have been used in vaccines for 90 years, it is still unknown why and how exactly aluminum causes such a strong immune response.
High toxicity and danger of aluminum consumed orally has been known since 1911 – when Dr William Gies published the results of seven years of research on aluminum in baking powder, preservatives and food coloring. Aluminum affects memory, concentration and behavior. (Aluminum is still used in baking powder and food preservatives).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aluminum, antiperspirants and breast cancer</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/034-aluminum-antiperspirants-and-breast-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/034-aluminum-antiperspirants-and-breast-cancer/</guid>
      <description>Aluminum in antiperspirants blocks the sweat glands preventing them from releasing sweat, which is what makes them so effective. The cause of 90% of breast cancer is environmental, not genetic. In 1926 only 31% of cancer tumors were located in upper outer part of the breast. In 1994 the numbers increased to 61%. This proportion is growing linearly each year. Genomic instability in outer part of the breast is constantly increasing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aluminum: a potential pro-oxidant in sunscreens/sunblocks?</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/039-aluminum-a-potential-pro-oxidant-in-sunscreens-sunblocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/039-aluminum-a-potential-pro-oxidant-in-sunscreens-sunblocks/</guid>
      <description>Aluminum is found in large quantities in sunscreens. Since aluminum is an oxidant, it is highly likely that it contributes to the development of melanoma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Antacids and dietary supplements with an influence on the gastric pH increase the risk for food sensitization</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/037-antacids-and-dietary-supplements-with-an-influence-on-the-gastric-ph-increase-the-risk-for-food-sensitization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/037-antacids-and-dietary-supplements-with-an-influence-on-the-gastric-ph-increase-the-risk-for-food-sensitization/</guid>
      <description>Aluminum hydroxide and aluminum phosphate are also used as antacids (used to treat heartburn and some other gastrointestinal diseases, many of which are sold without prescription), which in turn leads to allergies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association between maternal exposure to aluminum and the risk of congenital heart defects in offspring</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/010-association-between-maternal-exposure-to-aluminum-and-the-risk-of-congenital-heart-defects-in-offspring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/010-association-between-maternal-exposure-to-aluminum-and-the-risk-of-congenital-heart-defects-in-offspring/</guid>
      <description>High level of aluminum in mother’s hair is associated with congenital heart defects of the child.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do the aluminum vaccine adjuvants contribute to the rising prevalence of autism?</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/007-do-the-aluminum-vaccine-adjuvants-contribute-to-the-rising-prevalence-of-autism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/007-do-the-aluminum-vaccine-adjuvants-contribute-to-the-rising-prevalence-of-autism/</guid>
      <description>The more vaccinations containing aluminum are given in the country, the more children with ASD there are.
The increase in the number of children with ASD in the US correlates with the increase in the number of aluminum adjuvants used. (r = 0.92, p&amp;lt;0.0001)
The authors use Hill’s criteria and conclude that the relationship between aluminum in vaccines and ASD is probably causal. This article is also worth reading in full.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of routine vaccination on aluminum and essential element levels in preterm infants</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/020-effect-of-routine-vaccination-on-aluminum-and-essential-element-levels-in-preterm-infants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/020-effect-of-routine-vaccination-on-aluminum-and-essential-element-levels-in-preterm-infants/</guid>
      <description>15 premature babies were given several vaccines with 1,200 μg of aluminum. This aluminum has not been found either in the blood or in the urine. Where it went remained unclear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of routine vaccination on aluminum and essential element levels in preterm infants</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/021-effect-of-routine-vaccination-on-aluminum-and-essential-element-levels-in-preterm-infants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/021-effect-of-routine-vaccination-on-aluminum-and-essential-element-levels-in-preterm-infants/</guid>
      <description>A very interesting review article, which analyzes all the published studies of safety of aluminum adjuvants.
 Aluminum stimulates a humoral immune response and barely stimulates the cellular one; The FDA approved amount of aluminum per vaccine dose (0.85 mg) was determined empirically based on the effectiveness of this dose; Aforementioned study on rabbits is currently the only existing pharmacokinetic study on aluminum adjuvants on animals. Moreover, the adjuvants tested in this study differ from the adjuvants actually used in the vaccines; FDA’s conclusion that aluminum in vaccines is safe is based on two theoretical articles, which are analyzed in detail here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gut: An underestimated target organ for Aluminum</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/036-gut-an-underestimated-target-organ-for-aluminum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/036-gut-an-underestimated-target-organ-for-aluminum/</guid>
      <description>38% of orally consumed aluminum accumulates in the intestinal mucosa.
Even though the intestines absorb only a small amount of aluminum, 2% of aluminum entering the blood remains in the body and accumulates with age.
Aluminum is probably associated with inflammatory bowel disease.
Adults consume most of the aluminum with hot drinks (except coffee) and vegetables (except potato); children also consume it with pasta and confectionary; and babies get it from the formulas, which contain hundreds of times more aluminum than cow milk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Immunological notes. XVII-XXIV</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/005-immunological-notes.-xvii-xxiv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/diphtheria/005-immunological-notes.-xvii-xxiv/</guid>
      <description>In 1926, Glenny and his group experimented with the diphtheria vaccine and tried to improve its effectiveness. They accidentally found that adding aluminum to the vaccine triggers a stronger immune response. Since then, aluminum is added to most inactivated vaccines.
Glenny was not interested in the safety of having aluminum in a vaccine 90 years ago, nor does it interest anyone today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In vivo absorption of aluminium-containing vaccine adjuvants using 26Al</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/019-in-vivo-absorption-of-aluminium-containing-vaccine-adjuvants-using-26al/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/019-in-vivo-absorption-of-aluminium-containing-vaccine-adjuvants-using-26al/</guid>
      <description>Although the aluminum adjuvants have been used since 1926, what exactly happens to them after they are injected into a muscle is unknown to science.
The researches took several rabbits and injected two of them with radioactive aluminum hydroxide, and the other two with aluminum phosphate. 28 days later the rabbits were killed and at that moment 94% of aluminum hydroxide and 78% of aluminum phosphate still remained in the rabbits’ bodies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infants&#39; exposure to aluminum from vaccines and breast milk during the first 6 months</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/029-infants-exposure-to-aluminum-from-vaccines-and-breast-milk-during-the-first-6-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/029-infants-exposure-to-aluminum-from-vaccines-and-breast-milk-during-the-first-6-months/</guid>
      <description>Even one single Hepatitis B vaccine, which the baby gets on their first day of life, has 5 times more aluminum than they would get from 6 months of breastfeeding.
Moreover, it is impossible to compare aluminum and aluminum adjuvant, which is bound to the antigen, and which is much harder for the body to dispose of.
The aforementioned article from the 6th paragraph responds to the third argument. Offit fails to mention that the motor activity of 20% of mice from this experiment was significantly impaired.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Link between Aluminum and the Pathogenesis of Alzheimer&#39;s Disease: The Integration of the Aluminum and Amyloid Cascade Hypotheses</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/014-link-between-aluminum-and-the-pathogenesis-of-alzheimers-disease-the-integration-of-the-aluminum-and-amyloid-cascade-hypotheses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/014-link-between-aluminum-and-the-pathogenesis-of-alzheimers-disease-the-integration-of-the-aluminum-and-amyloid-cascade-hypotheses/</guid>
      <description>Even though this article is mainly about the role of aluminum in the Alzheimer’s disease, it also lists the currently known mechanisms of aluminum’s influence on biological processes.
Despite the fact that aluminum is one of the most common metals on Earth, in nature it is found only in the compounds with silicon and oxygen. Men only learned how to produce pure aluminum and create aluminum salts in the late nineteenth century.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macrophagic myofasciitis: characterization and pathophysiology</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/012-macrophagic-myofasciitis-characterization-and-pathophysiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/012-macrophagic-myofasciitis-characterization-and-pathophysiology/</guid>
      <description>A review article about Macrophagic myofasciitis (MMF). In some patients, the aluminum adjuvants do not dissolve after the vaccination, but rather remain at the injection site and form an aluminum granuloma. Accompanying symptoms are usually myalgia (muscle pains), chronic fatigue, cognitive impairment, as well as various autoimmune diseases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-linear dose-response of aluminum hydroxide adjuvant particles: Selective low dose neurotoxicity</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/022-non-linear-dose-response-of-aluminum-hydroxide-adjuvant-particles-selective-low-dose-neurotoxicity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/022-non-linear-dose-response-of-aluminum-hydroxide-adjuvant-particles-selective-low-dose-neurotoxicity/</guid>
      <description>Three groups of mice were injected with different doses of aluminum hydroxide (200, 400 and 800 mg/kg of weight). The experiment showed that aluminum granulomas only formed in the muscles of the mice that received high doses. The mice that got small doses did not have granulomas, but the aluminum reached their brains and they had psycho-physiological disorders. The concentration of aluminum in the brains of the group that received 200 μg/kg was 50 times higher then that of the control group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk Assessment of Using Aluminum Foil in Food Preparation</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/032-risk-assessment-of-using-aluminum-foil-in-food-preparation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/032-risk-assessment-of-using-aluminum-foil-in-food-preparation/</guid>
      <description>If you use aluminum dishes, disposable aluminum pans or aluminum foil, then you probably should stop. More: [1].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selective accumulation of aluminum in cerebral arteries in Alzheimer&#39;s disease (AD)</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/015-selective-accumulation-of-aluminum-in-cerebral-arteries-in-alzheimers-disease-ad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/015-selective-accumulation-of-aluminum-in-cerebral-arteries-in-alzheimers-disease-ad/</guid>
      <description>The closer the arteries are to the brain, the higher is the concentration of aluminum in patients with Alzheimer’s disease.
Patients with familial form of Alzheimer’s have been found to have incredibly high levels of aluminum in their brains.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silicon-Rich Mineral Water as a Non-Invasive Test of the &#34; Aluminum Hypothesis&#34; in Alzheimer&#39;s Disease</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/042-silicon-rich-mineral-water-as-a-non-invasive-test-of-the-aluminum-hypothesis-in-alzheimers-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/042-silicon-rich-mineral-water-as-a-non-invasive-test-of-the-aluminum-hypothesis-in-alzheimers-disease/</guid>
      <description>Mineral water rich in silica Si(OH)4 removes aluminum from the body.
12 weeks of drinking this water led to cognitive improvements in some Alzheimer’s patients.
Judging by experiments on rats, curcumin might protect from the inflammatory effects of aluminum, and also omega-3, mung bean extract, moringa, melatonin, olive oil, folic acid, propolis, lecitin, selenium, taurine, viramin E and quercetin. More: [1]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Studies on aluminum leaching from cookware in tea and coffee and evaluation of the content in the toothpaste, baking powder and paan masala</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/041-studies-on-aluminum-leaching-from-cookware-in-tea-and-coffee-and-evaluation-of-the-content-in-the-toothpaste-baking-powder-and-paan-masala/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/041-studies-on-aluminum-leaching-from-cookware-in-tea-and-coffee-and-evaluation-of-the-content-in-the-toothpaste-baking-powder-and-paan-masala/</guid>
      <description>There is a lot of aluminum in toothpastes, as well as in tea.
Toothpaste with aluminum aggravates dermatitis (which was caused by vaccination).
Toothpaste with aluminum causes dental caries.
Aluminum in toothpaste plays an even bigger role in the occurrence of Alzheimer’s than the aluminum in water. 60% of all the toothpaste on the market contains aluminum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There is (still) too much aluminum in infant formulas</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/040-there-is-still-too-much-aluminum-in-infant-formulas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/040-there-is-still-too-much-aluminum-in-infant-formulas/</guid>
      <description>There is a lot of aluminum in baby formula. According to EPA standard, drinking water may contain up to a maximum of 200 µg of aluminum per liter. 15 of the tested baby formulas have from 176 µg to 700 µg of aluminum per liter.
Three years later the authors analyzed 30 more types of baby formula, with similar results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vaccine adjuvants: current state and future trends</title>
      <link>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/025-vaccine-adjuvants-current-state-and-future-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mrascii.github.io/scibook/en/content/vaccines/aluminium/025-vaccine-adjuvants-current-state-and-future-trends/</guid>
      <description>Different types of adjuvants are analyzed here.
 One of the adjuvants used in vaccines is calcium phosphate. It has properties similar to those of the aluminum adjuvants, but since it is a molecule natural for the body, it does not cause neurological reactions and does not lead to allergic reactions. The cost of developing new adjuvants is exorbitantly high, and if the costs of developing vaccines justify themselves, the costs for developing adjuvants do not.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>